<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Montana Fires - Alice Creek Fire</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/feeds/alice-creek-fire.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/</id><updated>2017-09-01T09:48:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>National Guard Boeing CH-47 Chinook helicopters arrive on Alice Creek Fire</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5410_39598.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-01T09:48:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-01T09:48:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-01:/montana_fires/5410_39598.html</id><summary type="html">A COMMUNITY MEETING WILL BE HELD AT THE WOLF CREEK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, TONIGHT AT 6 P.M. ALL ARE WELCOME TO ATTEND.  AUGUSTA, MT – Two National Guard Boeing CH-47 Chinook helicopters arrived Thursday afternoon to provide air support to firefighters on the Alice Creek Fire. These very fast helicopters are able to carry up to 2,000 gallons of water per load and can fly for two-and- a-half hours before needing to refuel. Throughout the duration of this fire, firefighters have relied heavily on helicopters to drop water to cool the fire. With their massive water capacity, these helicopters are a welcome asset. These very large helicopters may catch the eye of drivers along Hwy. 200. Please do not stop along the roadway to look at the aircraft dipping as it may be dangerous to other drivers. Like yesterday, meteorologists are forecasting erratic 34 mph wind gusts that may pulse throughout the fire area most of the day. The National Weather Service extended the Red Flag warning through...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;National Guard Boeing CH-47 Chinook helicopters arrive on Alice Creek Fire&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Alice Creek Fire Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 1 day ago&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align="left"&gt;&lt;font face="'Times New Roman'"&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;A COMMUNITY MEETING WILL BE HELD AT THE WOLF CREEK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, TONIGHT AT 6 P.M. ALL ARE WELCOME TO ATTEND. &lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="'Times New Roman'" size="3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;AUGUSTA, MT – &lt;/b&gt;Two National Guard Boeing CH-47 Chinook helicopters arrived Thursday afternoon to provide air support to firefighters on the Alice Creek Fire. These very fast helicopters are able to carry up to 2,000 gallons of water per load and can fly for two-and- a-half hours before needing to refuel. Throughout the duration of this fire, firefighters have relied heavily on helicopters to drop water to cool the fire. With their massive water capacity, these helicopters are a welcome asset. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="'Times New Roman'" size="3"&gt;These very large helicopters may catch the eye of drivers along Hwy. 200. Please do not stop along the roadway to look at the aircraft dipping as it may be dangerous to other drivers. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="'Times New Roman'" size="3"&gt;Like yesterday, meteorologists are forecasting erratic 34 mph wind gusts that may pulse throughout the fire area most of the day. The National Weather Service extended the Red Flag warning through tonight as a result of very windy and dry conditions. These winds are channeling through the canyons of the Continental Divide, colliding with each other at ridgetops. While there was growth on the northeastern flank, the fire did not make an organized push east, which gave firefighters an opportunity to request an airtanker that dropped a load of retardant to slow its forward progress. The line held overnight. Firefighters are working with land owners to discuss contingency plans that may need to be put into effect today if winds become problematic. In total, the fire gained 153 acres yesterday. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="'Times New Roman'" size="3"&gt;A structure protection plan is in place that allows firefighters, including the Wolf Creek fire responders, to have a coordinated response should the need arise. Working together, fire resources are familiarizing themselves with the area, and working with landowners to implement emergency plans if needed to protect structures in the Elk Meadow/Evergreen, Toms Gulch, Alice Creek Basin, Bedrock and Dearborn areas. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="'Times New Roman'" size="3"&gt;Along the southeastern flank, three feller bunchers, two working their way south to the Green Creek and one working west, met at the end of Green Creek Road yesterday. They were assisted by a handcrew that are cleaning up woody debris in the machine’s path. This machinery is speeding containment efforts in the thick dead and down timber while making it safer for firefighters to successfully protect the structures and cultural and heritage artifacts that are abundant in that area. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="'Times New Roman'" size="3"&gt;A Community meeting will occur at the Wolf Creek Elementary School tonight at &lt;b&gt;6 p.m.&lt;/b&gt; to provide a situational update on the fire and allow the community to ask questions related to the fire activity that has occurred since Great Basin Team 5 took command of the fire Aug. 28. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="'Times New Roman'" size="3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;SIZE: &lt;/b&gt;7,003 acres&lt;b&gt; CONTAINMENT: &lt;/b&gt;0% &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="'Times New Roman'" size="3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;RESOURCES:&lt;/b&gt; Personnel: 186 Crews: 2 Engines: 16 Skidgens: 3 Dozers: 4 Helicopters: 2 &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="'Times New Roman'" size="3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;EVACUATIONS/ PRE-EVACUATIONS: &lt;/b&gt;Lewis and Clark County Sheriff issued &lt;b&gt;mandatory evacuations &lt;/b&gt;for residences in the Elk Meadows (Evergreen) subdivision and to ranches on Road 434/435 (north of Highway 200). A &lt;b&gt;Pre-evacuation notice&lt;/b&gt; was given to residences located near Elk Meadows subdivision (about mile-marker 93) along Hwy 200 up to mile-marker 98. A Red Cross shelter is available in Helena at First Assembly of God Church (2210 Dodge Ave.) if needed. Please call 1-800-272-6668 for assistance. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="'Times New Roman'" size="3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;ROAD CLOSURES: &lt;/b&gt;Lewis and Clark Co. Sheriff officers established road blocks at Elk Meadows driveway, the intersection of Hwy. 200 and Hwy. 434 and the intersection of Flat Creek Rd and Hwy. 434 to prevent unnecessary traffic from entering the fire area. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="'Times New Roman'"&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;TRAIL &amp;amp; AREA CLOSURES: &lt;/b&gt;Due to the fire activity, an area closure is in place that affects multiple trails and roads. A trail re-route is established for hikers along the Continental Divide National Scenic Trail. A map of the area closure is posted at: &lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/article/5410/39087/"&gt;&lt;font color="#0000ff" size="3"&gt;https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/article/5410/39087/&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="'Times New Roman'"&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;MORE INFORMATION: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;Facebook at &lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/HLCNF/"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;www.facebook.com/HLCNF/&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="'Times New Roman'" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content></entry></feed>