<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Montana Fires - Alice Creek Fire (Wildfire)</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/alice-creek-fire-wildfire.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2017-09-01T09:48:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>National Guard Boeing CH-47 Chinook helicopters arrive on Alice Creek Fire (Alice Creek Fire Wildfire)</title><link href="/5410_39598.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-01T09:48:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-01T09:48:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:None,2017-09-01:/5410_39598.html</id><summary type="html">A COMMUNITY MEETING WILL BE HELD AT THE WOLF CREEK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, TONIGHT AT 6 P.M. ALL ARE WELCOME TO ATTEND.  AUGUSTA, MT – Two National Guard Boeing CH-47 Chinook helicopters arrived Thursday afternoon to provide air support to firefighters on the Alice Creek Fire. These very fast helicopters are able to carry up to 2,000 gallons of water per load and can fly for two-and- a-half hours before needing to refuel. Throughout the duration of this fire, firefighters have relied heavily on helicopters to drop water to cool the fire. With their massive water capacity, these helicopters are a welcome asset. These very large helicopters may catch the eye of drivers along Hwy. 200. Please do not stop along the roadway to look at the aircraft dipping as it may be dangerous to other drivers. Like yesterday, meteorologists are forecasting erratic 34 mph wind gusts that may pulse throughout the fire area most of the day. The National Weather Service extended the Red Flag warning through...</summary><content type="html">A COMMUNITY MEETING WILL BE HELD AT THE WOLF CREEK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, TONIGHT AT 6 P.M. ALL ARE WELCOME TO ATTEND.  AUGUSTA, MT – Two National Guard Boeing CH-47 Chinook helicopters arrived Thursday afternoon to provide air support to firefighters on the Alice Creek Fire. These very fast helicopters are able to carry up to 2,000 gallons of water per load and can fly for two-and- a-half hours before needing to refuel. Throughout the duration of this fire, firefighters have relied heavily on helicopters to drop water to cool the fire. With their massive water capacity, these helicopters are a welcome asset. These very large helicopters may catch the eye of drivers along Hwy. 200. Please do not stop along the roadway to look at the aircraft dipping as it may be dangerous to other drivers. Like yesterday, meteorologists are forecasting erratic 34 mph wind gusts that may pulse throughout the fire area most of the day. The National Weather Service extended the Red Flag warning through...</content></entry></feed>