<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Montana Fires - Burdette Fire</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/feeds/burdette-fire.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/</id><updated>2017-08-31T11:33:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Smoke Forecast Outlook issued August 31, 2017 at 11:03 AM EDT</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5378_39516.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-31T11:33:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-08-31T11:33:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-08-31:/montana_fires/5378_39516.html</id><summary type="html">Smoke Forecast Outlook issued August 31, 2017 at 11:03 AM EDTOutlook for SunriseSmoke: A dry cold front will bring westerly winds and some relief from smoke as well as cooler morningtemperatures. Much of the forecast area will remain “Moderate” for Thursday, Missoula is the exception at"USG". Smoke is expected to filter back into valley locations overnight and remain through Friday morning.Fire: The Sunrise fire is located 11 miles SE of Superior, MT adjacent to I-90. A red flag warning is in effect. Minimalfire growth observed on the fire Wednesday. Increase in acreage is not expected on the Sunrise fire.Other: A Red Flag Warning for potential new lightning starts and gusty winds is in effect until 9pm tonight. Breezywest winds today following a weather disturbance bringing slightly cooler temperatures. Very hot and dry critical fireweather conditions remain. Expect an increase in fire behavior. Air quality has improved across the forecast areaand is expected to remain in the...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Smoke Forecast Outlook issued August 31, 2017 at 11:03 AM EDT&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Burdette Fire Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 2 days ago&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Smoke Forecast Outlook issued August 31, 2017 at 11:03 AM EDT&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Outlook for Sunrise&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Smoke: A dry cold front will bring westerly winds and some relief from smoke as well as cooler morning&lt;br/&gt;temperatures. Much of the forecast area will remain “Moderate” for Thursday, Missoula is the exception at&lt;br/&gt;"USG". Smoke is expected to filter back into valley locations overnight and remain through Friday morning.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Fire: The Sunrise fire is located 11 miles SE of Superior, MT adjacent to I-90. A red flag warning is in effect. Minimal&lt;br/&gt;fire growth observed on the fire Wednesday. Increase in acreage is not expected on the Sunrise fire.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Other: A Red Flag Warning for potential new lightning starts and gusty winds is in effect until 9pm tonight. Breezy&lt;br/&gt;west winds today following a weather disturbance bringing slightly cooler temperatures. Very hot and dry critical fire&lt;br/&gt;weather conditions remain. Expect an increase in fire behavior. Air quality has improved across the forecast area&lt;br/&gt;and is expected to remain in the “Moderate” range for Superior, Alberton, and Frenchtown. Missoula’s air quality&lt;br/&gt;will be best represented by “USG”. If you live within Missoula County, please refer to the Missoula City-County Health Department for detailed smoke health information&lt;br/&gt;(see link below).&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Additional Links&lt;br/&gt;DEQ Today's Air Missoula County Air Quality Updates&lt;br/&gt;Outdoor Activity Recommendations Health effects categories and visibility&lt;br/&gt;ArcGIS Wildfire Maps Inciweb Sunrise&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://wildlandfiresmoke.net/outlooks/2017/Montana#Area2" target="_self"&gt;http://wildlandfiresmoke.net/outlooks/2017/Montana#Area2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content></entry></feed>