<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Montana Fires - Granite County</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/feeds/granite-county.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/</id><updated>2017-09-12T12:28:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Meyers Sapphire Smoke Report for 9-12-17</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5397_40828.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-12T12:28:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-12T12:28:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-12:/montana_fires/5397_40828.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><content type="html"></content><category term="Meyers Fire"></category></entry><entry><title>Meyers Sapphire Complex Update for 9-12-17</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5397_40825.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-12T12:16:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-12T12:16:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-12:/montana_fires/5397_40825.html</id><summary type="html">A public meeting will be held tonight at 6:30 p.m. at the Wise River Community Center east of the Meyers Fire.  Although yesterday was an active fire day in several locations on the Meyers Fire and Sapphire Complex, there was minimal fire growth. Today, helicopters will be used to cool hot spots and monitor fire activity.  Sapphire Complex: 43,739 acres Location: Approximately 25 miles south-southeast of Missoula  Containment: 58% Cause: Lightning Total Personnel: 195  Three fires comprise the Sapphire Complex: Little Hogback, Goat Creek, and Sliderock. The fires are in steep, rocky terrain between Rock Creek and Upper Willow Creek drainages.  Little Hogback Fire: 34,539 acres  The east side of the fire is in patrol status with some rehabilitation starting on the north side. Firefighters continue to secure the south-central part of the fire’s periphery where active fire remains. There is also active fire on the northwest side and structure protection along Rock Creek Road is a...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Meyers Sapphire Complex Update for 9-12-17&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Meyers Fire Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 14 min. ago&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- 
cached related article links at 12:30:16
cached id d51b841a05e13d871d0b1f2db598de3b
--&gt;
&lt;div id="related_block"&gt;&lt;h4 id="related_head"&gt;Related Information&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul class="related_list"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/photos/MTBDF/2017-07-20-1925-Meyers-Fire/related_files/pict20170812-122022-0.pdf" rel="new"&gt;Printable copy of 9-12-17 Update (pdf 202 kb)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/photos/MTBDF/2017-07-20-1925-Meyers-Fire/related_files/pict20170812-122403-0.pdf" rel="new"&gt;Meyers Sapphire Smoke Report 9-12-17 Meyers East (pdf 193 kb)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/photos/MTBDF/2017-07-20-1925-Meyers-Fire/related_files/pict20170812-122534-0.pdf" rel="new"&gt;Meyers Sapphire Smoke Report 9-12-17 Bitterroot (pdf 182 kb)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p align="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;A public meeting will be held tonight at 6:30 p.m. at the Wise River Community Center east of the Meyers Fire. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although yesterday was an active fire day in several locations on the Meyers Fire and Sapphire Complex, there was minimal fire growth. Today, helicopters will be used to cool hot spots and monitor fire activity. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sapphire Complex: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;43,739 acres &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;Location: &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;Approximately 25 miles south-southeast of Missoula &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Containment: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;58% &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;Cause: &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;Lightning &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;Total Personnel: &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;195 &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;p&gt;Three fires comprise the Sapphire Complex: Little Hogback, Goat Creek, and Sliderock. The fires are in steep, rocky terrain between Rock Creek and Upper Willow Creek drainages. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Little Hogback Fire: 34,539 acres &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The east side of the fire is in patrol status with some rehabilitation starting on the north side. Firefighters continue to secure the south-central part of the fire’s periphery where active fire remains. There is also active fire on the northwest side and structure protection along Rock Creek Road is a priority, particularly in the Idle Ranches subdivision. Structures are prepped and sprinklers are in place to protect residences. Helicopters continue water drops to help keep fire growth in check. Unburned pockets in the interior continue to burn but this fire should be in monitoring and patrol status soon. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Goat Creek Fire: 8,300 acres &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Firefighters continue rehabilitation of constructed fire breaks and some heat remains in the interior. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sliderock Fire: 900 acres &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;p&gt;There has been no growth in the overall size of this fire; any hot spots are in the fire interior. Rehabilitation of constructed firelines will follow after this work is completed for the Goat Creek Fire. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Meyers Fire: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;61,885 acres &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;Location: &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;Approximately 25 miles southwest of Philipsburg, Montana &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Containment: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;8% &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;Cause: &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;Lightning &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;Total Personnel: &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;373 &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;p&gt;The fire is burning in mixed conifer stands, primarily lodgepole pine, Douglas-fir, and subalpine fir, with many standing dead trees. These snags have become increasingly dangerous to firefighters as they burn through and get pushed over by wind. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Carpp Creek drainage at the eastern part of the fire remains a high priority. Helicopters will continue to monitor this area and make water drops as needed to keep spot fires in check and hold the fire south of the creek. Structure protection measures ahead of this drainage, particularly at Moose Lake, continue to be monitored for readiness. Contingency fire breaks between there and Georgetown Lake are being assessed for any remaining prep work. Crews continue to mop-up and secure some areas of concern around the fire, including southeast of Zeke’s Meadows. The Twin Sisters area had some fire activity yesterday and helicopter water drops helped cool hot spots on that flank. Active fire is working its way down the East Fork of the Bitterroot drainage and fireline construction continues around the Billie Springer Memorial and Bonanza Lands subdivisions. Work on these firebreaks has taken longer than expected, but should be complete in the next few days. At the south end of the fire where it has crossed the Continental Divide into the Wise River Ranger District in Beaverhead and Deerlodge counties, exposed rocky areas have slowed growth. This area will continue to be monitored from the air, but incident managers do not anticipate significant fire growth there. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;p&gt;Resources Threatened &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sapphire Complex: &lt;/b&gt;Private property and structures in the Rock Creek, Upper Willow Creek, and Marshall Creek and East Bitterroot drainages remain at risk. Other resources threatened include fisheries in Rock Creek, grazing lands along the southern boundary of the Little Hogback Fire, Bonneville Power Administration powerline, and a communication site. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Meyers Fire: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;Private property and structures in the Moose Lake, Frog Pond, Billie Springer Memorial Park, and Bonanza Lands areas, as well as other scattered dwellings are still at risk and continue to be prepped and monitored. Nearby grazing land also remains a concern. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Evacuations &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sapphire Complex: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;A mandatory evacuation (Level Red) order for approximately fifty-six structures along Upper Rock Creek Road remains in effect. It starts at and includes Wild Rose Loop south to Stony Creek. Pre-evacuation (Level Yellow) notices remain in effect for Upper Rock Creek Road from Stony Creek south to the Kyle G. Bohrnsen Memorial Bridge. It includes residences on the lower Cornish Gulch Road and Basin Gulch Road, and Upper Rock Creek Road residences from Bobcat Creek south to Hogback Homestead. Pre-evacuation orders have been lifted for the Marshall Creek subdivision, Upper Willow Creek north from the intersection of Upper Rock Creek Road and the Upper Willow Creek Road, and the Rock Creek drainage from Babcock Creek south to Bobcat Creek. For information on evacuation planning refer to the Ready-Set-Go materials available at http://www.wildlandfirersg.org/Portals/18/Resources/States/MT/RSG_Montana_ActionGuide_web.pdf &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Meyers Fire: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;The Frog Pond and Moose Lake areas are still under a mandatory evacuation order and the Billie Springer Memorial and Bonanza subdivisions are under warning for evacuation. Additionally, an evacuation warning is in effect on East Fork Road from FS Road 5778 to Little East Fork Rd (FS Rd 724) on the Bitterroot National Forest. Those under an evacuation warning should be prepared to leave at a moment’s notice. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Closures &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Closures are in place to protect the public from potential harm from wildfires and firefighting operations. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sapphire Complex: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;The Rock Creek Road from I-90 south to Bitterroot Campground (MP 23.5) is OPEN. Due to fire traffic congestion and fire safety concerns, Rock Creek Road will stay CLOSED from Bitterroot Campground, south to Cornish Gulch (FSR5027), and public traffic is NOT allowed. The Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest reduced closure restrictions in the Black Pine ridge area, but maintains all area closures in Upper Willow Creek, North Fork Lower Willow Creek, and Harvey Creek areas. Upper Willow Creek Road remains closed to the public. The Lolo National Forest still has area closures east and north of Rock Creek Road, south of I-90 and east to the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest boundary. The Bureau of Land Management has an area closure in Upper Willow Creek, Ram Mountain, and nearby areas. The Lolo and Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forests, the Bureau of Land Management, and the Montana Department of Natural Resources (DNRC) closure orders and maps are posted under the closures tab on Inciweb. A temporary flight restriction (TFR) remains in effect surrounding the Little Hogback Fire area. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Meyers Fire: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;Bitterroot National Forest emergency closure orders are still in effect for upper areas of the East Fork Bitterroot River. The expanded Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest closure also remains in effect. On the south side of the fire, the closure extends between Bender Creek and LaMarche Creek, including Pintler Campground and Trailhead, Mystic Trailhead, Mussigbrod Campground and Trailhead, and all trailheads in the Mudd Creek and Fishtrap Creek areas. Several miles of the Continental Divide Trail are closed. A TFR is still in place surrounding the Meyers Fire area. Granite County is under Stage 2 fire restrictions for private lands in the county. Amended Stage 1 fire restrictions are in effect prohibiting &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;ALL &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;campfires in southwestern Montana on public lands, including in fire rings and developed recreation areas. For fire restriction details, visit firerestrictions.us/mt. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Weather &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;p&gt;High pressure will begin to move east today, bringing a chance of showers and thunderstorms late today into Wednesday morning. Cooler and wetter weather will settle over western Montana through Saturday. Snow elevation could drop from 9000 feet Thursday evening down to 6000 feet by Saturday morning. Today’s high temperatures will be in the mid-70s on the Meyers Fire and high-80s to low-90s on the Hogback Fire. Humidity will be in the teens in the valleys and high teens to low-20s at upper elevations. Southwest winds at 10-15 mph are expected by late morning. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;For further information&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;, visit https://inciweb.nwcg.gov and select "Meyers Fire" or "Sapphire Complex" in Montana, and follow the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest Facebook, Bitterroot National Forest Facebook or Lolo National Forest pages. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Meyers Fire"></category></entry><entry><title>Some Pre-Evacuation Orders Lifted for Little Hogback Fire</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5364_40738.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-11T13:44:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-11T13:44:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-11:/montana_fires/5364_40738.html</id><summary type="html">The Granite County Sheriff has lifted pre-evacuation orders for the following areas in the vicinity of the Little Hogback Fire: Marshall Creek subdivision, Upper Willow Creek north from the intersection of Upper Rock Creek Road and the Upper Willow Creek Road, and the Rock Creek drainage from Babcock Creek south to Bobcat Creek.    A mandatory evacuation (Level Red) order for approximately thirty-five residences along Upper Rock Creek Road remains in effect, beginning from and including Wild Rose Loop south to Stony Creek. Pre-evacuation (Level Yellow) notices remain in effect for Upper Rock Creek Road from Stony Creek south to Kyle G. Bohrnsen Memorial Bridge, including residences on the lower Cornish Gulch Road and Basin Gulch Road, and for Upper Rock Creek Road residences from Bobcat Creek south to Hogback Homestead.</summary><content type="html">The Granite County Sheriff has lifted pre-evacuation orders for the following areas in the vicinity of the Little Hogback Fire: Marshall Creek subdivision, Upper Willow Creek north from the intersection of Upper Rock Creek Road and the Upper Willow Creek Road, and the Rock Creek drainage from Babcock Creek south to Bobcat Creek.    A mandatory evacuation (Level Red) order for approximately thirty-five residences along Upper Rock Creek Road remains in effect, beginning from and including Wild Rose Loop south to Stony Creek. Pre-evacuation (Level Yellow) notices remain in effect for Upper Rock Creek Road from Stony Creek south to Kyle G. Bohrnsen Memorial Bridge, including residences on the lower Cornish Gulch Road and Basin Gulch Road, and for Upper Rock Creek Road residences from Bobcat Creek south to Hogback Homestead.</content><category term="Sapphire Complex"></category></entry><entry><title>Meyers Sapphire Complex Update for September 11, 2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5364_40735.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-11T13:04:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-11T13:04:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-11:/montana_fires/5364_40735.html</id><summary type="html">A public meeting will be held on Tuesday, September 12 at 6:30 p.m. at the Wise River Community Center east of the Meyers Fire.  Some pre-evacuation notices have been lifted for the Sapphire Complex. See "Evacuations" below.  Sapphire Complex: 43,642 acres Location: Approximately 25 miles south-southeast of Missoula  Containment: 59% Cause: Lightning Total Personnel: 196  Three fires comprise the Sapphire Complex: Little Hogback, Goat Creek, and Sliderock. The fires are in steep, rocky terrain between Rock Creek and Upper Willow Creek drainages.  Little Hogback Fire: 34,439 acres  The east side of the fire remains in patrol status. There is still a small area of active fire at the south-central part of the fire’s periphery; firefighters continue working to secure that edge. Fire is active along the western flank. Helicopter water drops yesterday kept westward fire growth in check. Unburned pockets in the interior continue to burn. Structure protection along Rock Creek Road remains...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Meyers Sapphire Complex Update for September 11, 2017&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Sapphire Complex Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 26 min. ago&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- 
cached related article links at 13:30:16
cached id c05fa72d846df5b3f98630d05a570bc5
--&gt;
&lt;div id="related_block"&gt;&lt;h4 id="related_head"&gt;Related Information&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul class="related_list"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/photos/MTLNF/2017-07-14-1837-Slide-Rock-Fire/related_files/pict20170811-132345-0.pdf" rel="new"&gt;Meyers Sapphire Complex Update for Sept. 11, 2017 (pdf 336 kb)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p align="LEFT"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;A public meeting will be held on Tuesday, September 12 at 6:30 p.m. at the Wise River Community Center east of the Meyers Fire. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt; &lt;p&gt;Some pre-evacuation notices have been lifted for the Sapphire Complex. See "Evacuations" below. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sapphire Complex: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;43,642 acres &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;Location: &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;Approximately 25 miles south-southeast of Missoula &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Containment: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;59% &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;Cause: &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;Lightning &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;Total Personnel: &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;196 &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt; &lt;p&gt;Three fires comprise the Sapphire Complex: Little Hogback, Goat Creek, and Sliderock. The fires are in steep, rocky terrain between Rock Creek and Upper Willow Creek drainages. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Little Hogback Fire: 34,439 acres &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The east side of the fire remains in patrol status. There is still a small area of active fire at the south-central part of the fire’s periphery; firefighters continue working to secure that edge. Fire is active along the western flank. Helicopter water drops yesterday kept westward fire growth in check. Unburned pockets in the interior continue to burn. Structure protection along Rock Creek Road remains a priority, particularly in the Idle Ranches subdivision. Sprinklers are still in place and functioning to protect nearby residences. This fire should be in monitoring/patrol soon. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Goat Creek Fire: 8,300 acres &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Any heat remaining is in the interior. Firefighters continue rehabilitation of constructed fire breaks. The incident team established a spike camp nearby to support remaining efforts on this fire as well as the Sliderock and Little Hogback fires. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sliderock Fire: 900 acres &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;&lt;p&gt;There has been no growth in the overall size of this fire; any hot spots are in the fire interior. Rehabilitation of constructed firelines will follow after this work is completed for the Goat Creek Fire. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Meyers Fire: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;60,792 acres &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;Location: &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;Approximately 25 miles southwest of Philipsburg, Montana &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Containment: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;8% &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;Cause: &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;Lightning &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;Total Personnel: &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;378 &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt; &lt;p&gt;The fire is burning in mixed conifer stands, primarily lodgepole pine, Douglas-fir, and subalpine fir, with many standing dead trees. These snags have become increasingly dangerous to firefighters as they burn through and get pushed over by wind. There are residences still at risk including those in the Moose Lake, Frog Pond, Billie Springer Memorial Park and Bonanza Lands areas. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Carpp Creek drainage at the eastern part of the fire remains a high priority today. Helicopters will continue to monitor this area and make water drops as needed to keep spot fires in check and hold the fire south of the creek. Structure protection measures ahead of this drainage, particularly at Moose Lake, continue to be monitored for readiness. Contingency fire breaks between there and Georgetown Lake are being assessed for any remaining prep work. Crews continued to mop-up and secure some areas of concern around the fire, including southeast of Zeke’s Meadows, and on the west flank including the Frog Pond area, which had minimal activity Sunday. Some helicopter water drops helped cool hot spots on that flank. Firefighters may burn out small pockets of unburned fuel in these areas to better secure the fire periphery, given safe conditions. Fireline construction is nearing completion around the East Fork Bitterroot communities. Work on these firebreaks should be done in the next day or two. Exposed rocky areas have slowed growth at the south end of the fire where it had crossed the Continental Divide into the Wise River Ranger District in Beaverhead and Deerlodge counties. This area will continue to be monitored from the air, although incident managers do not anticipate significant fire growth there. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Resources Threatened &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sapphire Complex: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;Private property and structures in the Rock Creek, Upper Willow Creek, and Marshall Creek drainages remain threatened. Other resources threatened include fisheries in Rock Creek, grazing lands along the southern boundary of the Little Hogback Fire, Bonneville Power Administration powerline, and a communication site. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Meyers Fire: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;Private property and structures in the Moose Lake, Frog Pond, Billie Springer Memorial Park, Bonanza Lands areas, as well as other scattered individual dwellings continue to be monitored and prepped. Nearby grazing lands also remain a concern. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Evacuations &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sapphire Complex: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;A mandatory evacuation (Level Red) order for approximately thirty-five residences along Upper Rock Creek Road remains in effect, beginning from and including Wild Rose Loop south to Stony Creek. Pre-evacuation (Level Yellow) notices remain in effect for Upper Rock Creek Road from Stony Creek south to Kyle G. Bohrnsen Memorial Bridge, including residences on the lower Cornish Gulch Road and Basin Gulch Road, and for Upper Rock Creek Road residences from Bobcat Creek south to Hogback Homestead. Pre-evacuation orders have been lifted for the Marshall Creek subdivision, Upper Willow Creek north from the intersection of Upper Rock Creek Road and the Upper Willow Creek Road, and the Rock Creek drainage from Babcock Creek south to Bobcat Creek. For information on evacuation planning refer to the Ready-Set-Go materials available at http://www.wildlandfirersg.org/Portals/18/Resources/States/MT/RSG_Montana_ActionGuide_web.pdf &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Meyers Fire: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;The Frog Pond and Moose Lake areas are still under an evacuation order. Additionally, an evacuation warning is in effect on East Fork Rd from FS Rd 5778 to Little East Fork Rd (FS RD 724) on the Bitterroot National Forest. Those under an evacuation warning should be prepared to leave at a moment’s notice. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Closures &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sapphire Complex: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;The Rock Creek Road from I-90 south to Bitterroot Campground (MP 23.5) is OPEN. Due to fire traffic congestion and fire safety concerns, Rock Creek Road will stay CLOSED from Bitterroot Campground, south to Cornish Gulch (FSR5027), and public traffic is NOT allowed. Upper Willow Creek Road is currently closed to the public. The Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest reduced closure restrictions in the Black Pine ridge area, but maintains all area closures in Upper Willow Creek, North Fork Lower Willow Creek, and Harvey Creek areas. The Bureau of Land Management has an area closure in Upper Willow Creek, Ram Mountain, and nearby areas. The Lolo and Beaverhead- Deerlodge National Forests, the Bureau of Land Management, and the Montana Department of Natural Resources (DNRC) closure orders and maps are posted under the closures tab on Inciweb. A temporary flight restriction (TFR) remains in effect surrounding the Little Hogback Fire area. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Meyers Fire: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;Bitterroot National Forest emergency closure orders are still in effect for upper areas of the East Fork Bitterroot River. The expanded Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest closure also remains in effect. On the south side of the fire, the closure extends between Bender Creek and LaMarche Creek, including Pintler Campground and Trailhead, Mystic Trailhead, Mussigbrod Campground and Trailhead, and all trailheads in the Mudd Creek and Fishtrap Creek areas. Several miles of the Continental Divide Trail are closed. A TFR is still in place surrounding the Meyers Fire area. Granite County is under Stage 2 fire restrictions for private lands in the county. Amended Stage 1 fire restrictions are in effect prohibiting &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;ALL &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;campfires in southwestern Montana on public lands, including in fire rings and developed recreation areas. For fire restriction details, visit firerestrictions.us/mt. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Weather &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Building high pressure will bring warmer high temperatures, lower humidity, and less wind. Stronger overnight inversions will form, dropping temperatures to near freezing at lower elevations, persisting longer in the day, and holding more smoke in the valleys. The afternoon will be breezy, especially above 6500 feet. Much cooler and wetter weather will settle in over western Montana Wednesday through Saturday. Snow elevation could drop from 9000 feet Thursday evening to 7500 feet Friday, and 6500 feet on Saturday. Thunderstorms are possible Tuesday night through Wednesday night. Today’s high temperature will be in the mid-70s on the Meyers Fire and mid-80s on the Hogback Fire, but a little cooler at higher elevations. Humidity may dip below 20% in the valleys; mid to upper 20s at upper elevations. Southwest winds at 10-15 mph are expected by late morning. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;For further information&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;, follow the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest Facebook, Bitterroot National Forest Facebook &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;or &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman,Times New Roman PSMT" size="3"&gt;Lolo National Forest pages. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Sapphire Complex"></category></entry><entry><title>Meyers Sapphire Complex Smoke Report for 09.11.17</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5364_40691.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-11T10:01:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-11T10:01:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-11:/montana_fires/5364_40691.html</id><summary type="html">Meyers Sapphire Complex Smoke Report for</summary><content type="html">Meyers Sapphire Complex Smoke Report for</content><category term="Sapphire Complex"></category></entry><entry><title>Meyers Sapphire Smoke Report for 9-11-17</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5397_40686.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-11T09:32:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-11T09:32:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-11:/montana_fires/5397_40686.html</id><summary type="html">Meyers Sapphire Smoke Report for</summary><content type="html">Meyers Sapphire Smoke Report for</content><category term="Meyers Fire"></category></entry><entry><title>Meyers Sapphire Update for September 10, 2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5397_40642.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-10T15:07:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-10T15:07:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-10:/montana_fires/5397_40642.html</id><summary type="html">A public meeting will be held on Tuesday, September 12 at 6:30 p.m. at the Wise River Community Center east of the Meyers Fire.  Despite red flag conditions yesterday, fire activity was low for most parts of the Meyers Fire and the Sapphire Complex.  Sapphire Complex: 43,642 acres Location: Approximately 25 miles south-southeast of Missoula Containment: 59% Cause: Lightning Total Personnel: 238  Three fires comprise the Sapphire Complex: Little Hogback, Goat Creek, and Sliderock. The fires are in steep, rocky terrain between Rock Creek and Upper Willow Creek drainages.  Little Hogback Fire: 34,442 acres  Some mop-up continues on hot spots along the southwest and south sides. Isolated areas of heat remain along the remainder of the perimeter; crews will continue monitoring for and addressing hot spots as needed. Unburned pockets in the interior continue to burn, especially in the northwest part of the fire well away from the perimeter. Structure protection along Rock Creek Road remains...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Meyers Sapphire Update for September 10, 2017&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Meyers Fire Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 23 min. ago&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- 
cached related article links at 15:30:15
cached id 2849d02405232403329254b4805ab807
--&gt;
&lt;div id="related_block"&gt;&lt;h4 id="related_head"&gt;Related Information&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul class="related_list"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/photos/MTBDF/2017-07-20-1925-Meyers-Fire/related_files/pict20170810-151058-0.pdf" rel="new"&gt;Meyers Sapphire Update for 09.10.17 (pdf 135 kb)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;A public meeting will be held on Tuesday, September 12 at 6:30 p.m. at the Wise River Community Center east of the Meyers Fire. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Despite red flag conditions yesterday, fire activity was low for most parts of the Meyers Fire and the Sapphire Complex. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Sapphire Complex: 43,642 acres Location: Approximately 25 miles south-southeast of Missoula Containment: 59% Cause: Lightning Total Personnel: 238 &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Three fires comprise the Sapphire Complex: Little Hogback, Goat Creek, and Sliderock. The fires are in steep, rocky terrain between Rock Creek and Upper Willow Creek drainages. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Little Hogback Fire: 34,442 acres &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Some mop-up continues on hot spots along the southwest and south sides. Isolated areas of heat remain along the remainder of the perimeter; crews will continue monitoring for and addressing hot spots as needed. Unburned pockets in the interior continue to burn, especially in the northwest part of the fire well away from the perimeter. Structure protection along Rock Creek Road remains a priority. Incident managers hope to shift from mop-up and patrolling to monitoring soon. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Goat Creek Fire: 8,300 acres &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;No substantial growth has been detected. Significant heat remains only in the interior and at a few spots on the east flank. Firefighters have shifted from mop-up to rehabilitation of constructed fire breaks. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Sliderock Fire: 900 acres &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There has been no growth in the overall size of this fire; any hot spots are in the fire interior. Rehabilitation of constructed firelines will follow after this work is completed for the Goat Creek Fire. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Meyers Fire: 60,254 acres Location: Approximately 25 miles southwest of Philipsburg, Montana Containment: 0% Cause: Lightning Total Personnel: 395 &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The fire is burning in mixed conifer stands, primarily lodgepole pine, Douglas-fir, and subalpine fir, with many standing dead trees. These snags have become increasingly dangerous to firefighters as they burn through and fall with stronger winds. There are residences still at risk including those in the Moose Lake, Frog Pond, Billie Springer Memorial Park and Bonanza Lands areas. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The fire spotted north across Carpp Creek in the eastern part of the fire, but with diminished smoke cover, helicopters were able to make water drops there to keep the spot fires in check. Crews continued to mop-up and secure some areas of concern around the fire, including southeast of Zeke’s Meadows, and on the west flank including the Frog Pond area, which had minimal activity yesterday. Fireline construction is about 2/3 complete around the East Fork Bitterroot communities. Exposed rocky areas have slowed growth at the south end of the fire. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There are two areas of the fire located in the Wise River Ranger District. One area, between Howell Creek and Beaver Creek in Beaverhead County, was active yesterday but showed minimal growth. The second area, between West Fork Fishtrap Creek and West Fork LaMarche Creek in Deerlodge County, is burning in a very rocky area with sparse fuels. These areas will continue to be monitored. Necessary preparations are being taken to protect structures that could be affected. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Structure protection continues to be the priority on the fire after firefighter and public safety. For Sunday, firefighters will focus on the northeast part of the fire and the Carpp Creek drainage, concentrating on keeping the spot fires detected yesterday in check. Firefighters will continue to improve firelines in the Billie Springer Memorial and Bonanza subdivisions as well as other private properties in the area, with hopes of completing these lines in the next two or three days. The southeast part of the fire will be patrolled primarily by air, weather permitting. Firefighters may burn out small pockets of unburned fuel southeast of Zeke’s Meadows to better secure that border, given safe conditions. Across the divide to the southeast, structure protection is being completed on the Bender and Mystic Lake cabins. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Resources Threatened &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Sapphire Complex: Private property and structures in the Rock Creek, Upper Willow Creek, and Marshall Creek drainages remain threatened. Other resources threatened include fisheries in Rock Creek, grazing lands along the southern boundary of the Little Hogback Fire, Bonneville Power Administration powerline, and a communication site. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Meyers Fire: Private property and structures in the Moose Lake, Frog Pond, Billie Springer Memorial Park, Bonanza Lake areas, as well as other scattered individual dwellings continue to be monitored and prepped. Nearby grazing lands also remain a concern. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Evacuations &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Sapphire Complex: A mandatory evacuation (Level Red) order for approximately thirty-five residences along Rock Creek Road remains in effect, beginning from and including Wild Rose Loop south to Stony Creek. Other pre-evacuation (Level Yellow) notices are still in effect. For information on evacuation planning refer to the Ready-Set-Go materials available at http://www.wildlandfirersg.org/Portals/18/Resources/States/MT/RSG_Montana_ActionGuide_web.pdf &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Meyers Fire: The Frog Pond and Moose Lake areas are still under an evacuation order. Additionally, an evacuation warning is in effect on East Fork Rd from FS Rd 5778 to Little East Fork Rd (FS RD 724) on the Bitterroot National Forest. Those under an evacuation warning should be prepared to leave at a moment’s notice. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Closures &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Sapphire Complex: The Rock Creek Road from I-90 south to Bitterroot Campground (MP 23.5) is OPEN. Due to fire traffic congestion and fire safety concerns, Rock Creek Road will stay CLOSED from Bitterroot Campground, south to Cornish Gulch (FSR5027), and public traffic is NOT allowed. Upper Willow Creek Road is currently closed to the public. The Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest reduced closure restrictions in the Black Pine ridge area, but maintains all area closures in Upper Willow Creek, North Fork Lower Willow Creek, and Harvey Creek areas. The Bureau of Land Management has an area closure in Upper Willow Creek, Ram Mountain, and nearby areas. The Lolo and Beaverhead- Deerlodge National Forests, the Bureau of Land Management, and the Montana Department of Natural Resources (DNRC) closure orders and maps are posted under the closures tab on Inciweb. A temporary flight restriction (TFR) remains in effect surrounding the Little Hogback Fire area. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Meyers Fire: Bitterroot National Forest emergency closure orders are still in effect for upper areas of the East Fork Bitterroot River. The expanded Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest closure also remains in effect. On the south side of the fire, the closure extends between Bender Creek and LaMarche Creek, including Pintler Campground and Trailhead, Mystic Trailhead, Mussigbrod Campground and Trailhead, and all trailheads in the Mudd Creek and Fishtrap Creek areas. Several miles of the Continental Divide Trail are closed. A temporary flight restriction (TFR) is still in place surrounding the Meyers Fire area. Granite County is under Stage 2 fire restrictions for private lands in the county. Amended Stage 1 fire restrictions are in effect prohibiting ALL campfires in southwestern Montana on public lands, including in fire rings and developed recreation areas. For fire restriction details, visit firerestrictions.us/mt. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Please adhere to all closures and allow our firefighters to perform their jobs safely. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Weather &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Building high pressure will bring warmer temperatures, lower humidity, and diminished winds. Today, precipitation chance is 10%, with high temps in the upper 70s to low 80s, and humidity bottoming out about 22%. Southwest winds will be 10-15 mph in the morning, increasing to 15-20 mph. Southwesterly ridgetop winds are predicted at 15-20 mph. A stronger overnight inversion will persist later in the day tomorrow, and will bring near or below-freezing overnight lows below the inversion. Consequently, low areas should hold more smoke. &lt;/p&gt; For further information, visit https://inciweb.nwcg.gov and select “Meyers Fire” or “Sapphire Complex” in Montana, and follow the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest Facebook, Bitterroot National Forest Facebook or Lolo National Forest pages.
		&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Meyers Fire"></category></entry><entry><title>Sapphire Complex Update 09-10-17</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5364_40643.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-10T15:01:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-10T15:01:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-10:/montana_fires/5364_40643.html</id><summary type="html">Meyers Sapphire Complex Fire Information via gmail.mcsv.net 11:43 AM (2 hours ago)to meView this email in your browserSeptember 10th, 2017Sapphire ComplexAcres: 43,642Location: Approximately 25 miles south-southeast of MissoulaContainment: 59%Cause: LightningTotal Personnel: 238Three fires comprise the Sapphire Complex: Little Hogback, Goat Creek, and Sliderock. The fires are burning in steep, rocky terrain between Rock Creek and Upper Willow Creek drainages.Little Hogback Fire: 34,442 acresSome mop-up continues on hot spots along the southwest and south sides. Isolated areas of heat remain along the remainder of the perimeter; crews will continue monitoring for and addressing hot spots as needed. Unburned pockets in the interior continue to burn, especially in the northwest part of the fire well away from the perimeter. Structure protection along Rock Creek Road remains a priority. Incident managers hope to shift from mop-up and patrolling to monitoring soon.Goat Creek Fire: 8,300...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sapphire Complex Update 09-10-17&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Sapphire Complex Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 29 min. ago&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- 
cached related article links at 15:30:15
cached id 716df6e9588a54bdb58460f5b67e3b24
--&gt;
&lt;div id="related_block"&gt;&lt;h4 id="related_head"&gt;Related Information&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul class="related_list"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/photos/MTLNF/2017-07-14-1837-Slide-Rock-Fire/related_files/pict20170810-151232-0.pdf" rel="new"&gt;Sapphire Comple Update 09-10-17 (pdf 244 kb)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br class="Apple-interchange-newline"/&gt;&lt;img align="center" alt="" class="m_-37292294381264390mcnImage CToWUd" src="https://ci6.googleusercontent.com/proxy/TQAdECqAHo54Rfm3T5YvYEC3Ui5t77nJMxig_G15wOD_nzEqSx7lp_97R0BKDH8u_09u4zchRwDAOMVNGA9S03gje5JDLw-ICgznMOdzxaRapRa42zY6sGVB0DVYGSvzvfkoevwHj44dUFznB1ZQ6HrsImF_EHLsTLDh9f8=s0-d-e1-ft#https://gallery.mailchimp.com/108753bc5ec436d34890f75c4/images/a0bc1390-e8ad-480e-af8e-559f9e24fc3b.jpg" style="border: 0px currentColor; border-image: none; height: auto; padding-bottom: 0px; text-decoration: none; vertical-align: bottom; display: inline !important; max-width: 605px;" width="564"/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Sapphire Complex"></category></entry><entry><title>Meyers Sapphire Complex Update for 09.10.17</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5364_40636.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-10T13:27:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-10T13:27:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-10:/montana_fires/5364_40636.html</id><summary type="html">A public meeting will be held on Tuesday, September 12 at 6:30 p.m. at the Wise River Community Center east of the Meyers Fire.      Despite red flag conditions yesterday, fire activity was low for most parts of the Meyers Fire and the Sapphire Complex.      Sapphire Complex: 43,642 acres Location: Approximately 25 miles south-southeast of Missoula  Containment: 59% Cause:  Lightning Total Personnel: 238  Three fires comprise the Sapphire Complex: Little Hogback, Goat Creek, and Sliderock. The fires are in steep, rocky terrain between Rock Creek and Upper Willow Creek drainages.  Little Hogback Fire: 34,442 acres  Some mop-up continues on hot spots along the southwest and south sides. Isolated areas of heat remain along the remainder of the perimeter; crews will continue monitoring for and addressing hot spots as needed. Unburned pockets in the interior continue to burn, especially in the northwest part of the fire well away from the perimeter. Structure protection along Rock Creek...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Meyers Sapphire Complex Update for 09.10.17&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Sapphire Complex Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 33 min. ago&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- 
cached related article links at 14:00:14
cached id cab9bd2d0460c7a40841a222e3fe7d39
--&gt;
&lt;div id="related_block"&gt;&lt;h4 id="related_head"&gt;Related Information&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul class="related_list"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/photos/MTLNF/2017-07-14-1837-Slide-Rock-Fire/related_files/pict20170810-133126-0.pdf" rel="new"&gt;Meyers Sapphire Complex Update for 09.10.17 (pdf 135 kb)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom:.3pt;"&gt; &lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;A public meeting will be held on Tuesday, September 12 at 6:30 p.m. at the Wise River Community Center east of the Meyers Fire. &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom:.3pt;"&gt; &lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom:.3pt;"&gt; &lt;b&gt;Despite red flag conditions yesterday, fire activity was low for most parts of the Meyers Fire and the Sapphire Complex. &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom:.3pt;"&gt; &lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom:.3pt;"&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;Sapphire Complex:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;43,642 acres&lt;b&gt; Location: &lt;/b&gt;Approximately 25 miles south-southeast of Missoula &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom:.3pt;"&gt; &lt;b&gt;Containment:&lt;/b&gt; 59% &lt;b&gt;Cause: &lt;/b&gt; Lightning &lt;b&gt;Total Personnel: &lt;/b&gt;238 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 6pt; margin-top: 6pt;"&gt; Three fires comprise the Sapphire Complex: Little Hogback, Goat Creek, and Sliderock. The fires are in steep, rocky terrain between Rock Creek and Upper Willow Creek drainages. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-left:.5in; tab-stops:center 3.85in;"&gt; &lt;b&gt;Little Hogback Fire: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;34,442 acres&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-left:.5in; tab-stops:center 3.85in;"&gt; Some mop-up continues on hot spots along the southwest and south sides. Isolated areas of heat remain along the remainder of the perimeter; crews will continue monitoring for and addressing hot spots as needed. Unburned pockets in the interior continue to burn, especially in the northwest part of the fire well away from the perimeter. Structure protection along Rock Creek Road remains a priority. Incident managers hope to shift from mop-up and patrolling to monitoring soon. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-left: 0.5in; margin-top: 6pt;"&gt; &lt;b&gt;Goat Creek Fire: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;8,300 acres&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-left: 0.5in; margin-top: 6pt;"&gt; No substantial growth has been detected. Significant heat remains only in the interior and at a few spots on the east flank. Firefighters have shifted from mop-up to rehabilitation of constructed fire breaks. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-left: 0.5in; margin-top: 6pt;"&gt; &lt;b&gt;Sliderock Fire: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;900 acres&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 6pt; margin-left: 0.5in;"&gt; There has been no growth in the overall size of this fire; any hot spots are in the fire interior. Rehabilitation of constructed firelines will follow after this work is completed for the Goat Creek Fire. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom:.3pt;"&gt; &lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom:.3pt;"&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;Meyers Fire:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;60,254 acres&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; Location: &lt;/b&gt;Approximately 25 miles southwest of Philipsburg, Montana&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom:.3pt;"&gt; &lt;b&gt;Containment:&lt;/b&gt; 0% &lt;b&gt;Cause: &lt;/b&gt; Lightning &lt;b&gt;Total Personnel: &lt;/b&gt;395 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The fire is burning in mixed conifer stands, primarily lodgepole pine, Douglas-fir, and subalpine fir, with many standing dead trees. These snags have become increasingly dangerous to firefighters as they burn through and fall with stronger winds. There are residences still at risk including those in the Moose Lake, Frog Pond, Billie Springer Memorial Park and Bonanza Lands areas. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The fire spotted north across Carpp Creek in the eastern part of the fire, but with diminished smoke cover, helicopters were able to make water drops there to keep the spot fires in check. Crews continued to mop-up and secure some areas of concern around the fire, including southeast of Zeke’s Meadows, and on the west flank including the Frog Pond area, which had minimal activity yesterday. Fireline construction is about 2/3 complete around the East Fork Bitterroot communities. Exposed rocky areas have slowed growth at the south end of the fire. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are two areas of the fire located in the Wise River Ranger District. One area, between Howell Creek and Beaver Creek in Beaverhead County, was active yesterday but showed minimal growth. The second area, between West Fork Fishtrap Creek and West Fork LaMarche Creek in Deerlodge County, is burning in a very rocky area with sparse fuels. These areas will continue to be monitored. Necessary preparations are being taken to protect structures that could be affected. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Structure protection continues to be the priority on the fire after firefighter and public safety. For Sunday, firefighters will focus on the northeast part of the fire and the Carpp Creek drainage, concentrating on keeping the spot fires detected yesterday in check. Firefighters will continue to improve firelines in the Billie Springer Memorial and Bonanza subdivisions as well as other private properties in the area, with hopes of completing these lines in the next two or three days. The southeast part of the fire will be patrolled primarily by air, weather permitting. Firefighters may burn out small pockets of unburned fuel southeast of Zeke’s Meadows to better secure that border, given safe conditions. Across the divide to the southeast, structure protection is being completed on the Bender and Mystic Lake cabins. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt; &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;Resources Threatened&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;u&gt; &lt;/u&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 6pt; margin-top: 6pt;"&gt; &lt;b&gt;Sapphire Complex: &lt;/b&gt;Private property and structures in the Rock Creek, Upper Willow Creek, and Marshall Creek drainages remain threatened. Other resources threatened include fisheries in Rock Creek, grazing lands along the southern boundary of the Little Hogback Fire, Bonneville Power Administration powerline, and a communication site. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 6pt; margin-top: 6pt;"&gt; &lt;b&gt;Meyers Fire: &lt;/b&gt;Private property and structures in the Moose Lake, Frog Pond, Billie Springer Memorial Park, Bonanza Lake areas, as well as other scattered individual dwellings continue to be monitored and prepped. Nearby grazing lands also remain a concern. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 6pt; margin-top: 6pt;"&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;Evacuations&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;u&gt; &lt;/u&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 6pt; margin-top: 6pt;"&gt; &lt;b&gt;Sapphire Complex: &lt;/b&gt;A mandatory evacuation (Level Red) order for approximately thirty-five residences along Rock Creek Road remains in effect, beginning from and including Wild Rose Loop south to Stony Creek. Other pre-evacuation (Level Yellow) notices are still in effect. For information on evacuation planning refer to the Ready-Set-Go materials available at &lt;a href="http://www.wildlandfirersg.org/Portals/18/Resources/States/MT/RSG_Montana_ActionGuide_web.pdf"&gt;http://www.wildlandfirersg.org/Portals/18/Resources/States/MT/RSG_Montana_ActionGuide_web.pdf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Meyers Fire: &lt;/b&gt;The Frog Pond and Moose Lake areas are still under an evacuation order. Additionally, an evacuation warning is in effect on East Fork Rd from FS Rd 5778 to Little East Fork Rd (FS RD 724) on the Bitterroot National Forest. Those under an evacuation warning should be prepared to leave at a moment’s notice. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 6pt; margin-top: 6pt;"&gt; &lt;a name="_gjdgxs"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;Closures &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 6pt; margin-top: 6pt;"&gt; &lt;b&gt;Sapphire Complex: &lt;/b&gt;The Rock Creek Road from I-90 south to Bitterroot Campground (MP 23.5) is OPEN. Due to fire traffic congestion and fire safety concerns, Rock Creek Road will stay CLOSED from Bitterroot Campground, south to Cornish Gulch (FSR5027), and public traffic is NOT allowed. Upper Willow Creek Road is currently closed to the public. The Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest reduced closure restrictions in the Black Pine ridge area, but maintains all area closures in Upper Willow Creek, North Fork Lower Willow Creek, and Harvey Creek areas. The Bureau of Land Management has an area closure in Upper Willow Creek, Ram Mountain, and nearby areas. The Lolo and Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forests, the Bureau of Land Management, and the Montana Department of Natural Resources (DNRC) closure orders and maps are posted under the &lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/closures/5364/"&gt;closures tab&lt;/a&gt; on Inciweb. A temporary flight restriction (TFR) remains in effect surrounding the Little Hogback Fire area. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Meyers Fire: &lt;/b&gt;Bitterroot National Forest emergency closure orders are still in effect for upper areas of the East Fork Bitterroot River.&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;The expanded Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest closure also remains in effect. On the south side of the fire, the closure extends between Bender Creek and LaMarche Creek, including Pintler Campground and Trailhead, Mystic Trailhead, Mussigbrod Campground and Trailhead, and all trailheads in the Mudd Creek and Fishtrap Creek areas. Several miles of the Continental Divide Trail are closed. A temporary flight restriction (TFR) is still in place surrounding the Meyers Fire area. Granite County is under Stage 2 fire restrictions for private lands in the county. Amended Stage 1 fire restrictions are in effect prohibiting &lt;b&gt;ALL&lt;/b&gt; campfires in southwestern Montana on public lands, including in fire rings and developed recreation areas. For fire restriction details, visit &lt;a href="https://firerestrictions.us/mt/"&gt;firerestrictions.us/mt&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 6pt; margin-top: 6pt;"&gt; Please adhere to all closures and allow our firefighters to perform their jobs safely. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 3.75pt; margin-right: 1.5pt; margin-top: 3.75pt;"&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;Weather&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 3.75pt; margin-right: 1.5pt; margin-top: 3.75pt;"&gt; Building high pressure will bring warmer temperatures, lower humidity, and diminished winds. Today, precipitation chance is 10%, with high temps in the upper 70s to low 80s, and humidity bottoming out about 22%. Southwest winds will be 10-15 mph in the morning, increasing to 15-20 mph. Southwesterly ridgetop winds are predicted at 15-20 mph. A stronger overnight inversion will persist later in the day tomorrow, and will bring near or below-freezing overnight lows below the inversion. Consequently, low areas should hold more smoke. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;For further information&lt;/b&gt;, visit &lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5397/"&gt;https://inciweb.nwcg.gov&lt;/a&gt; and select “Meyers Fire” or “Sapphire Complex” in Montana, and follow the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/US-Forest-Service-Beaverhead-Deerlodge-National-Forest-1540138089548920/"&gt;Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/DiscoverBitterrootNF"&gt;Bitterroot National Forest Facebook&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/lolonationalforest/"&gt;Lolo National Forest&lt;/a&gt; pages. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Sapphire Complex"></category></entry><entry><title>Meyers-Sapphire Smoke Report for 9-10-17</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5397_40588.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-10T10:35:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-10T10:35:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-10:/montana_fires/5397_40588.html</id><summary type="html">Meyers-Sapphire Smoke Report for</summary><content type="html">Meyers-Sapphire Smoke Report for</content><category term="Meyers Fire"></category></entry><entry><title>Meyers Sapphire Complex Smoke Report for 09.10.17</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5364_40580.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-10T10:08:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-10T10:08:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-10:/montana_fires/5364_40580.html</id><summary type="html">Smoke Report for</summary><content type="html">Smoke Report for</content><category term="Sapphire Complex"></category></entry><entry><title>Sapphire Complex Update for September 9, 2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5364_40552.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-09T17:25:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-09T17:25:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-09:/montana_fires/5364_40552.html</id><summary type="html">The Southern Area Type I Incident Management Team, with Incident Commander Mike Dueitt, has assumed command of both the Sapphire Complex and the Meyers Fire. The contact phone number for both fires is 406-859-9107, and the Incident Command Post is now at the Meyers Fire camp off Skalkaho Road.  A Red Flag Warning will be in effect today from 2:00pm to 9:00pm. Gusty winds may significantly increase fire behavior and create hazards from falling trees on both the Sapphire Complex and Meyers Fires. Structure protection will be the main focus today. The small amount of rain yesterday had a very minimal impact on fire behavior, especially with the winds moving through the area today. Sapphire Complex: 43,516 acres Location: Approximately 25 miles south-southeast of MissoulaContainment: 53% Cause: Lightning Total Personnel: 304Three fires comprise the Sapphire Complex: Little Hogback, Goat Creek, and Sliderock. The fires are burning in steep, rocky terrain between Rock Creek and Upper Willow...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sapphire Complex Update for September 9, 2017&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Sapphire Complex Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 5 min. ago&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b id="docs-internal-guid-2174bfab-68c0-cdc7-fc8b-15d23f1ff9b4" style="font-weight: normal;"&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 6pt; margin-bottom: 6pt;"&gt;The Southern Area Type I Incident Management Team, with Incident Commander Mike Dueitt, has assumed command of both the Sapphire Complex and the Meyers Fire. The contact phone number for both fires is 406-859-9107, and the Incident Command Post is now at the Meyers Fire camp off Skalkaho Road. &lt;br/&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 0pt; margin-bottom: 0.3pt;"&gt;A Red Flag Warning will be in effect today from 2:00pm to 9:00pm. Gusty winds may significantly increase fire behavior and create hazards from falling trees on both the Sapphire Complex and Meyers Fires. Structure protection will be the main focus today. The small amount of rain yesterday had a very minimal impact on fire behavior, especially with the winds moving through the area today. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 0pt; margin-bottom: 0.3pt;"&gt;Sapphire Complex: 43,516 acres Location: Approximately 25 miles south-southeast of Missoula&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 0pt; margin-bottom: 0.3pt;"&gt;Containment: 53% Cause: Lightning Total Personnel: 304&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 6pt; margin-bottom: 6pt;"&gt;Three fires comprise the Sapphire Complex: Little Hogback, Goat Creek, and Sliderock. The fires are burning in steep, rocky terrain between Rock Creek and Upper Willow Creek drainages. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 0pt; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-left: 36pt;"&gt;Little Hogback Fire: 34,310 acres, 30% contained. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 0pt; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-left: 36pt;"&gt;Fire activity was minimal along the entire perimeter with only a few interior hot spots. Crews will continue monitoring handlines in Windlass Gulch, and mopping up on the east and north sides of the fire. Structure protection along Rock Creek Road remains a priority for firefighters, and protection of life is always the primary objective.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 6pt; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-left: 36pt;"&gt;Goat Creek Fire: 8,305 acres, 95% contained. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 0pt; margin-bottom: 6pt; margin-left: 36pt;"&gt;Crews are performing suppression repair, including piling and sorting timber, where practical. Rehabilitation of firelines and suppression activities continues. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 6pt; margin-bottom: 0pt; margin-left: 36pt;"&gt;Sliderock Fire: 901 acres, 95% contained. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 0pt; margin-bottom: 6pt; margin-left: 36pt;"&gt;Crews continue to mop up hotspots and patrol the Sliderock Fire. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 0pt; margin-bottom: 0.3pt;"&gt;Meyers Fire: 59,933 acres Location: Approximately 25 miles southwest of Philipsburg, Montana&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 0pt; margin-bottom: 0.3pt;"&gt;Containment: 0% Cause: Lightning Total Personnel: 350&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The fire is burning in mixed conifer stands, primarily lodgepole pine, Douglas-fir, and subalpine fir, with many standing dead trees. There are residences still at risk including those in the Moose Lake, Frog Pond, Billy Springer Memorial Park and Bonanza Lands areas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 0pt; margin-bottom: 0pt;"&gt;Yesterday’s Activities: Fire activity was minimal across the Meyers Fire. Crews continued mop-up across the fire including areas around Moose Lake, Zeke’s Meadows and on the northwest flank of the fire. Structure protection is in place in the East Fork of the Bitterroot with contingency lines being built around the Billy Springer Memorial and Bonanza subdivisions as well as other private properties. A public meeting was held last night for the East Fork Bitterroot communities with approximately 65 people in attendance. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 0pt; margin-bottom: 0pt;"&gt;Today’s Activities: Structure protection continues to be the priority on the fire. Hand and mechanical line improvement measures will continue in the Billy Springer Memorial and Bonanza subdivisions as well as other private properties in the area. Firefighters will continue mopping up across the fire area and identify opportunities for possible direct hand lines around Zeke’s Meadow to the west. Crews will also be scouting opportunities to improve contingency lines to reduce impacts and threats. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Resources Threatened &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 6pt; margin-bottom: 6pt;"&gt;Sapphire Complex: Private property and structures in the Rock Creek, Upper Willow Creek, and Marshall Creek drainages remain threatened. Other resources threatened include fisheries in Rock Creek, grazing lands along the southern boundary of the Little Hogback Fire, Bonneville Power Administration powerline, and a communication site.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 6pt; margin-bottom: 6pt;"&gt;Meyers Fire: Private property and structures in the Moose Lake, Frog Pond, Billy Springer Memorial Park, Bonanza Lake areas, as well as other scattered individual dwellings. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 6pt; margin-bottom: 6pt;"&gt;Evacuations &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 6pt; margin-bottom: 6pt;"&gt;Sapphire Complex: A mandatory evacuation (Level Red) order for approximately thirty-five residences along Rock Creek Road remains in effect, beginning from and including Wild Rose Loop south to Stony Creek. All other pre-evacuation (Level Yellow) notices are still in effect. For information on evacuation planning refer to the Ready-Set-Go materials available at &lt;a href="http://www.wildlandfirersg.org/Portals/18/Resources/States/MT/RSG_Montana_ActionGuide_web.pdf" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;http://www.wildlandfirersg.org/Portals/18/Resources/States/MT/RSG_Montana_ActionGuide_web.pdf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 0pt; margin-bottom: 0pt;"&gt;Meyers Fire: The Frog Pond and Moose Lake areas are under an evacuation order. Additionally, an evacuation warning is in effect on East Fork Rd from FS Rd 5778 to Little East Fork Rd (FS RD 724) on the Bitterroot National Forest. Those under an evacuation warning should be prepared to leave at a moment’s notice. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 6pt; margin-bottom: 6pt;"&gt;Closures &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 6pt; margin-bottom: 6pt;"&gt;Sapphire Complex: The Rock Creek Road from I-90 south to Bitterroot Campground (MP 23.5) is OPEN. Due to fire traffic congestion and fire safety concerns, Rock Creek Road will stay CLOSED from Bitterroot Campground, south to Cornish Gulch (FSR5027), and public traffic is NOT allowed. Upper Willow Creek Road is currently closed to the public. The Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest reduced closure restrictions in the Black Pine ridge area, but maintains all area closures in Upper Willow Creek, North Fork Lower Willow Creek, and Harvey Creek areas. The Bureau of Land Management has an area closure in Upper Willow Creek, Ram Mountain, and nearby areas. The Lolo and Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forests, the Bureau of Land Management, and the Montana Department of Natural Resources (DNRC) closure orders and maps are posted under the &lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/closures/5364/" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;closures tab&lt;/a&gt; on Inciweb. A temporary flight restriction (TFR) remains in effect surrounding the Little Hogback Fire area, but has been rescinded over the Goat Creek and Sliderock fire areas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 0pt; margin-bottom: 0pt;"&gt;Meyers Fire: Closure orders are in place in both the Bitterroot and Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forests. Bitterroot National Forest emergency closure orders are in effect for upper areas of the East Fork Bitterroot River. The expanded Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest closure is still in effect. A temporary flight restriction (TFR) remains in effect surrounding the Meyers Fire area. Granite County is under Stage 2 fire restrictions for private lands in the county. Amended Stage 1 fire restrictions are in effect today which prohibits ALL campfires in southwestern Montana on public lands, including in fire rings and developed recreation areas. For fire restriction details, visit &lt;a href="https://firerestrictions.us/mt/" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;firerestrictions.us/mt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 6pt; margin-bottom: 6pt;"&gt;Please adhere to all closures and allow our firefighters to perform their jobs safely.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 3.75pt; margin-right: 1.5pt; margin-bottom: 3.75pt;"&gt;Weather&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 3.75pt; margin-right: 1.5pt; margin-bottom: 3.75pt;"&gt;Dense smoke moderated temperatures again yesterday, with highs only in the mid-80s in the valleys and the mid- to upper 70s on ridgetops. Humidities continued to be in the teens with light, terrain driven winds. Thunderstorms last night brought a small amount of rain to the fire areas, but no significant amounts. Today, winds are expected to pick up as low pressure moves into the area. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 0pt; margin-bottom: 0pt;"&gt;For further information, follow the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/US-Forest-Service-Beaverhead-Deerlodge-National-Forest-1540138089548920/" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/DiscoverBitterrootNF" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;Bitterroot National Forest Facebook&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/lolonationalforest/" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;Lolo National Forest&lt;/a&gt; pages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br class="Apple-interchange-newline"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Sapphire Complex"></category></entry><entry><title>Meyers Fire Update for September 9, 2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5397_40538.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-09T15:09:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-09T15:09:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-09:/montana_fires/5397_40538.html</id><summary type="html">The Southern Area Type I Incident Management Team, with Incident Commander Mike Dueitt, has assumed command of both the Sapphire Complex and the Meyers Fire. The contact phone number for both fires is 406-859-9107, and the Incident Command Post is now at the Meyers Fire camp off Skalkaho Road.  A Red Flag Warning will be in effect today from 2:00pm to 9:00pm. Gusty winds may significantly increase fire behavior and create hazards from falling trees on both the Sapphire Complex and Meyers Fires. Structure protection will be the main focus today. The small amount of rain yesterday had a very minimal impact on fire behavior, especially with the winds moving through the area today.     Sapphire Complex: 43,516 acres Location: Approximately 25 miles south-southeast of Missoula Containment: 53% Cause:  Lightning Total Personnel: 304 Three fires comprise the Sapphire Complex: Little Hogback, Goat Creek, and Sliderock. The fires are burning in steep, rocky terrain between Rock Creek and...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Meyers Fire Update for September 9, 2017&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Meyers Fire Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 21 min. ago&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- 
cached related article links at 15:30:13
cached id f696cb93719cd50322ac1f4b81df3c23
--&gt;
&lt;div id="related_block"&gt;&lt;h4 id="related_head"&gt;Related Information&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul class="related_list"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/photos/MTBDF/2017-07-20-1925-Meyers-Fire/related_files/pict20170809-151816-0.pdf" rel="new"&gt;Meyers Fire Update for September 9, 2017 (pdf 138 kb)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/photos/MTBDF/2017-07-20-1925-Meyers-Fire/related_files/pict20170809-151950-0.pdf" rel="new"&gt;Smoke Forecast for September 9, 2017 (pdf 190 kb)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 6pt 0in; tab-stops: center 3.85in;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman"&gt;The Southern Area Type I Incident Management Team, with Incident Commander Mike Dueitt, has assumed command of both the Sapphire Complex and the Meyers Fire. The contact phone number for both fires is &lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;406-859-9107&lt;/b&gt;, and the Incident Command Post is now at the Meyers Fire camp off Skalkaho Road. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0.3pt;"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;A Red Flag Warning will be in effect today from 2:00pm to 9:00pm. Gusty winds may significantly increase fire behavior and create hazards from falling trees on both the Sapphire Complex and Meyers Fires. Structure protection will be the main focus today. The small amount of rain yesterday had a very minimal impact on fire behavior, especially with the winds moving through the area today. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0.3pt;"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0.3pt;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Sapphire Complex: &lt;/b&gt;43,516 acres&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt; Location: &lt;/b&gt;Approximately 25 miles south-southeast of Missoula&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0.3pt;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Containment:&lt;/b&gt; 53% &lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Cause: &lt;/b&gt; Lightning &lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Total Personnel: &lt;/b&gt;304&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 6pt 0in; tab-stops: center 3.85in;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman"&gt;Three fires comprise the Sapphire Complex: Little Hogback, Goat Creek, and Sliderock. The fires are burning in steep, rocky terrain between Rock Creek and Upper Willow Creek drainages. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt 0.5in; tab-stops: center 3.85in;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Little Hogback Fire: 34,310 acres, 30% contained.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt 0.5in; tab-stops: center 3.85in;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman"&gt;Fire activity was minimal along the entire perimeter with only a few interior hot spots. Crews will continue monitoring handlines in Windlass Gulch, and mopping up on the east and north sides of the fire. Structure protection along Rock Creek Road remains a priority for firefighters, and protection of life is always the primary objective.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 6pt 0in 0pt 0.5in;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Goat Creek Fire: 8,305 acres, 95% contained.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 6pt 0.5in;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman"&gt;Crews are performing suppression repair, including piling and sorting timber, where practical. Rehabilitation of firelines and suppression activities continues. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 6pt 0in 0pt 0.5in;"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;Sliderock Fire: 901 acres, 95% contained. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 6pt 0.5in;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman"&gt;Crews continue to mop up hotspots and patrol the Sliderock Fire. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0.3pt;"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0.3pt;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Meyers Fire: &lt;/b&gt;59,933 acres&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt; Location: &lt;/b&gt;Approximately 25 miles southwest of Philipsburg, Montana&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0.3pt;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Containment:&lt;/b&gt; 0% &lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Cause: &lt;/b&gt; Lightning &lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Total Personnel: &lt;/b&gt;350&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman"&gt;The fire is burning in mixed conifer stands, primarily lodgepole pine, Douglas-fir, and subalpine fir, with many standing dead trees. There are residences still at risk including those in the Moose Lake, Frog Pond, Billy Springer Memorial Park and Bonanza Lands areas.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt;"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Yesterday’s Activities:&lt;/b&gt; Fire activity was minimal across the Meyers Fire. Crews continued mop-up across the fire including areas around Moose Lake, Zeke’s Meadows and on the northwest flank of the fire. Structure protection is in place in the East Fork of the Bitterroot with contingency lines being built around the Billy Springer Memorial and Bonanza subdivisions as well as other private properties. A public meeting was held last night for the East Fork Bitterroot communities with approximately 65 people in attendance. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt;"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Today’s Activities:&lt;/b&gt; Structure protection continues to be the priority on the fire. Hand and mechanical line improvement measures will continue in the Billy Springer Memorial and Bonanza subdivisions as well as other private properties in the area. Firefighters will continue mopping up across the fire area and identify opportunities for possible direct hand lines around Zeke’s Meadow to the west. Crews will also be scouting opportunities to improve contingency lines to reduce impacts and threats. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 6pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 6pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Resources Threatened&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;u&gt; &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 6pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Sapphire Complex: &lt;/b&gt;Private property and structures in the Rock Creek, Upper Willow Creek, and Marshall Creek drainages remain threatened. Other resources threatened include fisheries in Rock Creek, grazing lands along the southern boundary of the Little Hogback Fire, Bonneville Power Administration powerline, and a communication site.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 6pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Meyers Fire: &lt;/b&gt;Private property and structures in the Moose Lake, Frog Pond, Billy Springer Memorial Park, Bonanza Lake areas, as well as other scattered individual dwellings. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 6pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Evacuations&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;u&gt; &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 6pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Sapphire Complex: &lt;/b&gt;A mandatory evacuation (Level Red) order for approximately thirty-five residences along Rock Creek Road remains in effect, beginning from and including Wild Rose Loop south to Stony Creek. All other pre-evacuation (Level Yellow) notices are still in effect.&lt;font size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;For information on evacuation planning refer to the Ready-Set-Go materials available at &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.wildlandfirersg.org/Portals/18/Resources/States/MT/RSG_Montana_ActionGuide_web.pdf"&gt;&lt;font color="#0563c1" face="Times New Roman"&gt;http://www.wildlandfirersg.org/Portals/18/Resources/States/MT/RSG_Montana_ActionGuide_web.pdf&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Meyers Fire: &lt;/b&gt;The Frog Pond and Moose Lake areas are under an evacuation order. Additionally, an evacuation warning is in effect on East Fork Rd from FS Rd 5778 to Little East Fork Rd (FS RD 724) on the Bitterroot National Forest. Those under an evacuation warning should be prepared to leave at a moment’s notice. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 6pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;a name="_gjdgxs"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;Closures &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 6pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Sapphire Complex: &lt;/b&gt;The Rock Creek Road from I-90 south to Bitterroot Campground (MP 23.5) is OPEN. Due to fire traffic congestion and fire safety concerns, Rock Creek Road will stay CLOSED from Bitterroot Campground, south to Cornish Gulch (FSR5027), and public traffic is NOT allowed. Upper Willow Creek Road is currently closed to the public. The Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest reduced closure restrictions in the Black Pine ridge area, but maintains all area closures in Upper Willow Creek, North Fork Lower Willow Creek, and Harvey Creek areas. The Bureau of Land Management has an area closure in Upper Willow Creek, Ram Mountain, and nearby areas. The Lolo and Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forests, the Bureau of Land Management, and the Montana Department of Natural Resources (DNRC) closure orders and maps are posted under the &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/closures/5364/"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;closures tab&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman"&gt; on Inciweb. A temporary flight restriction (TFR) remains in effect surrounding the Little Hogback Fire area, but has been rescinded over the Goat Creek and Sliderock fire areas.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Meyers Fire: &lt;/b&gt;Closure orders are in place in both the Bitterroot and Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forests.&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt; &lt;/b&gt;Bitterroot National Forest emergency closure orders are in effect for upper areas of the East Fork Bitterroot River.&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt; &lt;/b&gt;The expanded Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest closure is still in effect. A temporary flight restriction (TFR) remains in effect surrounding the Meyers Fire area. Granite County is under Stage 2 fire restrictions for private lands in the county. Amended Stage 1 fire restrictions are in effect today which prohibits &lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;ALL&lt;/b&gt; campfires in southwestern Montana on public lands, including in fire rings and developed recreation areas. For fire restriction details, visit &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://firerestrictions.us/mt/"&gt;&lt;font color="#0563c1" face="Times New Roman"&gt;firerestrictions.us/mt&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman"&gt;.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 6pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;Please adhere to all closures and allow our firefighters to perform their jobs safely.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 3.75pt 1.5pt 3.75pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;Weather&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 3.75pt 1.5pt 3.75pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;Dense smoke moderated temperatures again yesterday, with highs only in the mid-80s in the valleys and the mid- to upper 70s on ridgetops. Humidities continued to be in the teens with light, terrain driven winds. Thunderstorms last night brought a small amount of rain to the fire areas, but no significant amounts. Today, winds are expected to pick up as low pressure moves into the area. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt;"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt;"&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;For further information&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman"&gt;follow the &lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/US-Forest-Service-Beaverhead-Deerlodge-National-Forest-1540138089548920/"&gt;&lt;font color="#0563c1" face="Times New Roman"&gt;Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest Facebook&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman"&gt;, &lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/DiscoverBitterrootNF"&gt;&lt;font color="#0563c1" face="Times New Roman"&gt;Bitterroot National Forest Facebook&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman"&gt; or &lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/lolonationalforest/"&gt;&lt;font color="#0563c1" face="Times New Roman"&gt;Lolo National Forest&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman"&gt; pages.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Meyers Fire"></category></entry><entry><title>Smoke Update for 09.09.17</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5364_40535.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-09T14:54:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-09T14:54:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-09:/montana_fires/5364_40535.html</id><summary type="html">Smoke Update for</summary><content type="html">Smoke Update for</content><category term="Sapphire Complex"></category></entry><entry><title>Meyers Sapphire Complex Fires Update Saturday, September 9, 2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5364_40518.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-09T11:58:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-09T11:58:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-09:/montana_fires/5364_40518.html</id><summary type="html">Fire Information Line: 406-859-9107Email: meyerswhetstone@gmail.comInciweb: https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5364/https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5397/ Follow Fire Information on Facebook: Lolo National Forest Beaverhead-Deerlodge National ForestBitterroot National Forest The Southern Area Type I Incident Management Team, with Incident Commander Mike Dueitt, has assumed command ofboth the Sapphire Complex and the Meyers Fire. The contact phone number for both fires is 406-859-9107, and the IncidentCommand Post is now at the Meyers Fire camp off Skalkaho Road. A Red Flag Warning will be in effect today from 2:00pm to 9:00pm. Gusty winds may significantly increase firebehavior and create hazards from falling trees on both the Sapphire Complex and Meyers Fires. Structure protectionwill be the main focus today. The small amount of rain yesterday had a very minimal impact on fire behavior,especially with the winds moving through the area today. Sapphire Complex: 43,516 acres Location:...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Meyers Sapphire Complex Fires Update Saturday, September 9, 2017&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Sapphire Complex Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 32 min. ago&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fire Information Line: 406-859-9107Email: meyerswhetstone@gmail.comInciweb: https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5364/https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5397/&lt;br/&gt; Follow Fire Information on Facebook: Lolo National Forest Beaverhead-Deerlodge National ForestBitterroot National Forest&lt;br/&gt; The Southern Area Type I Incident Management Team, with Incident Commander Mike Dueitt, has assumed command ofboth the Sapphire Complex and the Meyers Fire. The contact phone number for both fires is 406-859-9107, and the IncidentCommand Post is now at the Meyers Fire camp off Skalkaho Road.&lt;br/&gt; A Red Flag Warning will be in effect today from 2:00pm to 9:00pm. Gusty winds may significantly increase firebehavior and create hazards from falling trees on both the Sapphire Complex and Meyers Fires. Structure protectionwill be the main focus today. The small amount of rain yesterday had a very minimal impact on fire behavior,especially with the winds moving through the area today.&lt;br/&gt; Sapphire Complex: 43,516 acres Location: Approximately 25 miles south-southeast of MissoulaContainment: 53% Cause: Lightning Total Personnel: 304Three fires comprise the Sapphire Complex: Little Hogback, Goat Creek, and Sliderock. The fires are burning in steep, rockyterrain between Rock Creek and Upper Willow Creek drainages.&lt;br/&gt; Little Hogback Fire: 34,310 acres, 30% contained.Fire activity was minimal along the entire perimeter with only a few interior hot spots. Crews will continuemonitoring handlines in Windlass Gulch, and mopping up on the east and north sides of the fire. Structure protectionalong Rock Creek Road remains a priority for firefighters, and protection of life is always the primary objective.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;b&gt;Goat Creek Fire:&lt;/b&gt; 8,305 acres, 95% contained.Crews are performing suppression repair, including piling and sorting timber, where practical. Rehabilitation offirelines and suppression activities continues.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;b&gt;Sliderock Fire:&lt;/b&gt; 901 acres, 95% contained.Crews continue to mop up hotspots and patrol the Sliderock Fire.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;b&gt;Meyers Fire:&lt;/b&gt; 59,933 acres Location: Approximately 25 miles southwest of Philipsburg, MontanaContainment: 0% Cause: Lightning Total Personnel: 350The fire is burning in mixed conifer stands, primarily lodgepole pine, Douglas-fir, and subalpine fir, with many standing deadtrees. There are residences still at risk including those in the Moose Lake, Frog Pond, Billy Springer Memorial Park andBonanza Lands areas.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;b&gt;Yesterday’s Activities:&lt;/b&gt; Fire activity was minimal across the Meyers Fire. Crews continued mop-up across the fire includingareas around Moose Lake, Zeke’s Meadows and on the northwest flank of the fire. Structure protection is in place in the EastFork of the Bitterroot with contingency lines being built around the Billy Springer Memorial and Bonanza subdivisions aswell as other private properties. A public meeting was held last night for the East Fork Bitterroot communities withapproximately 65 people in attendance.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;b&gt;Today’s Activities: &lt;/b&gt;Structure protection continues to be the priority on the fire. Hand and mechanical line improvementmeasures will continue in the Billy Springer Memorial and Bonanza subdivisions as well as other private properties in thearea. Firefighters will continue mopping up across the fire area and identify opportunities for possible direct hand linesaround Zeke’s Meadow to the west. Crews will also be scouting opportunities to improve contingency lines to reduce impactsand threats.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;b&gt;Resources Threatened&lt;/b&gt;Sapphire Complex: Private property and structures in the Rock Creek, Upper Willow Creek, and Marshall Creek drainagesremain threatened. Other resources threatened include fisheries in Rock Creek, grazing lands along the southern boundary ofthe Little Hogback Fire, Bonneville Power Administration powerline, and a communication site.Meyers Fire: Private property and structures in the Moose Lake, Frog Pond, Billy Springer Memorial Park, Bonanza Lakeareas, as well as other scattered individual dwellings.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;b&gt;Evacuations&lt;/b&gt;Sapphire Complex: A mandatory evacuation (Level Red) order for approximately thirty-five residences along Rock CreekRoad remains in effect, beginning from and including Wild Rose Loop south to Stony Creek. All other pre-evacuation (LevelYellow) notices are still in effect. For information on evacuation planning refer to the Ready-Set-Go materials available athttp://www.wildlandfirersg.org/Portals/18/Resources/States/MT/RSG_Montana_ActionGuide_web.pdfMeyers Fire: The Frog Pond and Moose Lake areas are under an evacuation order. Additionally, an evacuation warning is ineffect on East Fork Rd from FS Rd 5778 to Little East Fork Rd (FS RD 724) on the Bitterroot National Forest. Those underan evacuation warning should be prepared to leave at a moment’s notice.&lt;b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Closures&lt;/b&gt;Sapphire Complex: The Rock Creek Road from I-90 south to Bitterroot Campground (MP 23.5) is OPEN. Due to fire trafficcongestion and fire safety concerns, Rock Creek Road will stay CLOSED from Bitterroot Campground, south to CornishGulch (FSR5027), and public traffic is NOT allowed. Upper Willow Creek Road is currently closed to the public. TheBeaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest reduced closure restrictions in the Black Pine ridge area, but maintains all areaclosures in Upper Willow Creek, North Fork Lower Willow Creek, and Harvey Creek areas. The Bureau of LandManagement has an area closure in Upper Willow Creek, Ram Mountain, and nearby areas. The Lolo and Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forests, the Bureau of Land Management, and the Montana Department of Natural Resources (DNRC)closure orders and maps are posted under the closures tab on Inciweb. A temporary flight restriction (TFR) remains in effectsurrounding the Little Hogback Fire area, but has been rescinded over the Goat Creek and Sliderock fire areas.Meyers Fire: Closure orders are in place in both the Bitterroot and Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forests. BitterrootNational Forest emergency closure orders are in effect for upper areas of the East Fork Bitterroot River. The expandedBeaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest closure is still in effect. A temporary flight restriction (TFR) remains in effectsurrounding the Meyers Fire area. Granite County is under Stage 2 fire restrictions for private lands in the county. AmendedStage 1 fire restrictions are in effect today which prohibits ALL campfires in southwestern Montana on public lands,including in fire rings and developed recreation areas. For fire restriction details, visit firerestrictions.us/mt.Please adhere to all closures and allow our firefighters to perform their jobs safely.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;b&gt;Weather&lt;/b&gt;Dense smoke moderated temperatures again yesterday, with highs only in the mid-80s in the valleys and the mid- to upper70s on ridgetops. Humidities continued to be in the teens with light, terrain driven winds. Thunderstorms last night brought asmall amount of rain to the fire areas, but no significant amounts. Today, winds are expected to pick up as low pressuremoves into the area.&lt;br/&gt; For further information, visit https://inciweb.nwcg.gov and select “Meyers Fire” or “Sapphire Complex” in Montana, andfollow the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest Facebook, Bitterroot National Forest Facebook or Lolo National Forestpages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Sapphire Complex"></category></entry><entry><title>Meyers Sapphire Complex Smoke Report 09.08.17</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5364_40436.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-08T19:25:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-08T19:25:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-08:/montana_fires/5364_40436.html</id><summary type="html">Meyers Sapphire Complex Smoke Report</summary><content type="html">Meyers Sapphire Complex Smoke Report</content><category term="Sapphire Complex"></category></entry><entry><title>New Contact Information for the Sapphire Complex</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5364_40435.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-08T19:17:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-08T19:17:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-08:/montana_fires/5364_40435.html</id><summary type="html">The Southern Area Type I Incident Management Team, with Incident Commander Mike Dueitt, has assumed command of both the Sapphire Complex and the Meyers Fire. The contact phone number for both fires will be 406-859-9107 and the email address for information is</summary><content type="html">The Southern Area Type I Incident Management Team, with Incident Commander Mike Dueitt, has assumed command of both the Sapphire Complex and the Meyers Fire. The contact phone number for both fires will be 406-859-9107 and the email address for information is</content><category term="Sapphire Complex"></category></entry><entry><title>Meyers Sapphire Complex Daily Update 09.08.17</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5364_40434.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-08T19:12:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-08T19:12:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-08:/montana_fires/5364_40434.html</id><summary type="html">The Southern Area Type I Incident Management Team, with Incident Commander Mike Dueitt, has assumed command of both the Sapphire Complex and the Meyers Fire. The contact phone number for both fires will be 406-859-9107, and the Incident Command Post is now at the Meyers Fire camp off Skalkaho Road.   Sapphire Complex: 43,516 acres Location: Approximately 25 miles south-southeast of Missoula   Containment: 53% Cause:  Lightning Total Personnel: 304   Three fires comprise the Sapphire Complex: Little Hogback, Goat Creek, and Sliderock. The fires are burning in steep, rocky terrain between Rock Creek and Upper Willow Creek drainages.  Little Hogback Fire: 34,310 acres, 30% contained.  Fire activity was minimal along the entire perimeter. Hand lines continue to hold in Windlass Gulch and mop up operations continue on the east and north sides of the fire. Firefighters continue to provide structure protection along Rock Creek Road. Preventing fire growth toward homes and ranches continues...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Meyers Sapphire Complex Daily Update 09.08.17&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Sapphire Complex Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 18 min. ago&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 6pt; margin-top: 6pt;"&gt; The Southern Area Type I Incident Management Team, with Incident Commander Mike Dueitt, has assumed command of both the Sapphire Complex and the Meyers Fire. The contact phone number for both fires will be &lt;b&gt;406-859-9107&lt;/b&gt;, and the Incident Command Post is now at the Meyers Fire camp off Skalkaho Road. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="margin-bottom:.3pt;"&gt; &lt;b&gt;Sapphire Complex: &lt;/b&gt;43,516 acres&lt;b&gt; Location: &lt;/b&gt;Approximately 25 miles south-southeast of Missoula &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="margin-bottom:.3pt;"&gt; &lt;b&gt;Containment:&lt;/b&gt; 53% &lt;b&gt;Cause: &lt;/b&gt; Lightning &lt;b&gt;Total Personnel: &lt;/b&gt;304 &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="margin-bottom: 6pt; margin-top: 6pt;"&gt; Three fires comprise the Sapphire Complex: Little Hogback, Goat Creek, and Sliderock. The fires are burning in steep, rocky terrain between Rock Creek and Upper Willow Creek drainages. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Little Hogback Fire: 34,310 acres, 30% contained.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Fire activity was minimal along the entire perimeter. Hand lines continue to hold in Windlass Gulch and mop up operations continue on the east and north sides of the fire. Firefighters continue to provide structure protection along Rock Creek Road. Preventing fire growth toward homes and ranches continues to dictate operational priorities, and protection of life is always the primary objective. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="margin-top:6.0pt;"&gt; &lt;b&gt;Goat Creek Fire: 8,305 acres, 95% contained.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="margin-bottom:6.0pt;"&gt; Crews are performing suppression repair, including piling and sorting timber, where practical. Rehabilitation of firelines and suppression activities continues. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="margin-top:6.0pt;"&gt; &lt;b&gt;Sliderock Fire: 901 acres, 95% contained. &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="margin-bottom:6.0pt;"&gt; Crews continue to mop up hotspots and patrol the Sliderock Fire. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="margin-bottom:3.75pt; margin-left: 1.5pt; margin-right:1.5pt; margin-top:3.75pt;"&gt; &lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="margin-bottom:.3pt;"&gt; &lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="margin-bottom:.3pt;"&gt; &lt;b&gt;Meyers Fire: &lt;/b&gt;59,441 acres&lt;b&gt; Location: &lt;/b&gt;Approximately 25 miles southwest of Philipsburg, Montana&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="margin-bottom:.3pt;"&gt; &lt;b&gt;Containment:&lt;/b&gt; 0% &lt;b&gt;Cause: &lt;/b&gt; Lightning &lt;b&gt;Total Personnel: &lt;/b&gt;350 &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The fire is burning in mixed conifer stands, primarily lodgepole pine, Douglas-fir, and subalpine fir, with many standing dead trees. There are residences still at risk including those in the Moose Lake, Frog Pond, Billy Springer Memorial Park and Bonanza Lands areas. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Yesterday’s Activities: &lt;/b&gt;As the incoming Southern Area Incident Management Type 1 Team transitioned command from the Northern Rockies outgoing team, firefighters continued efforts on the line. Growth was moderate across the fire with an increase of 1,508 acres. There was some fire activity north of Frog Pond with crews addressing the slow spotting that occurred. Crews also continued mopping up the burnouts in the Moose Lake and Zeke’s Meadows areas with the aid of air drops. Structure protection is in place in the East Fork of the Bitterroot with contingency lines being built around the Billy Springer Memorial and Bonanza subdivisions as well as other private properties. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Today’s Activities:&lt;/b&gt; Structure protection continues to be the priority on the fire. Hand and mechanical line improvement measures will continue in the Billy Springer Memorial and Bonanza subdivisions as well as other private properties in the area. Firefighters will continue mopping up the burnouts in Zeke’s Meadows and Moose Lake areas and identify opportunities for possible direct hand lines around Zeke’s Meadow to the west. Tactical burning may occur where appropriate and crews will continue to engage active fire if necessary. &lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="margin-bottom: 6pt; margin-top: 6pt;"&gt; &lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="margin-bottom: 6pt; margin-top: 6pt;"&gt; &lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="margin-bottom: 6pt; margin-top: 6pt;"&gt; &lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="margin-bottom: 6pt; margin-top: 6pt;"&gt; &lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="margin-bottom: 6pt; margin-top: 6pt;"&gt; &lt;b&gt;Resources Threatened&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="margin-bottom: 6pt; margin-top: 6pt;"&gt; &lt;b&gt;Sapphire Complex: &lt;/b&gt;Private property and structures in the Rock Creek, Upper Willow Creek, and Marshall Creek drainages remain threatened. Other resources threatened include fisheries in Rock Creek, grazing lands along the southern boundary of the Little Hogback Fire, Bonneville Power Administration powerline, and a communication site. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="margin-bottom: 6pt; margin-top: 6pt;"&gt; &lt;b&gt;Meyers Fire: &lt;/b&gt;Private property and structures in the Moose Lake, Frog Pond, Billy Springer Memorial Park, Bonanza Lake areas. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="margin-bottom: 6pt; margin-top: 6pt;"&gt; &lt;b&gt;Evacuations&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="margin-bottom: 6pt; margin-top: 6pt;"&gt; &lt;b&gt;Sapphire Complex: &lt;/b&gt;A mandatory evacuation (Level Red) order for approximately thirty-five residences along Rock Creek Road remains in effect, beginning from and including Wild Rose Loop south to Stony Creek. All other pre-evacuation (Level Yellow) notices are still in effect. For information on evacuation planning refer to the Ready-Set-Go materials available at &lt;a href="http://www.wildlandfirersg.org/Portals/18/Resources/States/MT/RSG_Montana_ActionGuide_web.pdf"&gt;http://www.wildlandfirersg.org/Portals/18/Resources/States/MT/RSG_Montana_ActionGuide_web.pdf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Meyers Fire: &lt;/b&gt;The Frog Pond and Moose Lake areas are under an evacuation order. Additionally, an evacuation warning is in effect on East Fork Rd from FS Rd 5778 to Little East Fork Rd (FS RD 724) on the Bitterroot National Forest. Those under an evacuation warning should be prepared to leave at a moment’s notice. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="margin-bottom: 6pt; margin-top: 6pt;"&gt; &lt;a name="_gjdgxs"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;Closures &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="margin-bottom: 6pt; margin-top: 6pt;"&gt; &lt;b&gt;Sapphire Complex: &lt;/b&gt;The Rock Creek Road from I-90 south to Bitterroot Campground (MP 23.5) is OPEN. Due to fire traffic congestion and fire safety concerns, Rock Creek Road will stay CLOSED from Bitterroot Campground, south to Cornish Gulch (FSR5027), and public traffic is NOT allowed. Upper Willow Creek Road is currently closed to the public. The Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest reduced closure restrictions in the Black Pine ridge area, but maintains all area closures in Upper Willow Creek, North Fork Lower Willow Creek, and Harvey Creek areas. The Bureau of Land Management has an area closure in Upper Willow Creek, Ram Mountain, and nearby areas. The Lolo and Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forests, the Bureau of Land Management, and the Montana Department of Natural Resources (DNRC) closure orders and maps are posted under the &lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/closures/5364/"&gt;closures tab&lt;/a&gt; on Inciweb. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Meyers Fire: &lt;/b&gt;Closure orders are in place in both the Bitterroot and Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forests.&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;Bitterroot National Forest emergency closure orders are in effect for upper areas of the East Fork Bitterroot River.&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;The expanded Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest closure is still in effect. A temporary flight restriction (TFR) is in effect surrounding the Meyers Fire area. Granite County is under Stage 2 fire restrictions for private lands in the county. Amended Stage 1 fire restrictions are in effect today which prohibits &lt;b&gt;ALL&lt;/b&gt; campfires in southwestern Montana on public lands, including in fire rings and developed recreation areas. For fire restriction details, visit &lt;a href="https://firerestrictions.us/mt/"&gt;firerestrictions.us/mt&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="margin-bottom: 6pt; margin-top: 6pt;"&gt; Please adhere to all closures and allow our firefighters to perform their jobs safely. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="margin-bottom: 3.75pt; margin-right: 1.5pt; margin-top: 3.75pt;"&gt; &lt;b&gt;Weather: &lt;/b&gt;Dense smoke kept temperatures moderate yesterday, with high temperatures in the upper 70’s and lower 80’s. Humidities continued to be in the teens with light, terrain driven winds. High pressure will be moving east today, bringing with it mid-level moisture and the possibility of thunderstorms to the fire areas. Temperatures will generally be in the mid-70s to 80 degrees with humidities increasing to 20-25%. Dense smoke will again be an issue across both fires as the upper level ridge shifts overhead. &lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;b style="font-size: 11.008px;"&gt;For further information&lt;/b&gt;, visit &lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5397/" style="font-size: 11.008px;"&gt;https://inciweb.nwcg.gov&lt;/a&gt; and select “Meyers Fire” or “Sapphire Complex” in Montana, and follow the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/US-Forest-Service-Beaverhead-Deerlodge-National-Forest-1540138089548920/" style="font-size: 11.008px;"&gt;Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/DiscoverBitterrootNF" style="font-size: 11.008px;"&gt;Bitterroot National Forest Facebook&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/lolonationalforest/" style="font-size: 11.008px;"&gt;Lolo National Forest&lt;/a&gt; pages.
		&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Sapphire Complex"></category></entry><entry><title>Meyers Fire Update for September 8, 2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5397_40429.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-08T18:09:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-08T18:09:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-08:/montana_fires/5397_40429.html</id><summary type="html">The Southern Area Type I Incident Management Team, with Incident Commander Mike Dueitt, has assumed command of both the Sapphire Complex and the Meyers Fire. The contact phone number for both fires will be 406-859-9107, and the Incident Command Post is now at the Meyers Fire camp off Skalkaho Road. Meyers Fire: 59,441 acresLocation: Approximately 25 miles southwest of Philipsburg, MontanaContainment: 0%Cause: LightningTotal Personnel: 350The fire is burning in mixed conifer stands, primarily lodgepole pine, Douglas-fir, and subalpine fir, with many standing dead trees. There are residences still at risk including those in the Moose Lake, Frog Pond, Billy Springer Memorial Park and Bonanza Lands areas.Yesterday’s Activities: As the incoming Southern Area Incident Management Type 1 Team transitioned command from the Northern Rockies outgoing team, firefighters continued efforts on the line. Growth was moderate across the fire with an increase of 1,508 acres. There was some fire...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Meyers Fire Update for September 8, 2017&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Meyers Fire Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 21 min. ago&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b id="docs-internal-guid-c2e8bde3-63c0-1903-1673-2d7d16a3daef" style="font-weight: normal;"&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 6pt; margin-bottom: 6pt;"&gt;&lt;b id="docs-internal-guid-c2e8bde3-63c0-1903-1673-2d7d16a3daef" style="font-weight: normal;"&gt;The Southern Area Type I Incident Management Team, with Incident Commander Mike Dueitt, has assumed command of both the Sapphire Complex and the Meyers Fire. The contact phone number for both fires will be 406-859-9107, and the Incident Command Post is now at the Meyers Fire camp off Skalkaho Road. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;b id="docs-internal-guid-c2e8bde3-63c0-1903-1673-2d7d16a3daef" style="font-weight: normal;"&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 0pt; margin-bottom: 0.3pt;"&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 0pt; margin-bottom: 0.3pt;"&gt;Meyers Fire: 59,441 acres&lt;br/&gt;Location: Approximately 25 miles southwest of Philipsburg, Montana&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 0pt; margin-bottom: 0.3pt;"&gt;Containment: 0%&lt;br/&gt;Cause: Lightning&lt;br/&gt;Total Personnel: 350&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 0pt; margin-bottom: 0pt;"&gt;The fire is burning in mixed conifer stands, primarily lodgepole pine, Douglas-fir, and subalpine fir, with many standing dead trees. There are residences still at risk including those in the Moose Lake, Frog Pond, Billy Springer Memorial Park and Bonanza Lands areas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 0pt; margin-bottom: 0pt;"&gt;Yesterday’s Activities: As the incoming Southern Area Incident Management Type 1 Team transitioned command from the Northern Rockies outgoing team, firefighters continued efforts on the line. Growth was moderate across the fire with an increase of 1,508 acres. There was some fire activity north of Frog Pond with crews addressing the slow spotting that occurred. Crews also continued mopping up the burnouts in the Moose Lake and Zeke’s Meadows areas with the aid of air drops. Structure protection is in place in the East Fork of the Bitterroot with contingency lines being built around the Billy Springer Memorial and Bonanza subdivisions as well as other private properties. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 0pt; margin-bottom: 0pt;"&gt;Today’s Activities: Structure protection continues to be the priority on the fire. Hand and mechanical line improvement measures will continue in the Billy Springer Memorial and Bonanza subdivisions as well as other private properties in the area. Firefighters will continue mopping up the burnouts in Zeke’s Meadows and Moose Lake areas and identify opportunities for possible direct hand lines around Zeke’s Meadow to the west. Tactical burning may occur where appropriate and crews will continue to engage active fire if necessary. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 6pt; margin-bottom: 6pt;"&gt;Resources Threatened &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 6pt; margin-bottom: 6pt;"&gt;Private property and structures in the Moose Lake, Frog Pond, Billy Springer Memorial Park, Bonanza Lake areas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 6pt; margin-bottom: 6pt;"&gt;Evacuations &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 6pt; margin-bottom: 6pt;"&gt;The Frog Pond and Moose Lake areas are under an evacuation order. Additionally, an evacuation warning is in effect on East Fork Rd from FS Rd 5778 to Little East Fork Rd (FS RD 724) on the Bitterroot National Forest. Those under an evacuation warning should be prepared to leave at a moment’s notice. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 6pt; margin-bottom: 6pt;"&gt;Closures &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 6pt; margin-bottom: 6pt;"&gt;Closure orders are in place in both the Bitterroot and Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forests. Bitterroot National Forest emergency closure orders are in effect for upper areas of the East Fork Bitterroot River. The expanded Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest closure is still in effect. A temporary flight restriction (TFR) is in effect surrounding the Meyers Fire area. Granite County is under Stage 2 fire restrictions for private lands in the county. Amended Stage 1 fire restrictions are in effect today which prohibits ALL campfires in southwestern Montana on public lands, including in fire rings and developed recreation areas. For fire restriction details, visit &lt;a href="https://firerestrictions.us/mt/" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;firerestrictions.us/mt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 6pt; margin-bottom: 6pt;"&gt;Please adhere to all closures and allow our firefighters to perform their jobs safely.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 3.75pt; margin-right: 1.5pt; margin-bottom: 3.75pt;"&gt;Weather: Dense smoke kept temperatures moderate yesterday, with high temperatures in the upper 70’s and lower 80’s. Humidities continued to be in the teens with light, terrain driven winds. High pressure will be moving east today, bringing with it mid-level moisture and the possibility of thunderstorms to the fire areas. Temperatures will generally be in the mid-70s to 80 degrees with humidities increasing to 20-25%. Dense smoke will again be an issue across both fires as the upper level ridge shifts overhead. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="line-height: 1.2; margin-top: 0pt; margin-bottom: 0pt;"&gt;For further information, follow the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/US-Forest-Service-Beaverhead-Deerlodge-National-Forest-1540138089548920/" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/DiscoverBitterrootNF" style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;Bitterroot National Forest Facebook&lt;/a&gt; pages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Meyers Fire"></category></entry><entry><title>Sapphire Complex Daily Update 09.07.2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5364_40282.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-07T11:28:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-07T11:28:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-07:/montana_fires/5364_40282.html</id><summary type="html">Three fires comprise the Sapphire Complex: Little Hogback, Goat Creek, and Sliderock fires. The fires are burning in steep, rocky terrain between the Rock Creek and Upper Willow Creek drainages. Mike Dueitt’s Southeastern Type I Incident Management Team (IMT) will assume command of both the Sapphire Complex and the Meyers Fire beginning at 6:00pm tonight. Beginning this evening, the contact phone number for both fires will be 406-859-9107, and the Incident Command Post will be moving to the Meyers Fire camp off of Skalkaho Road.  Little Hogback Fire: 34,310 acres, 30% contained.  Fire continued to spread slowly on the southwestern flank and along the northern perimeter. Crews finished constructing hand line, tying in to existing lines along Windlass Gulch, hoping to prevent the fire from spreading further. Firefighters were able to burnout into Windless Gulch and hand lines continue to hold there. Mop up operations continue on the east side of the fire, and crews are performing...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sapphire Complex Daily Update 09.07.2017&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Sapphire Complex Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 32 min. ago&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- 
cached related article links at 12:00:21
cached id 259b4d0e6490f92eb919e30e215276ed
--&gt;
&lt;div id="related_block"&gt;&lt;h4 id="related_head"&gt;Related Information&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul class="related_list"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/photos/MTLNF/2017-07-14-1837-Slide-Rock-Fire/related_files/pict20170807-113239-0.pdf" rel="new"&gt;Sapphire Complex Daily Update 09.07.2017 (pdf 41 kb)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 6pt 0in; border: currentColor; border-image: none; tab-stops: center 3.85in; mso-padding-alt: 0in 0in 0in 0in;"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;Three fires comprise the Sapphire Complex: Little Hogback, Goat Creek, and Sliderock fires. The fires are burning in steep, rocky terrain between the Rock Creek and Upper Willow Creek drainages. Mike Dueitt’s Southeastern Type I Incident Management Team (IMT) will assume command of both the Sapphire Complex and the Meyers Fire beginning at 6:00pm tonight. Beginning this evening, the contact phone number for both fires will be &lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;406-859-9107&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;, and the Incident Command Post will be moving to the Meyers Fire camp off of Skalkaho Road.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt; border: currentColor; border-image: none; tab-stops: center 3.85in; mso-padding-alt: 0in 0in 0in 0in;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Little Hogback Fire: 34,310 acres, 30% contained.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt; border: currentColor; border-image: none; tab-stops: center 3.85in; mso-padding-alt: 0in 0in 0in 0in;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman"&gt;Fire continued to spread slowly on the southwestern flank and along the northern perimeter. Crews finished constructing hand line, tying in to existing lines along Windlass Gulch, hoping to prevent the fire from spreading further. Firefighters were able to burnout into Windless Gulch and hand lines continue to hold there. Mop up operations continue on the east side of the fire, and crews are performing suppression repair where practical. Crews continue to provide structure protection along Rock Creek Road and helicopters aided firefighters by cooling hot spots in the remote terrain. Structure protection measures (including extensive hoselays) are still in place along Rock Creek Road. Preventing fire growth toward homes and ranches continues to dictate operational priorities, and protection of life is always the primary objective.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 6pt 0in 0pt; border: currentColor; border-image: none; mso-padding-alt: 0in 0in 0in 0in;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Goat Creek Fire: 8,305 acres, 95% contained.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 6pt; border: currentColor; border-image: none; mso-padding-alt: 0in 0in 0in 0in;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman"&gt;Rehabilitation of firelines and suppression activities continues in earnest. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 6pt 0in 0pt; border: currentColor; border-image: none; mso-padding-alt: 0in 0in 0in 0in;"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;Sliderock Fire: 901 acres, 95% contained. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 6pt; border: currentColor; border-image: none; mso-padding-alt: 0in 0in 0in 0in;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman"&gt;Crews continue to mop up hotspots and patrol the Sliderock Fire. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 6pt 0in; border: currentColor; border-image: none; mso-padding-alt: 0in 0in 0in 0in;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Resources Threatened:&lt;/b&gt; Private property and structures in the Rock Creek, Upper Willow Creek, and Marshall Creek drainages remain threatened. Other resources threatened include fisheries in Rock Creek, grazing lands along the southern boundary of the Little Hogback Fire, Bonneville Power Administration powerline, and a communication site.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 6pt 0in; border: currentColor; border-image: none; mso-padding-alt: 0in 0in 0in 0in;"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Evacuations:&lt;/b&gt; A Level Red-Evacuation Order for approximately thirty-five residences along Rock Creek Road remains in effect, beginning from and including Wild Rose Loop south to Stony Creek. All other Level Yellow-Pre-evacuation notices are still in effect.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;For information on evacuation planning refer to the Ready-Set-Go materials available at &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.wildlandfirersg.org/Portals/18/Resources/States/MT/RSG_Montana_ActionGuide_web.pdf"&gt;&lt;font color="#0563c1" face="Times New Roman"&gt;http://www.wildlandfirersg.org/Portals/18/Resources/States/MT/RSG_Montana_ActionGuide_web.pdf&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 6pt 0in; border: currentColor; border-image: none; mso-padding-alt: 0in 0in 0in 0in;"&gt;&lt;a name="_gjdgxs"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Closures: &lt;/b&gt;The Rock Creek Road from I-90 south to Bitterroot Campground (MP 23.5) is OPEN. Due to fire traffic congestion and fire safety concerns, Rock Creek Road will stay CLOSED from Bitterroot Campground, south to Cornish Gulch (FSR5027), and public traffic is NOT allowed. Upper Willow Creek Road is currently closed to the public. The Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest reduced closure restrictions in the Black Pine ridge area, but maintains all area closures in Upper Willow Creek, North Fork Lower Willow Creek, and Harvey Creek areas. The Bureau of Land Management has an area closure in Upper Willow Creek, Ram Mountain, and nearby areas. The Lolo and Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forests, the Bureau of Land Management, and the Montana Department of Natural Resources (DNRC) closure orders and maps are posted under the &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/closures/5364/"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;closures tab&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman"&gt; on Inciweb. Please adhere to all closures and allow our firefighters to perform their jobs safely.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 3.75pt 1.5pt;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Weather: &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 3.75pt 1.5pt;"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;Smoky conditions moderated temperatures on Wednesday, but they still climbed into the mid-80’s, while humidity dropped to near 10%. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;Thursday will continue to be warm and dry with light, terrain dominated winds.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 6pt 0in; border: currentColor; border-image: none; mso-padding-alt: 0in 0in 0in 0in;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Fire Restrictions:&lt;/b&gt; Stage 1 Fire Restrictions are in place on the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest (Forest Service land east of Sandstone Ridge), with the additional modification to prohibit all campfires. Stage 2 Fire Restrictions are in place on BLM, private and state lands in Granite County, and the Lolo National Forest (Forest Service land west of Sandstone Ridge). &lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;For information on fire restrictions, please visit &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://firerestrictions.us/"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;firerestrictions.us&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman"&gt;.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Sapphire Complex"></category></entry><entry><title>Sapphire Complex Smoke Report 09.07.2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5364_40278.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-07T11:20:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-07T11:20:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-07:/montana_fires/5364_40278.html</id><summary type="html">Sapphire Complex Smoke Report</summary><content type="html">Sapphire Complex Smoke Report</content><category term="Sapphire Complex"></category></entry><entry><title>Meyers Fire Update for September 7, 2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5397_40250.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-07T08:29:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-07T08:29:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-07:/montana_fires/5397_40250.html</id><summary type="html">Current Size:  57,933 acresResources Assigned: 376  Status: The fire is burning in mixed conifer stands, primarily lodgepole pine, Douglas-fir, and subalpine fir, with numerous standing dead trees. There are residences still at risk in the Moose Lake, Frog Pond, Billy Springer Memorial Park and Bonanza Lands areas. Yesterday’s Activities: Thick smoke laid across the fire limiting fire growth much of the day. Winds were favorable for burnout operations in Moose Lake and Zeke’s Meadows later in the day. Both burnout operations were successful in reducing fuels in these areas to limit future fire spread. Reconnaissance flights over the fire confirmed fire is active on the east side of the Continental Divide in Howell Creek. Firefighters started assessing structures and other values at risk in advance of the fire on the east side of the Divide. Crews were shared with the Sapphire Complex to assist with their burning operations. Mike Dueitt’s Southern Area Type 1 Team met with the...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Meyers Fire Update for September 7, 2017&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Meyers Fire Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 31 min. ago&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- 
cached related article links at 09:00:28
cached id 2e2eafda03b811082f71e76a3ee53704
--&gt;
&lt;div id="related_block"&gt;&lt;h4 id="related_head"&gt;Related Information&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul class="related_list"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/photos/MTBDF/2017-07-20-1925-Meyers-Fire/related_files/pict20170807-084711-0.pdf" rel="new"&gt;Meyers Fire Update September 7, 2017 (pdf 94 kb)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="2"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 4pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Current Size: &lt;/b&gt; 57,933 acres&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Resources Assigned&lt;/b&gt;: 376 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 4pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 4pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Status:&lt;/b&gt; The fire is burning in mixed conifer stands, primarily lodgepole pine, Douglas-fir, and subalpine fir, with numerous standing dead trees. There are residences still at risk in the Moose Lake, Frog Pond, Billy Springer Memorial Park and Bonanza Lands areas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 4pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 4pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Yesterday’s Activities: &lt;/b&gt;Thick smoke laid across the fire limiting fire growth much of the day. Winds were favorable for burnout operations in Moose Lake and Zeke’s Meadows later in the day. Both burnout operations were successful in reducing fuels in these areas to limit future fire spread. Reconnaissance flights over the fire confirmed fire is active on the east side of the Continental Divide in Howell Creek. Firefighters started assessing structures and other values at risk in advance of the fire on the east side of the Divide. Crews were shared with the Sapphire Complex to assist with their burning operations. Mike Dueitt’s Southern Area Type 1 Team met with the Meyers Fire and Sapphire Complex teams, local land management agencies, and cooperators to begin transition of incident management.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 4pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 4pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Current Resources: Five&lt;/b&gt; 20-person crews, &lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;twenty-one&lt;/b&gt; engines, &lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;four&lt;/b&gt; pieces of heavy equipment (skidgines, dozers, masticators), &lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;ten &lt;/b&gt;water tenders, and &lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;three&lt;/b&gt; helicopters. Total personnel: &lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;376&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 4pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 4pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Today’s Activities:&lt;/b&gt; The high pressure weather system that moved into the area will hold the smoke over the fire area. This will again limit fire activity. Most of the fire growth will occur due to slope and terrain, not wind. Structure protection is still the priority on the fire. Crews will patrol and mop up the previous day’s burnout operations to ensure no heat remains. Machine and hand line is still under construction on the East Fork of the Bitterroot around the 2 subdivisions. Firefighters will hold and improve lines in Frog Pond and conduct burnout operations where feasible. The Type 1 team will be shadowing both the Sapphire Complex and Meyers Fire personnel before taking command of the fires at 6:00 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 4pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 4pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Evacuations: &lt;/b&gt;The Frog Pond and Moose Lake areas are under an evacuation order. Additionally, an evacuation warning is in effect on East Fork Rd from FS Rd 5778 to Little East Fork Rd (FS RD 724) on the Bitterroot National Forest. Those under an evacuation warning should be prepared to leave at a moment’s notice. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 4pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 4pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Restrictions/Closures: &lt;/b&gt;Closure orders are in place on both National Forests.&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt; &lt;/b&gt;Bitterroot National Forest emergency closure orders are in effect for upper areas of the East Fork Bitterroot River.&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt; &lt;/b&gt;The Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest &lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;has expanded&lt;/b&gt; the emergency closure order around the fire.&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt; &lt;/b&gt;A temporary flight restriction (TFR) is in effect surrounding the Meyers Fire area. Granite County is under Stage 2 fire restrictions for private lands in the county. Amended Stage 1 fire restrictions are in effect today which prohibits &lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;ALL&lt;/b&gt; campfires in southwestern Montana on public lands, including in fire rings and developed recreation areas. For fire restriction details, visit &lt;a href="https://firerestrictions.us/mt/"&gt;&lt;font color="#0000ff"&gt;firerestrictions.us/mt&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 4pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 4pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;For further information&lt;/b&gt;, follow the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/US-Forest-Service-Beaverhead-Deerlodge-National-Forest-1540138089548920/"&gt;&lt;font color="#0000ff"&gt;Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest Facebook&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/DiscoverBitterrootNF"&gt;&lt;font color="#0000ff"&gt;Bitterroot National Forest Facebook&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt; pages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 4pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 4pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Meyers Fire"></category></entry><entry><title>Sapphire Complex Smoke Report 09.06.2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5364_40179.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-06T10:45:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-06T10:45:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-06:/montana_fires/5364_40179.html</id><summary type="html">Sapphire Complex Smoke Report</summary><content type="html">Sapphire Complex Smoke Report</content><category term="Sapphire Complex"></category></entry><entry><title>Sapphire Complex Daily Update 09.06.2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5364_40177.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-06T10:42:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-06T10:42:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-06:/montana_fires/5364_40177.html</id><summary type="html">Three fires comprise the Sapphire Complex: Little Hogback, Goat Creek, and Sliderock fires. Mike Almas’ Northern Rockies Type II Incident Management Team (IMT) is managing the incident. The fires are burning in steep, rocky terrain between the Rock Creek and Upper Willow Creek drainages.     Little Hogback Fire: 34,219 acres, 30% contained.     Fire grew actively along the north-central perimeter and continued to spread on the southwestern fire perimeter, in the upper end of Windlass Gulch. Fire managers hope to hold the fire there and have assessed three potential contingency lines if it does advance. To prevent fire spread, crews will construct hand line to tie-in with existing lines. If weather is favorable and lines tied in, a burnout is planned to secure the fire in Windlass. Mop up operations continue on the east side of the fire, and crews are performing suppression repair where practical. Crews continue to provide structure protection along Rock Creek Road and helicopters...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sapphire Complex Daily Update 09.06.2017&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Sapphire Complex Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 18 min. ago&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- 
cached related article links at 11:00:18
cached id f5d3021a555edf3025bf9e40eee99acf
--&gt;
&lt;div id="related_block"&gt;&lt;h4 id="related_head"&gt;Related Information&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul class="related_list"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/photos/MTLNF/2017-07-14-1837-Slide-Rock-Fire/related_files/pict20170806-104539-0.pdf" rel="new"&gt;Sapphire Complex Daily Update 09.06.2017 (pdf 40 kb)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;Three fires comprise the Sapphire Complex: Little Hogback, Goat Creek, and Sliderock fires. Mike Almas’ Northern Rockies Type II Incident Management Team (IMT) is managing the incident. The fires are burning in steep, rocky terrain between the Rock Creek and Upper Willow Creek drainages. &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Little Hogback Fire: 34,219 acres, 30% contained.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;Fire grew actively along the north-central perimeter and continued to spread on the southwestern fire perimeter, in the upper end of Windlass Gulch. Fire managers hope to hold the fire there and have assessed three potential contingency lines if it does advance. To prevent fire spread, crews will construct hand line to tie-in with existing lines. If weather is favorable and lines tied in, a burnout is planned to secure the fire in Windlass. Mop up operations continue on the east side of the fire, and crews are performing suppression repair where practical. Crews continue to provide structure protection along Rock Creek Road and helicopters aided firefighters by cooling hot spots in the remote terrain. Structure protection measures (including extensive hoselays) are still in place along Rock Creek Road. Preventing fire growth toward homes and ranches continues to dictate operational priorities, and protection of life is always the primary objective.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Goat Creek Fire: 8,305 acres, 95% contained.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;Rehabilitation of firelines and suppression activities continues in earnest. &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;Sliderock Fire: 901 acres, 95% contained. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;Crews continue to mop up hotspots and patrol the Sliderock Fire. &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Resources Threatened:&lt;/b&gt; Private property and structures in the Rock Creek, Upper Willow Creek, and Marshall Creek drainages remain threatened. Other resources threatened include fisheries in Rock Creek, grazing lands along the southern boundary of the Little Hogback Fire, Bonneville Power Administration powerline, and a communication site.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Evacuations:&lt;/b&gt; A Level Red-Evacuation Order for approximately thirty-five residences along Rock Creek Road remains in effect, beginning from and including Wild Rose Loop south to Stony Creek. All other Level Yellow-Pre-evacuation notices are still in effect.&lt;font size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;For information on evacuation planning refer to the Ready-Set-Go materials available at &lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.wildlandfirersg.org/Portals/18/Resources/States/MT/RSG_Montana_ActionGuide_web.pdf"&gt;&lt;font color="#0563c1" face="Times New Roman"&gt;http://www.wildlandfirersg.org/Portals/18/Resources/States/MT/RSG_Montana_ActionGuide_web.pdf&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="_gjdgxs"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Closures: &lt;/b&gt;The Rock Creek Road from I-90 south to Bitterroot Campground (MP 23.5) is OPEN. Due to fire traffic congestion and fire safety concerns, Rock Creek Road will stay CLOSED from Bitterroot Campground, south to Cornish Gulch (FSR5027), and public traffic is NOT allowed. Upper Willow Creek Road is currently closed to the public. The Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest reduced closure restrictions in the Black Pine ridge area, but maintains all area closures in Upper Willow Creek, North Fork Lower Willow Creek, and Harvey Creek areas. The Bureau of Land Management has an area closure in Upper Willow Creek, Ram Mountain, and nearby areas. The Lolo and Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forests, the Bureau of Land Management, and the Montana Department of Natural Resources (DNRC) closure orders and maps are posted under the &lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/closures/5364/"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;closures tab&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt; on Inciweb. Please adhere to all closures and allow our firefighters to perform their jobs safely.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Weather: &lt;/b&gt; Dry conditions continued across the region Tuesday. Temperatures climbed to the lower 80s in the valleys and middle 70s along mid-slopes and ridge tops. Warmer, drier conditions are expected throughout the week.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Fire Restrictions:&lt;/b&gt; Stage 1 Fire Restrictions are in place on the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest (Forest Service land east of Sandstone Ridge), with the additional modification to prohibit all campfires. Stage 2 Fire Restrictions are in place on BLM, private and state lands in Granite County, and the Lolo National Forest (Forest Service land west of Sandstone Ridge). &lt;b&gt;For information on fire restrictions, please visit &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://firerestrictions.us/"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;firerestrictions.us&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Sapphire Complex"></category></entry><entry><title>Meyers Fire Update September 6th, 2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5397_40163.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-06T08:41:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-06T08:41:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-06:/montana_fires/5397_40163.html</id><summary type="html">Current Size:  56,333 acres Resources Assigned: 345 Status: The fire is burning in mixed conifer stands, primarily lodgepole pine, Douglas fir, and subalpine fir, with numerous standing dead trees. There are residences still at risk in the Moose Lake, Frog Pond, Springer Memorial Park and Bonanza Lands areas. Yesterday’s Activities: The significant change in fire weather conditions the past two days gave firefighters a chance to reassess and adress the fire growth that occurred over the holiday weekend. The crews working at Moose Lake had the time and space to safely reset sprinkler systems throughout the community and perform burnout operations west of the Mooselake Rd. Around the Springer Memorial Park, dozer and hand line construction will provide a fire control line while sprinkler systems and other structure protection measures are implemented around buildings within the park. South of Frog Pond western extension of the fire front was assessed for its potential to impact the...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Meyers Fire Update September 6th, 2017&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Meyers Fire Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 20 min. ago&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- 
cached related article links at 09:00:33
cached id aa012180d3775a04427a923959c8fd01
--&gt;
&lt;div id="related_block"&gt;&lt;h4 id="related_head"&gt;Related Information&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul class="related_list"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/photos/MTBDF/2017-07-20-1925-Meyers-Fire/related_files/pict20170806-084351-0.pdf" rel="new"&gt;Printable Meyers Fire Update September 6th, 2017 (pdf 95 kb)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b style="font-size: 11.008px;"&gt;Current Size: &lt;/b&gt; 56,333 acres &lt;b style="font-size: 11.008px;"&gt;Resources Assigned&lt;/b&gt;: 345 &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Status:&lt;/b&gt; The fire is burning in mixed conifer stands, primarily lodgepole pine, Douglas fir, and subalpine fir, with numerous standing dead trees. There are residences still at risk in the Moose Lake, Frog Pond, Springer Memorial Park and Bonanza Lands areas.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Yesterday’s Activities: &lt;/b&gt;The significant change in fire weather conditions the past two days gave firefighters a chance to reassess and adress the fire growth that occurred over the holiday weekend. The crews working at Moose Lake had the time and space to safely reset sprinkler systems throughout the community and perform burnout operations west of the Mooselake Rd. Around the Springer Memorial Park, dozer and hand line construction will provide a fire control line while sprinkler systems and other structure protection measures are implemented around buildings within the park. South of Frog Pond western extension of the fire front was assessed for its potential to impact the area from a new direction. Crews continued to prepare cabins to resist the fire’s approach. On the north end of the fire, burning conditions were not conducive to black line or burnout operations. Instead, crews used direct attack in the bottom of Senate Creek to contain a small spot fire. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Current Resources: Four&lt;/b&gt; 20-person crews, &lt;b&gt;twenty-one&lt;/b&gt; engines, &lt;b&gt;four&lt;/b&gt; pieces of heavy equipment (skidgines, dozers, masticators), &lt;b&gt;ten &lt;/b&gt;water tenders, and &lt;b&gt;three&lt;/b&gt; helicopters. Total personnel: &lt;b&gt;345&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Today’s Activities: &lt;/b&gt;With a warming trend and west/northwest winds returning to the Meyers Fire area, increases in fire activity can be expected. Firefighters will utilize conditions to their advantage to complete burnout operations east of Zeke’s meadow, south and west of Moose Lake, and in advantageous places within the Frog Pond area. Point protection of houses will continue as these tactics are implemented and in anticipation of expected fire advance. Bull dozer and hand line construction around Springer Memorial Park and Bonanza is ongoing as structure assessments and preparations are made amidst the communities. With the fire’s advance southeast across the Continental Divide into the upper portions of Howell’s Creek, firefighters are making aerial and ground observations to determine a course of action for point protection of values at risk. Mike Dueitt’s Southern Area Type 1 Incident Management Team will be arriving in Montana and familiarizing themselves with the Meyers Fire and Sapphire Complex. Management and command of the fires will transition to the new team on Thursday September 7, 2017 at 6:00PM. &lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Evacuations: &lt;/b&gt;The Frog Pond and Moose Lake areas are under an evacuation order. Additionally, an evacuation warning is in effect on East Fork Rd from FS Rd 5778 to Little East Fork Rd (FS RD 724) on the Bitterroot National Forest. Those under an evacuation warning should be prepared to leave at a moment’s notice. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Restrictions/Closures: Closure orders are in place on both National Forests. &lt;/b&gt;Bitterroot National Forest emergency closure orders are in effect for upper areas of the East Fork Bitterroot River.&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest has an emergency closure order around the fire extending into the Anaconda Pintler Wilderness.&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;A temporary flight restriction (TFR) is in effect surrounding the Meyers Fire area. Granite County is under Stage 2 fire restrictions for private lands in the county. Amended Stage 1 fire restrictions are in effect today which prohibits &lt;b&gt;ALL&lt;/b&gt; campfires in southwestern Montana on public lands, including in fire rings and developed recreation areas. For fire restriction details, visit &lt;a href="https://firerestrictions.us/mt/"&gt;firerestrictions.us/mt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;For further information&lt;/b&gt;, follow the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/US-Forest-Service-Beaverhead-Deerlodge-National-Forest-1540138089548920/"&gt;Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/DiscoverBitterrootNF"&gt;Bitterroot National Forest Facebook&lt;/a&gt; pages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Meyers Fire"></category></entry><entry><title>Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest Closure Order</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5397_40209.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-05T18:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-05T18:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-05:/montana_fires/5397_40209.html</id><summary type="html">See the links to the right for the updated closure order for the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National</summary><content type="html">See the links to the right for the updated closure order for the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National</content><category term="Meyers Fire"></category></entry><entry><title>Meyers Fire Update September 5, 2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5397_40107.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-05T13:03:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-05T13:03:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-05:/montana_fires/5397_40107.html</id><summary type="html">FACT SHEET       Meyers Fire      September 5, 2017         Fire Information Line: (406) 859-9107 Office hours: 8:00 a.m. to 8:00 p.m.     Email: meyerswhetstone@gmail.com     Public Meeting Tonight in Philipsburg at 5:00 pm at Granite High School Cafeteria            Incident: The Meyers Fire was started by lightning on July 14, 2017. It merged with the Whetstone Fire (3,621 acre), also started by lightning, on July 13, 2017.    Location: 25 miles southwest of Philipsburg, Montana.    Agency Jurisdiction:  USDA Forest Service, Beaverhead-Deerlodge and Bitterroot National Forests    Incident Management: Irv Leach’s Northern Rockies Type 2 Incident Management Team.           Current Size:  54,814 acres  Resources Assigned: 344      Status: The fire is burning in mixed conifer stands, primarily lodgepole pine, Douglas fir, and subalpine fir, with numerous standing dead trees. There are residences still at risk in the Moose Lake, Frog Pond, Springer Memorial Park and...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Meyers Fire Update September 5, 2017&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Meyers Fire Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 27 min. ago&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- 
cached related article links at 13:30:23
cached id 3f5efd2a2f134c47111f20d015502279
--&gt;
&lt;div id="related_block"&gt;&lt;h4 id="related_head"&gt;Related Information&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul class="related_list"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/photos/MTBDF/2017-07-20-1925-Meyers-Fire/related_files/pict20170805-130521-0.pdf" rel="new"&gt;Meyers Fire Update September 5, 2017 (pdf 95 kb)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;b&gt;FACT SHEET&lt;/b&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;font face="Arial Black"&gt;Meyers Fire &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p align="center" style="margin: 4pt 0in; text-align: center;"&gt; September 5, 2017 &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p align="center" style="margin: 4pt 0in 4pt 9.35pt; text-align: center; tab-stops: right 7.0in;"&gt; Fire Information Line: &lt;b&gt;(406) 859-9107&lt;/b&gt; Office hours: 8:00 a.m. to 8:00 p.m. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p align="center" style="margin: 4pt 0in 4pt 9.35pt; text-align: center; tab-stops: right 7.0in;"&gt; Email: &lt;a href="mailto:meyerswhetstone@gmail.com"&gt;&lt;font color="#0000ff"&gt;meyerswhetstone@gmail.com&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p align="center" style="margin: 4pt 0in 4pt 9.35pt; text-align: center; tab-stops: right 7.0in;"&gt; &lt;b&gt;Public Meeting Tonight in Philipsburg at 5:00 pm at Granite High School Cafeteria&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p align="center" style="margin: 4pt 0in 4pt 9.35pt; text-align: center; tab-stops: right 7.0in;"&gt; &lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Incident:&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;The Meyers Fire was started by lightning on July 14, 2017. It merged with the Whetstone Fire (3,621 acre), also started by lightning, on July 13, 2017.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Location: &lt;/b&gt;25 miles southwest of Philipsburg, Montana.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Agency Jurisdiction:&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;USDA Forest Service, &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Beaverhead-Deerlodge and Bitterroot National Forests&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Incident Management:&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Irv Leach’s Northern Rockies Type 2 Incident Management Team.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Current Size: &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;54,814 acres &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;b&gt;Resources Assigned&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;: 344 &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Status:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;The fire is burning in mixed conifer stands, primarily lodgepole pine, Douglas fir, and subalpine fir, with numerous standing dead trees. There are residences still at risk in the Moose Lake, Frog Pond, Springer Memorial Park and Bonanza Lands areas.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Yesterday’s Activities: &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Overall fire activity moderated due to lower temperatures, smoky skies shading the fire, and a reduction in wind speed. Smoke limited helicopter use, but they were able to support water bucket drops southwest of Kaiser Lake up the Senate Creek drainage. Pumps and sprinklers are in working order around the residences. Frog Pond and Moose Lake structures have not been damaged by the fire growth around them. At the Springer Memorial and Bonanza Lands area, the hand line and machine line under constructions were prepped and brought in closer to the existing subdivisions. The containment dropped from five percent to zero based on the increases fire perimeter on Sunday. &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Current Resources: &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Three&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; 20-person crews, &lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;twenty&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; engines, &lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;four&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; pieces of heavy equipment (skidgines, dozers, masticators), &lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;ten &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;water tenders, and &lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;three&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; helicopters.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Total personnel:&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;b&gt;344&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Today’s Activities: &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Today will generally be warmer across the Meyers Fire area with light winds coming from the east. Fire behavior will be less affected by wind and driven more by terrain and should be similar to yesterday due to the smoke cover preventing the sun’s warmth heating the fuels. Structure protection measures are strong in resident areas of Frog Pond, Moose Lake, and East Fork Bitterroot. Some crews will be moving to the Bitterroot National Forest side of the fire to help work on the in-direct line around Spinger Memorial. Burning operations around Zeke’s Meadow and Moose Lake plan to bring fire closer to the lines built over the last few weeks.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Evacuations: &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;The Frog Pond and Moose Lake areas are under an evacuation order. Additionally, an evacuation warning is in effect on East Fork Rd from FS Rd 5778 to Little East Fork Rd (FS RD 724) on the Bitterroot National Forest. Those under an evacuation warning should be prepared to leave at a moment’s notice. &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Restrictions/Closures: &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Closure orders are in place on both National Forests. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Bitterroot National Forest emergency closure orders are in effect for upper areas of the East Fork Bitterroot River.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest has an emergency closure order around the fire extending into the Anaconda Pintler Wilderness.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;A temporary flight restriction (TFR) is in effect surrounding the Meyers Fire area. Granite County is under Stage 2 fire restrictions for private lands in the county. Amended Stage 1 fire restrictions are in effect today which prohibits &lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;ALL&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; campfires in southwestern Montana on public lands, including in fire rings and developed recreation areas. For fire restriction details, visit &lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://firerestrictions.us/mt/"&gt;&lt;font color="#0000ff" size="2"&gt;firerestrictions.us/mt&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;For further information&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;, follow the &lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/US-Forest-Service-Beaverhead-Deerlodge-National-Forest-1540138089548920/"&gt;&lt;font color="#0000ff" size="2"&gt;Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest Facebook&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; and &lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/DiscoverBitterrootNF"&gt;&lt;font color="#0000ff" size="2"&gt;Bitterroot National Forest Facebook&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; pages.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Meyers Fire"></category></entry><entry><title>Public Meeting, Meyers Fire and Sapphire Complex, September 5, Philipsburg</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5397_40053.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-05T10:16:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-05T10:16:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-05:/montana_fires/5397_40053.html</id><summary type="html">A public meeting for the Meyers Fire and Sapphire Complex will be held tonight, September 5, at 5:00 pm. It will be in the cafeteria at the Granite County High School, 407 Schnepel Street, Philipsburg. Representatives from the Beaverhead-Deerlodge and Lolo National Forests, Northern Rockies Incident Management Teams, and other local officials will be present to provide current</summary><content type="html">A public meeting for the Meyers Fire and Sapphire Complex will be held tonight, September 5, at 5:00 pm. It will be in the cafeteria at the Granite County High School, 407 Schnepel Street, Philipsburg. Representatives from the Beaverhead-Deerlodge and Lolo National Forests, Northern Rockies Incident Management Teams, and other local officials will be present to provide current</content><category term="Meyers Fire"></category></entry><entry><title>Smoke Outlook- East of the Sapphire Mountains 09.05.2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5364_40086.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-05T10:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-05T10:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-05:/montana_fires/5364_40086.html</id><summary type="html">Smoke OUtlook- East of the Sapphire Mountains,</summary><content type="html">Smoke OUtlook- East of the Sapphire Mountains,</content><category term="Sapphire Complex"></category></entry><entry><title>Sapphire Complex Daily Update 09.05.2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5364_40091.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-05T10:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-05T10:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-05:/montana_fires/5364_40091.html</id><summary type="html">Three fires comprise the Sapphire Complex: Little Hogback, Goat Creek, and Sliderock fires. Mike Almas’ Northern Rockies Type II Incident Management Team (IMT) is managing the incident. The fires are burning in steep, rocky terrain between the Rock Creek and Upper Willow Creek drainages.      Little Hogback Fire: 34,102 acres, 30% contained.      Monday, the fire grew actively along the north-central perimeter and continued to spread on the southwestern fire perimeter, in the upper end of Windlass Gulch. Although fire managers are hoping to hold the fire there, they have assessed three potential contingency lines if the fire continues to advance. Mop up operations are continuing on the east side of the fire, and crews are performing suppression repair where it is practical to do so. Crews continued to provide point protection for structures along Rock Creek Road and helicopters aided firefighters by cooling hot spots in the remote terrain. Structure protection measures (including...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sapphire Complex Daily Update 09.05.2017&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Sapphire Complex Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 3 hrs. ago&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- 
cached related article links at 12:30:18
cached id aec5133565531db7f355862273032ec3
--&gt;
&lt;div id="related_block"&gt;&lt;h4 id="related_head"&gt;Related Information&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul class="related_list"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/photos/MTLNF/2017-07-14-1837-Slide-Rock-Fire/related_files/pict20170805-122633-0.pdf" rel="new"&gt;Sapphire Complex Daily Update  09.05.2017 (pdf 136 kb)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p style="margin: 6pt 0in; tab-stops: center 3.85in;"&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;Three fires comprise the Sapphire Complex: Little Hogback, Goat Creek, and Sliderock fires. Mike Almas’ Northern Rockies Type II Incident Management Team (IMT) is managing the incident. The fires are burning in steep, rocky terrain between the Rock Creek and Upper Willow Creek drainages. &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt; tab-stops: center 3.85in;"&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Little Hogback Fire: 34,102 acres, 30% contained.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt; tab-stops: center 3.85in;"&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;Monday, the fire grew actively along the north-central perimeter and continued to spread on the southwestern fire perimeter, in the upper end of Windlass Gulch. Although fire managers are hoping to hold the fire there, they have assessed three potential contingency lines if the fire continues to advance. Mop up operations are continuing on the east side of the fire, and crews are performing suppression repair where it is practical to do so. Crews continued to provide point protection for structures along Rock Creek Road and helicopters aided firefighters by cooling hot spots in the remote terrain. Structure protection measures (including extensive hoselays) are still in place along Rock Creek Road. Preventing fire growth toward homes and ranches continues to dictate operational priorities, and protection of life is always the primary objective.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Goat Creek Fire: 8,305 acres, 95% contained.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;Rehabilitation of firelines and suppression activities is continuing in earnest. &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;Sliderock Fire: 901 acres, 95% contained. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;Crews continue to mop up hotspots and patrol the Sliderock Fire. &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Resources Threatened:&lt;/b&gt; Private property and structures in the Rock Creek, Upper Willow Creek, and Marshall Creek drainages remain threatened. Other resources threatened include fisheries in Rock Creek, grazing lands along the southern boundary of the Little Hogback Fire, Bonneville Power Administration powerline, and a communication site.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Evacuations:&lt;/b&gt; A Level Red-Evacuation Order for approximately thirty-five residences along Rock Creek Road remains in effect, beginning from and including Wild Rose Loop south to Stony Creek. All other Level Yellow-Pre-evacuation notices are still in effect.&lt;font size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;For information on evacuation planning refer to the Ready-Set-Go materials available at &lt;a href="http://www.wildlandfirersg.org/Portals/18/Resources/States/MT/RSG_Montana_ActionGuide_web.pdf"&gt;&lt;font color="#0563c1"&gt;http://www.wildlandfirersg.org/Portals/18/Resources/States/MT/RSG_Montana_ActionGuide_web.pdf&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="_gjdgxs"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Closures: &lt;/b&gt;The Rock Creek Road from I-90 south to Bitterroot Campground (MP 23.5) is OPEN. Due to fire traffic congestion and fire safety concerns, the Rock Creek Road will continue to be CLOSED from Bitterroot Campground, south to Cornish Gulch (FSR5027), and public traffic is NOT allowed. Upper Willow Creek Road is currently closed to the public. The Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest has reduced closure restrictions in the Black Pine ridge area, but maintains all area closures in the Upper Willow Creek, North Fork Lower Willow Creek, and Harvey Creek areas. The Bureau of Land Management has implemented an area closure in the Upper Willow Creek, Ram Mountain, and nearby areas. The Lolo and Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forests the Bureau of Land Management, and the Montana Department of Natural Resources (DNRC) closure orders and maps are posted under the &lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/closures/5364/"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;closures tab&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt; on Inciweb. Please adhere to all closures and allow our firefighters to perform their jobs safely.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;Weather: &lt;/b&gt; Although a cold front moved through Sunday, high pressure will return to the area. Thick smoke from regional fires may help keep temperatures lower over the fire area. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Fire Restrictions:&lt;/b&gt; Stage 1 Fire Restrictions are in place on the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest (Forest Service land east of Sandstone Ridge), with the additional modification to prohibit all campfires. Stage 2 Fire Restrictions are in place on BLM, private and state lands in Granite County, and the Lolo National Forest (Forest Service land west of Sandstone Ridge). &lt;b&gt;For information on fire restrictions, please visit &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="https://firerestrictions.us/"&gt;&lt;b&gt;firerestrictions.us&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Sapphire Complex"></category></entry><entry><title>Public Meeting Tuesday, September 5</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5364_40035.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-04T21:41:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-04T21:41:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-04:/montana_fires/5364_40035.html</id><summary type="html">Please join Mike Almas’ Incident Management Team for a public meeting regarding the Sapphire Complex fires this Tuesday, September 5, 2017 at 5 p.m. at the Granite High School in Phillipsburg. For more information email: SapphireComplexInfo@gmail.com or call (406) 540-3589.</summary><content type="html">Please join Mike Almas’ Incident Management Team for a public meeting regarding the Sapphire Complex fires this Tuesday, September 5, 2017 at 5 p.m. at the Granite High School in Phillipsburg. For more information email: SapphireComplexInfo@gmail.com or call (406) 540-3589.</content><category term="Sapphire Complex"></category></entry><entry><title>Public Meeting East Fork Bitterroot Residences</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5397_40003.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-04T14:14:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-04T14:14:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-04:/montana_fires/5397_40003.html</id><summary type="html">A public meeting for the Meyers Fire will be held tonight, September 4, at 6:00 pm. It will be at the Billy Springer Memorial Park Clubhouse, 1416 Springer Road, Sula. Representatives from the Darby/Sula Ranger District, Northern Rockies Incident Management Team, and Ravalli County Sheriff's Office will be present to provide current</summary><content type="html">A public meeting for the Meyers Fire will be held tonight, September 4, at 6:00 pm. It will be at the Billy Springer Memorial Park Clubhouse, 1416 Springer Road, Sula. Representatives from the Darby/Sula Ranger District, Northern Rockies Incident Management Team, and Ravalli County Sheriff's Office will be present to provide current</content><category term="Meyers Fire"></category></entry><entry><title>Meyers Fire Update September 4, 2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5397_39957.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-04T10:42:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-04T10:42:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-04:/montana_fires/5397_39957.html</id><summary type="html">FACT SHEET   Meyers Fire  September 4, 2017      Fire Information Line: (406) 859-9107 Office hours: 8:00 a.m. to 8:00 p.m.     Email: meyerswhetstone@gmail.com      Incident: The Meyers Fire was started by lightning on July 14, 2017. It merged with the Whetstone Fire (3,621 acre), also started by lightning, on July 13, 2017.    Location: 25 miles southwest of Philipsburg, Montana.    Agency Jurisdiction:  USDA Forest Service, Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest    Cooperating Agencies: Georgetown Lake Volunteer Fire Department, Granite County Commissioners, Granite County Sheriff’s Office, Ravalli County Sheriff’s Office, Granite County Office of Emergency Management, Ravalli County Office of Emergency Management, Montana DNRC, and Montana National Guard.    Incident Management: Irv Leach’s Northern Rockies Type 2 Incident Management Team.      Current Size:  53,737 acres  Resources Assigned: 334      Status: The fire is burning in mixed conifer stands, primarily...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Meyers Fire Update September 4, 2017&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Meyers Fire Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 18 min. ago&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- 
cached related article links at 11:00:16
cached id 694419ba65e0afd6fc648dabdc935d75
--&gt;
&lt;div id="related_block"&gt;&lt;h4 id="related_head"&gt;Related Information&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul class="related_list"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/photos/MTBDF/2017-07-20-1925-Meyers-Fire/related_files/pict20170804-104822-0.pdf" rel="new"&gt;Meyers Fire Update September 4, 2017 (pdf 95 kb)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 4pt 0in 4pt 9.35pt; tab-stops: right 7.0in;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 4pt 0in 4pt 9.35pt; tab-stops: right 7.0in;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;FACT SHEET&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;&lt;font face="Arial Black"&gt;Meyers Fire &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p align="center" style="margin: 4pt 0in; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;September 4, 2017 &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 4pt 0in 4pt 9.35pt; tab-stops: right 7.0in;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Fire Information Line: &lt;b&gt;(406) 859-9107&lt;/b&gt; Office hours: 8:00 a.m. to 8:00 p.m. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 4pt 0in 4pt 9.35pt; tab-stops: right 7.0in;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 4pt 0in 4pt 9.35pt; tab-stops: right 7.0in;"&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; Email: &lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="mailto:meyerswhetstone@gmail.com"&gt;&lt;font color="#0000ff" size="2"&gt;meyerswhetstone@gmail.com&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Incident:&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;The Meyers Fire was started by lightning on July 14, 2017. It merged with the Whetstone Fire (3,621 acre), also started by lightning, on July 13, 2017.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Location: &lt;/b&gt;25 miles southwest of Philipsburg, Montana.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Agency Jurisdiction:&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;USDA Forest Service, &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Cooperating Agencies:&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Georgetown Lake Volunteer Fire Department, Granite County Commissioners, Granite County Sheriff’s Office, Ravalli County Sheriff’s Office, Granite County Office of Emergency Management, Ravalli County Office of Emergency Management, Montana DNRC, and Montana National Guard.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Incident Management:&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Irv Leach’s Northern Rockies Type 2 Incident Management Team.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Current Size: &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;53,737 acres &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;b&gt;Resources Assigned&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;: 334 &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Status:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;The fire is burning in mixed conifer stands, primarily lodgepole pine, Douglas fir, and subalpine fir, with numerous standing dead trees. There are residences still at risk in the Moose Lake, Frog Pond, Springer Memorial Park and Bonanza areas.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Yesterday’s Activities: &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Fire activity was high on the south and east sides of the fire with significant growth in Fishtrap Creek and Carpp Creek drainages. The fire has grown to the east of the Continental Divide on the Beaverhead-Deerlodge and Bitterroot National Forests. The fire grew over 15,000 acres. Indirect, contingency lines, and perimeter structure protection continued in the Frog Pond, Moose Lake, Springer Memorial Park and Bonanza Lands communities. Structure protection and life safety continue to be priorities. Engines and National Guard fire equipment are in place in the Moose Lake subdivision. The Granite County Sheriff ordered a mandatory evacuation for Moose Lake last night. Additional burning and chipping of fuels was completed around Frog Pond residential area.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Crews worked to limit fire spread north of Zekes Meadow using helicopter water drops, but the old cabin in the meadow burned down.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Current Resources: &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Three&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; 20-person crews, &lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;nineteen&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; engines, &lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;four&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; pieces of heavy equipment (skidgines, dozers, masticators), &lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;ten &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;water tenders, and &lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;three&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; helicopters.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Total personnel:&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;b&gt;334&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Today’s Activities:&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Temperatures will be lower today, in the mid 70’s and humidity will be slightly higher. The wind will switch and be out of the northeast. Fire activity is expected to moderate today. Across the fire, point protection for structures remains the priority. Sprinklers are in place and are continually tested. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Construction will continue on hand and machine line around Springer Memorial Park and Bonanza Land residences. The line east from Zekes Meadow will be assessed to determine if it can be used for future burn out operations. Operations in Frog Pond area will bring the fire along the edges of meadows to further reduce fuels and secure the line. Engines and National Guard fire equipment is in place around Moose Lake.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Evacuations: &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;The Frog Pond and Moose Lake areas are under an evacuation order. Additionally, an evacuation warning is in effect on East Fork Rd from FS Rd 5778 to Little East Fork Rd (FS RD 724) on the Bitterroot National Forest. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Those under an evacuation warning should be prepared to leave at a moment’s notice. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Restrictions/Closures: &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Expanded closure orders were issued on both National Forests yesterday. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Bitterroot National Forest emergency closure orders are in effect for upper areas of the East Fork Bitterroot River.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest has an emergency closure order around the fire extending into the Anaconda Pintler Wilderness.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;A temporary flight restriction (TFR) is in effect surrounding the Meyers Fire area. Granite County is under Stage 2 fire restrictions for private lands in the county. Amended Stage 1 fire restrictions are in effect today which prohibits &lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;ALL&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; campfires in southwestern Montana on public lands, including in fire rings and developed recreation areas. &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;For further information&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;, follow the &lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/US-Forest-Service-Beaverhead-Deerlodge-National-Forest-1540138089548920/"&gt;&lt;font color="#0000ff" size="2"&gt;Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest Facebook&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; and &lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/DiscoverBitterrootNF"&gt;&lt;font color="#0000ff" size="2"&gt;Bitterroot National Forest Facebook&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; pages.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Meyers Fire"></category></entry><entry><title>Sapphire Complex Daily Update 09/04/17</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5364_39954.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-04T10:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-04T10:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-04:/montana_fires/5364_39954.html</id><summary type="html">Three fires comprise the Sapphire Complex: Little Hogback, Goat Creek, and Sliderock fires. Mike Almas’ Northern Rockies Type II Incident Management Team (IMT) is managing the incident. The fires are burning in steep, rocky terrain between the Rock Creek and Upper Willow Creek drainages.Little Hogback Fire: 32,698 acres, 30% contained.  Sunday, the southwestern flank continued spreading up canyon into Windlass Gulch. Crews continued to provide point protection for structures along Rock Creek Road and helicopters aided firefighters by cooling hot spots in the remote terrain. Fire managers are looking at several options for contingency lines to help stop fire spread to the north and east of Rock Creek Road. Structure protection measures (including extensive hoselays) are still in place along Rock Creek Road. Preventing fire growth toward homes and ranches continues to dictate operational priorities, and protection of life is always the primary objective.   Goat Creek Fire: 8,305...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sapphire Complex Daily Update 09/04/17&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Sapphire Complex Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 1:00 hrs. ago&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- 
cached related article links at 11:00:17
cached id 1ffebb03816303cf5834574a3a9fd203
--&gt;
&lt;div id="related_block"&gt;&lt;h4 id="related_head"&gt;Related Information&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul class="related_list"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/photos/MTLNF/2017-07-14-1837-Slide-Rock-Fire/related_files/pict20170804-103538-0.pdf" rel="new"&gt;Sapphire Complex Daily Update 09.04.17 (pdf 117 kb)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;Three fires comprise the Sapphire Complex: Little Hogback, Goat Creek, and Sliderock fires. Mike Almas’ Northern Rockies Type II Incident Management Team (IMT) is managing the incident. The fires are burning in steep, rocky terrain between the Rock Creek and Upper Willow Creek drainages.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b 11.008px;"="" font-size:="" new="" roman";="" style="" times=""&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Little Hogback Fire: 32,698 acres, 30% contained.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;Sunday, the southwestern flank continued spreading up canyon into Windlass Gulch. Crews continued to provide point protection for structures along Rock Creek Road and helicopters aided firefighters by cooling hot spots in the remote terrain. Fire managers are looking at several options for contingency lines to help stop fire spread to the north and east of Rock Creek Road. Structure protection measures (including extensive hoselays) are still in place along Rock Creek Road. Preventing fire growth toward homes and ranches continues to dictate operational priorities, and protection of life is always the primary objective. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="margin-top:6.0pt;"&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Goat Creek Fire: 8,305 acres, 95% contained.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="margin-bottom:6.0pt;"&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;Rehabilitation of firelines and fuel break construction is progressing rapidly, and crews continue to mop up interior hot spots. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="margin-top:6.0pt;"&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sliderock Fire: 901 acres, 95% contained. &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="margin-bottom:6.0pt;"&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;Crews continue to mop up hotspots and patrol the Sliderock Fire, resulting in increased containment. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="margin-bottom:6.0pt; margin-left:0in; margin-right:0in; margin-top:6.0pt;"&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Resources Threatened:&lt;/b&gt; Private property and structures in the Rock Creek, Upper Willow Creek, and Marshall Creek drainages remain threatened. Other resources threatened include fisheries in Rock Creek, grazing lands along the southern boundary of the Little Hogback Fire, Bonneville Power Administration powerline, and a communication site. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="margin-bottom:6.0pt; margin-left:0in; margin-right:0in; margin-top:6.0pt;"&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Evacuations:&lt;/b&gt; Due to fire activity on the Little Hogback fire and predicted weather conditions, the Granite County Sheriff issued a Level Red-Evacuation Order for some residences along Rock Creek Road, effective Saturday, September 2, at 10:00 p.m. The Level Red- Evacuation Order was issued to residences along both sides of Upper Rock Creek Road and adjacent roads/neighborhoods, beginning from and including Wild Rose Loop south to Stony Creek. Approximately 35 residences are impacted by the Level Red- Evacuation order. All other Level Yellow-Pre-evacuation notices are still in effect. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="margin-bottom:6.0pt; margin-left:0in; margin-right:0in; margin-top:6.0pt;"&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;b style=""&gt;Closures: &lt;/b&gt;The Rock Creek Road from I-90 south to Bitterroot Campground (MP 23.5) is OPEN. Due to fire traffic congestion and fire safety concerns, the Rock Creek Road will continue to be CLOSED from Bitterroot Campground, south to Cornish Gulch (FSR5027), and public traffic is NOT allowed. Upper Willow Creek Road is currently closed to the public. The Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest has reduced closure restrictions in the Black Pine ridge area, but maintains all area closures in the Upper Willow Creek, North Fork Lower Willow Creek, and Harvey Creek areas. The Bureau of Land Management has implemented an area closure in the Upper Willow Creek, Ram Mountain, and nearby areas. The Lolo and Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forests and the Bureau of Land Management have posted closure orders and maps under the &lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/closures/5364/" style=""&gt;closures tab&lt;/a&gt; on Inciweb. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;font new="" roman";"="" style="" times=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;Weather: &lt;/b&gt; Conditions continued to be hot and very dry on Sunday with gusty winds out of the west-northwest. A cold front moved through overnight, bringing with it cooler temperatures, slightly higher humidities and lighter winds out of the east-northeast, however a red flag warning will continue to be in effect through Monday evening. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;br 11.008px;"="" font-size:="" new="" roman";="" style="font-family: " times=""/&gt;&lt;b 11.008px;"="" font-size:="" new="" roman";="" style="" times=""&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Fire Restrictions:&lt;/b&gt; Stage 1 Fire Restrictions are in place on the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest (Forest Service land east of Sandstone Ridge), with the additional modification to prohibit all campfires. Stage 2 Fire Restrictions are in place on BLM, private and state lands in Granite County, and the Lolo National Forest (Forest Service land west of Sandstone Ridge). &lt;b style=""&gt;For information on fire restrictions, please visit &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a 11.008px;"="" font-size:="" href="https://firerestrictions.us/" new="" roman";="" style="" times=""&gt;&lt;b&gt;firerestrictions.us&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b 11.008px;"="" font-size:="" new="" roman";="" style="" times=""&gt;.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Sapphire Complex"></category></entry><entry><title>Smoke Outlook - East of the Sapphire Mountains 09.04.2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5364_39969.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-04T09:30:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-04T09:30:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-04:/montana_fires/5364_39969.html</id><summary type="html">Smoke Outlook - East of the Sapphire</summary><content type="html">Smoke Outlook - East of the Sapphire</content><category term="Sapphire Complex"></category></entry><entry><title>Meyers Fire Closure Area September 3, 2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5397_39907.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-03T17:47:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-03T17:47:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-03:/montana_fires/5397_39907.html</id><summary type="html">See the PDFs linked on the right for the closure orders issued by the Beaverhead-Deerlodge and Bitterroot National</summary><content type="html">See the PDFs linked on the right for the closure orders issued by the Beaverhead-Deerlodge and Bitterroot National</content><category term="Meyers Fire"></category></entry><entry><title>Sapphire Complec Daily Spoke Report 09.03.17</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5364_39835.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-03T10:32:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-03T10:32:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-03:/montana_fires/5364_39835.html</id><summary type="html">Sapphire Complex Spoke Report</summary><content type="html">Sapphire Complex Spoke Report</content><category term="Sapphire Complex"></category></entry><entry><title>Sapphire Complex Daily Update 09.03.2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5364_39845.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-03T09:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-03T09:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-03:/montana_fires/5364_39845.html</id><summary type="html">Three fires comprise the Sapphire Complex: Little Hogback, Goat Creek, and Sliderock fires. Mike Almas’ Northern Rockies Type II Incident Management Team (IMT) is managing the incident. The fires are burning in steep, rocky terrain between the Rock Creek and Upper Willow Creek drainages.      Little Hogback Fire: 31,452 acres, 30% contained.       Saturday, while crews were engaged in challenging burnout operations between Sheep Gulch and Capron Creek, a spot fire occurred due to erratic winds. As a result, firefighters could not successfully complete operations and were forced to fall back and provide point protection along Rock Creek Road. Several retardant drops were performed near the structures along Rock Creek Road and helicopters were used to aid firefighters with suppression in the steep terrain. The spot fire is now well established at more than 700 acres which may not be reflected in the total acreage listed above. Structure protection measures (including extensive...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sapphire Complex Daily Update 09.03.2017&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Sapphire Complex Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 3 hrs. ago&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- 
cached related article links at 11:30:18
cached id d5e4b1d06d0651abe01ccd1e9139d955
--&gt;
&lt;div id="related_block"&gt;&lt;h4 id="related_head"&gt;Related Information&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul class="related_list"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/photos/MTLNF/2017-07-14-1837-Slide-Rock-Fire/related_files/pict20170803-112004-0.pdf" rel="new"&gt;Sapphire Complex Daily Update 09.03.2017 (pdf 117 kb)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 6pt 0in; tab-stops: center 3.85in;"&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;Three fires comprise the Sapphire Complex: Little Hogback, Goat Creek, and Sliderock fires. Mike Almas’ Northern Rockies Type II Incident Management Team (IMT) is managing the incident. The fires are burning in steep, rocky terrain between the Rock Creek and Upper Willow Creek drainages.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt; tab-stops: center 3.85in;"&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Little Hogback Fire: 31,452 acres, 30% contained.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt; tab-stops: center 3.85in;"&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;Saturday, while crews were engaged in challenging burnout operations between Sheep Gulch and Capron Creek, a spot fire occurred due to erratic winds. As a result, firefighters could not successfully complete operations and were forced to fall back and provide point protection along Rock Creek Road. Several retardant drops were performed near the structures along Rock Creek Road and helicopters were used to aid firefighters with suppression in the steep terrain. The spot fire is now well established at more than 700 acres which may not be reflected in the total acreage listed above. Structure protection measures (including extensive hoselays) are still in place along Rock Creek Road. Preventing fire growth toward homes and ranches continues to dictate operational priorities, and protection of life is always the primary objective. &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Goat Creek Fire: 8,305 acres, 95% contained.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;Rehabilitation of firelines and fuel break construction is progressing rapidly, and crews continue to mop up interior hot spots. &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;Sliderock Fire: 901 acres, 95% contained. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;Crews continue to mop up hotspots and patrol the Sliderock Fire, resulting in increased containment.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Resources Threatened:&lt;/b&gt; Private property and structures in the Rock Creek, Upper Willow Creek, and Marshall Creek drainages remain threatened. Other resources threatened include fisheries in Rock Creek, grazing lands along the southern boundary of the Little Hogback Fire, Bonneville Power Administration powerline, and a communication site.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Evacuations:&lt;/b&gt; Due to fire activity on the Little Hogback fire and predicted weather conditions, the Granite County Sheriff issued a Level Red-Evacuation Order for some residences along Rock Creek Road, effective Saturday, September 2, at 10:00 p.m. The Level Red- Evacuation Order was issued to residences along both sides of Upper Rock Creek Road and adjacent roads/neighborhoods, beginning from and including Wild Rose Loop south to Stony Creek. Approximately 35 residences will be impacted by the Level Red- Evacuation order. All other Level Yellow-Pre-evacuation notices are still in effect.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Closures: &lt;/b&gt;The Rock Creek Road from I-90 south to Bitterroot Campground (MP 23.5) is OPEN. Due to fire traffic congestion and fire safety concerns, the Rock Creek Road will continue to be CLOSED from Bitterroot Campground, south to Cornish Gulch (FSR5027), and public traffic is NOT allowed. Upper Willow Creek Road is currently closed to the public. The Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest has reduced closure restrictions in the Black Pine ridge area, but maintains all area closures in the Upper Willow Creek, North Fork Lower Willow Creek, and Harvey Creek areas. The Bureau of Land Management has implemented an area closure in the Upper Willow Creek, Ram Mountain, and nearby areas. The Lolo and Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forests and the Bureau of Land Management have posted closure orders and maps under the &lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/closures/5364/"&gt;&lt;font color="#0000ff" face="Times New Roman"&gt;closures tab&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt; on Inciweb. &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt; &lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;Weather: &lt;/b&gt; Hot and very dry conditions persisted Saturday throughout the fire area with temperatures near 90 and relative humidities between 10% and 15%. Winds were out of the west at 12 to 16mph with gusts to 25mph increasing fire activity. Winds and higher temperatures will continue today prompting a red flag warning through Monday. &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Fire Restrictions:&lt;/b&gt; Stage 1 Fire Restrictions are in place on the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest (Forest Service land east of Sandstone Ridge), with the additional modification to prohibit all campfires. Stage 2 Fire Restrictions are in place on BLM, private and state lands in Granite County, and the Lolo National Forest (Forest Service land west of Sandstone Ridge). &lt;b&gt;For information on fire restrictions, please visit &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://firerestrictions.us/"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font color="#0000ff" face="Times New Roman"&gt;firerestrictions.us&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Sapphire Complex"></category></entry><entry><title>Meyers Fire Update September 3, 2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5397_39815.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-03T08:25:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-03T08:25:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-03:/montana_fires/5397_39815.html</id><summary type="html">Current Size:  37,649 acresResources Assigned: 333    Red flag warning issued till 9 p.m. tonight. No campfires allowed.   Status: The fire is burning in mixed conifer stands, primarily lodgepole pine, Douglas fir, and subalpine fir, with numerous standing dead trees. There are residences still at risk in the Moose Lake, Frog Pond, Springer Memorial Park and Bonanza areas. Yesterday’s Activities: Fire activity was highest around Zeke’s Meadow, Porter Ridge, and Reynolds Creek on the Bitterroot National Forest. Overall the fire grew over 7000 acres. Indirect, contingency lines, and perimeter structure protection were prepped in the East Fork of the Bitterroot area of the fire. The McCart lookout is nearly complete with foil wrapping. The indirect line near Zeke’s meadow is also nearly complete in preparation for possible burnout in the future. Conditions were favorable in the Frog Pond area for burnout operations in green areas of the fire and helicopters were able to drop water...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Meyers Fire Update September 3, 2017&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Meyers Fire Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 5 min. ago&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 4pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Current Size: &lt;/b&gt; 37,649 acres&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Resources Assigned&lt;/b&gt;: 333 &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 4pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="2"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p align="center" style="margin: 4pt 0in; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="4"&gt;Red flag warning issued till 9 p.m. tonight. No campfires allowed.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 4pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="2"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 4pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Status:&lt;/b&gt; The fire is burning in mixed conifer stands, primarily lodgepole pine, Douglas fir, and subalpine fir, with numerous standing dead trees. There are residences still at risk in the Moose Lake, Frog Pond, Springer Memorial Park and Bonanza areas.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 4pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Yesterday’s Activities: &lt;/b&gt;Fire activity was highest around Zeke’s Meadow, Porter Ridge, and Reynolds Creek on the Bitterroot National Forest. Overall the fire grew over 7000 acres. Indirect, contingency lines, and perimeter structure protection were prepped in the East Fork of the Bitterroot area of the fire. The McCart lookout is nearly complete with foil wrapping. The indirect line near Zeke’s meadow is also nearly complete in preparation for possible burnout in the future. Conditions were favorable in the Frog Pond area for burnout operations in green areas of the fire and helicopters were able to drop water on areas to slow the growth in other areas. Structure protection is still a priority for Moose Lake. A packer bridge sustained some railing damage from fire, but remains serviceable. Sprinklers were set on the bridges to prevent any further damage. Helicopters made 156 water drops, but had to stop operations later in the day because of high winds. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 4pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Current Resources: Three&lt;/b&gt; 20-person crews, &lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;seventeen&lt;/b&gt; engines, &lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;four&lt;/b&gt; pieces of heavy equipment (dozers, masticators), &lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;ten &lt;/b&gt;water tenders, and &lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;three&lt;/b&gt; helicopters. Total personnel: &lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;333&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 4pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Today’s Activities:&lt;/b&gt; Today is a critical fire weather day. A Red Flag warning has been issued and will remain in effect till 9 p.m. tonight. With temperatures 20 degrees above normal, extremely low humidity, sustained winds with gusts, significant fire growth is forecasted. Expect large smoke plumes. The most intense fire growth is projected in the East Fork of the Bitterroot moving east. Smoke from the fire activity in the East Fork Bitterroot will influence the progression of fire east of Moose Lake Road. Across the fire, point protection for structures will remain the priority. Crews will grid for spot fire on the east side of Moose Lake Road (FS Road 5106) to keep the fire west of the road north of Moose Lake. Hand and machine line construction is expected to start from the East Fork Road. The indirect line near Zeke’s Meadow will be improved today with a 20 person hot shot crew. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 4pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Evacuations: &lt;/b&gt;The Frog Pond area is under an evacuation order. Moose Lake residents are under an evacuation warning. Additionally, an evacuation warning is in effect on East Fork Rd from FS Rd 5778 to Little East Fork Rd (FS RD 724) on the Bitterroot National Forest. &lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Those under an evacuation warning should be prepared to leave at a moment’s notice. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 4pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Restrictions/Closures: &lt;/b&gt;Bitterroot National Forest emergency closure orders are in effect for upper areas of the East Fork Bitterroot River.&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt; &lt;/b&gt;Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt; &lt;/b&gt;emergency closure orders are in effect around the fire area.&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt; &lt;/b&gt;The closure of Forest Roads 893, 8684 and 8685 was rescinded at 6:00AM Friday, September 1, 2017. A temporary flight restriction (TFR) is in effect surrounding the Meyers Fire area. Granite County is under Stage 2 fire restrictions for private lands in the county. Amended Stage 1 fire restrictions have gone into effect today which prohibit &lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;ALL&lt;/b&gt; campfires in southwestern Montana, including in fire rings and developed recreation areas. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 4pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="2"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 4pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;For further information&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="2"&gt;follow the &lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/US-Forest-Service-Beaverhead-Deerlodge-National-Forest-1540138089548920/"&gt;&lt;font color="#0000ff" size="2"&gt;Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest Facebook&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="2"&gt; and &lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/DiscoverBitterrootNF"&gt;&lt;font color="#0000ff" size="2"&gt;Bitterroot National Forest Facebook&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="2"&gt; pages.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Meyers Fire"></category></entry><entry><title>New Level Red- Evacuation Orders issued by the Granite County Sheriff</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5364_39809.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-03T00:15:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-03T00:15:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-03:/montana_fires/5364_39809.html</id><summary type="html">Effective, Saturday, September 2, at 10:00 p.m., the Granite County Sheriff issued a Level Red- Evacuation Order for residences along both sides of Upper Rock Creek Road and adjacent roads/neighborhoods, beginning from and including Wild Rose Loop south to Stony Creek. Approximately thirty-five residences will be impacted by the Level Red- Evacuation order. The Sheriff also reaffirmed a Level Yellow- Pre-evacuation Notice for Upper Rock Creek Road from Stony Creek south to Kyle G. Bohrnsen Memorial Bridge, including residences on the lower Cornish Gulch Road and Basin Gulch Road. The evacuation orders were issued due to extreme fire activity, large fire growth along the southwest fire perimeter on Little Hogback Fire (part of the Sapphire Complex), the potential for spotting, and predicted winds from the northwest. See the Granite County Sheriff's Facebook page for more</summary><content type="html">Effective, Saturday, September 2, at 10:00 p.m., the Granite County Sheriff issued a Level Red- Evacuation Order for residences along both sides of Upper Rock Creek Road and adjacent roads/neighborhoods, beginning from and including Wild Rose Loop south to Stony Creek. Approximately thirty-five residences will be impacted by the Level Red- Evacuation order. The Sheriff also reaffirmed a Level Yellow- Pre-evacuation Notice for Upper Rock Creek Road from Stony Creek south to Kyle G. Bohrnsen Memorial Bridge, including residences on the lower Cornish Gulch Road and Basin Gulch Road. The evacuation orders were issued due to extreme fire activity, large fire growth along the southwest fire perimeter on Little Hogback Fire (part of the Sapphire Complex), the potential for spotting, and predicted winds from the northwest. See the Granite County Sheriff's Facebook page for more</content><category term="Sapphire Complex"></category></entry><entry><title>Red Flag Warning Meyers Fire September 2-3, 2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5397_39797.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-02T18:01:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-02T18:01:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-02:/montana_fires/5397_39797.html</id><summary type="html">The National Weather Service has issued a RED FLAG WARNING for the area around the Meyers Fire. This is effective immediately through 9:00 pm Sunday. This is due to dry, unstable air and gusty winds to 30</summary><content type="html">The National Weather Service has issued a RED FLAG WARNING for the area around the Meyers Fire. This is effective immediately through 9:00 pm Sunday. This is due to dry, unstable air and gusty winds to 30</content><category term="Meyers Fire"></category></entry><entry><title>Meyers Fire Closure September 2, 2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5397_39791.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-02T16:51:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-02T16:51:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-02:/montana_fires/5397_39791.html</id><summary type="html">The area closure on the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest around the Meyers Fire has been updated to include area in the Anaconda-Pintler Wilderness. This includes the Continental Divide Trail from Cutaway Pass to Mystic</summary><content type="html">The area closure on the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest around the Meyers Fire has been updated to include area in the Anaconda-Pintler Wilderness. This includes the Continental Divide Trail from Cutaway Pass to Mystic</content><category term="Meyers Fire"></category></entry><entry><title>Sapphire Complex Smoke Report 09.02.2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5364_39741.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-02T11:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-02T11:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-02:/montana_fires/5364_39741.html</id><summary type="html">Sapphire Complex Smoke Report</summary><content type="html">Sapphire Complex Smoke Report</content><category term="Sapphire Complex"></category></entry><entry><title>Sapphire Complex Daily Update 09.02.2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5364_39752.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-02T10:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-02T10:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-02:/montana_fires/5364_39752.html</id><summary type="html">Three fires comprise the Sapphire Complex: Little Hogback, Goat Creek, and Sliderock fires. Mike Almas’ Northern Rockies Type II Incident Management Team (IMT) is managing the incident. The fires are burning in steep, rocky terrain between the Rock Creek and Upper Willow Creek drainages.      Little Hogback Fire: 31,322 acres, 30% contained.      Friday, firefighters (aided by helicopter support) began performing a burnout operation starting on the ridge between Windlass and Sheep Gulch and continuing between Sheep Gulch and Capron Creek. These challenging burnout operations must be performed methodically, but weather has been cooperative and operations have been successful thus far. Such operations may be critical in securing firelines along the fire’s southwest perimeter and protecting structures in that area and will likely continue for one more day. Crews working along the fire’s eastern, western, and southern flanks further improved containment and firelines, mopping up...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sapphire Complex Daily Update 09.02.2017&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Sapphire Complex Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 5 hrs. ago&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- 
cached related article links at 14:31:35
cached id 2db96eb55560499397a27af9e72d3da9
--&gt;
&lt;div id="related_block"&gt;&lt;h4 id="related_head"&gt;Related Information&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul class="related_list"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/photos/MTLNF/2017-07-14-1837-Slide-Rock-Fire/related_files/pict20170802-121630-0.pdf" rel="new"&gt;Sapphire Complex Daily Update 09.02.2017 (pdf 117 kb)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 6pt 0in; tab-stops: center 3.85in;"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p style="margin: 6pt 0in; tab-stops: center 3.85in;"&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;Three fires comprise the Sapphire Complex: Little Hogback, Goat Creek, and Sliderock fires. Mike Almas’ Northern Rockies Type II Incident Management Team (IMT) is managing the incident. The fires are burning in steep, rocky terrain between the Rock Creek and Upper Willow Creek drainages. &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt; tab-stops: center 3.85in;"&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Little Hogback Fire: 31,322 acres, 30% contained.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt; tab-stops: center 3.85in;"&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;Friday, firefighters (aided by helicopter support) began performing a burnout operation starting on the ridge between Windlass and Sheep Gulch and continuing between Sheep Gulch and Capron Creek. These challenging burnout operations must be performed methodically, but weather has been cooperative and operations have been successful thus far. Such operations may be critical in securing firelines along the fire’s southwest perimeter and protecting structures in that area and will likely continue for one more day. Crews working along the fire’s eastern, western, and southern flanks further improved containment and firelines, mopping up hot spots, working inward from the fire perimeter. Structure protection measures (including extensive hoselays) are still in place along Rock Creek Road. Preventing fire growth toward homes and ranches continues to dictate operational priorities, and protection of life is always the primary objective. &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Goat Creek Fire: 8,305 acres, 95% contained.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;Rehabilitation of firelines and fuel break construction is progressing rapidly, and crews continue to mop up hot spots within the fire’s perimeter.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;Sliderock Fire: 901 acres, 95% contained. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;Crews continue to mop up hotspots and patrol the Sliderock Fire, resulting in increased containment.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Resources Threatened:&lt;/b&gt; Private property and structures in the Rock Creek, Upper Willow Creek, and Marshall Creek drainages remain threatened. Other resources threatened include fisheries in Rock Creek, grazing lands along the southern boundary of the Little Hogback Fire, Bonneville Power Administration powerline, and a communication site.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Evacuations:&lt;/b&gt; Three structures in the lower end of Capron Creek, near mile marker 33 on Rock Creek Road remain in Level Red- Evacuation Status. Many homes and communities are still potentially threatened by the fires within the Sapphire Complex, and as a result “Yellow” Pre-evacuation status for those areas also remain in effect. See Inciweb maps and evacuation alerts for details. &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Closures: &lt;/b&gt;The Rock Creek Road from I-90 south to Bitterroot Campground (MP 23.5) is OPEN. Due to fire traffic congestion and fire safety concerns, the Rock Creek Road will continue to be CLOSED from Bitterroot Campground, south to Cornish Gulch (FSR5027), and public traffic is NOT allowed. Upper Willow Creek Road is currently closed to the public. The Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest has reduced closure restrictions in the Black Pine ridge area, but maintains all area closures in the Upper Willow Creek, North Fork Lower Willow Creek, and Harvey Creek areas. The Bureau of Land Management has implemented an area closure in the Upper Willow Creek, Ram Mountain, and nearby areas. The Lolo and Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forests and the Bureau of Land Management have posted closure orders and maps under the &lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/closures/5364/"&gt;&lt;font color="#0000ff" face="Times New Roman"&gt;closures tab&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt; on Inciweb.&lt;u&gt; &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 6pt 0in; tab-stops: center 3.85in;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Weather: &lt;/b&gt; Although winds are predicted to lessen over the fire area today, relative humidities are expected to be very low and temperatures will approach the 90s, which could result in increased fire behavior. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 6pt 0in;"&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Fire Restrictions:&lt;/b&gt; Stage 1 Fire Restrictions are in place on the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest (Forest Service land east of Sandstone Ridge), with the additional modification to prohibit all campfires. Stage 2 Fire Restrictions are in place on BLM, private and state lands in Granite County, and the Lolo National Forest (Forest Service land west of Sandstone Ridge). &lt;b&gt;For information on fire restrictions, please visit &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="https://firerestrictions.us/"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font color="#0000ff"&gt;firerestrictions.us&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 6pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 6pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;u&gt; &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Sapphire Complex"></category></entry><entry><title>Meyers Fire Update September 2, 2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5397_39713.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-02T09:46:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-02T09:46:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-02:/montana_fires/5397_39713.html</id><summary type="html">Current Size:  30,486 acresResources Assigned: 322        Extreme fire conditions. No campfires allowed.      Status: The fire is burning in mixed conifer stands, primarily lodgepole pine, Douglas fir, and subalpine fir, with numerous standing dead trees. There are residences still at risk in the Moose Lake, Frog Pond, Springer Memorial Park and Bonanza areas.    Yesterday’s Activities: Fire activity was not as intense as on Thursday, but the periphery did continue to expand in several areas with some short-range spotting, torching and fire runs occurring. The eastern edge of the fire south of Moose Lake advanced beyond the Continental Divide Trail into Deer Lodge County, with some additional spotting ahead of the fire. The Moose Lake and East Fork Bitterroot communities remain in a pre-evacuation warning status. Along the fire’s west edge, ground crews made progress on control lines and burn outs, and continued structure protection measures in the Frog Pond and East Fork...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Meyers Fire Update September 2, 2017&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Meyers Fire Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 5 hrs. ago&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Current Size: &lt;/b&gt; 30,486 acres&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Resources Assigned&lt;/b&gt;: 322 &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p align="center" style="margin: 4pt 0in; text-align: center;"&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;font size="4"&gt;Extreme fire conditions. No campfires allowed.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="4"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Status:&lt;/b&gt; The fire is burning in mixed conifer stands, primarily lodgepole pine, Douglas fir, and subalpine fir, with numerous standing dead trees. There are residences still at risk in the Moose Lake, Frog Pond, Springer Memorial Park and Bonanza areas.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Yesterday’s Activities: &lt;/b&gt;Fire activity was not as intense as on Thursday, but the periphery did continue to expand in several areas with some short-range spotting, torching and fire runs occurring. The eastern edge of the fire south of Moose Lake advanced beyond the Continental Divide Trail into Deer Lodge County, with some additional spotting ahead of the fire. The Moose Lake and East Fork Bitterroot communities remain in a pre-evacuation warning status. Along the fire’s west edge, ground crews made progress on control lines and burn outs, and continued structure protection measures in the Frog Pond and East Fork Bitterroot communities. Hand crews and heavy equipment neared completion of a control line running east from Zeke’s Meadow, which itself was partially burned out today to increase holding capabilities along the north edge.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Current Resources: Three&lt;/b&gt; 20-person crews, &lt;b&gt;twenty&lt;/b&gt; engines, &lt;b&gt;four&lt;/b&gt; pieces of heavy equipment (dozers, masticators), &lt;b&gt;ten &lt;/b&gt;water tenders, and &lt;b&gt;three&lt;/b&gt; helicopters. Total personnel: &lt;b&gt;322&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Today’s Activities:&lt;/b&gt; Fire weather will intensify again today and tomorrow after yesterday’s slight reprieve. Spotting of ¼ to ½ mile may occur. Fire activity will increase, especially along the southwest, south, and southeast edges of the fire. Fire staff will work on building a machine and hand line ahead of the southwest edge of the fire to protect the East Fork Bitterroot structures. Structure protection efforts will continue here, at Frog Pond, Moose Lake, and other isolated buildings. Crews will continue burn out operations to reduce unburned fuels between the fire and the Frog Pond area. Because of the potential for increased fire activity along the east side, the Moose Lake community will be a main focus of attention today.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Evacuations: &lt;/b&gt;The Frog Pond area is under an evacuation order. Moose Lake residents are under an evacuation warning. Additionally, an evacuation warning is in effect on East Fork Rd from FS Rd 5778 to Little East Fork Rd (FS RD 724) on the Bitterroot National Forest.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Restrictions/Closures: &lt;/b&gt;Bitterroot National Forest emergency closure orders are in effect for upper areas of the East Fork Bitterroot River.&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;emergency closure orders are in effect around the fire area.&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;The closure of Forest Roads 893, 8684 and 8685 was rescinded at 6:00AM Friday, September 1, 2017. A temporary flight restriction (TFR) is in effect surrounding the Meyers Fire area. Granite County is under Stage 2 fire restrictions for private lands in the county. Amended Stage 1 fire restrictions have gone into effect today which prohibit &lt;b&gt;ALL&lt;/b&gt; campfires in southwestern Montana, including in fire rings and developed recreation areas. &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;For further information&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;follow the &lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/US-Forest-Service-Beaverhead-Deerlodge-National-Forest-1540138089548920/"&gt;&lt;font color="#0000ff" size="2"&gt;Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest Facebook&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; and &lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/DiscoverBitterrootNF"&gt;&lt;font color="#0000ff" size="2"&gt;Bitterroot National Forest Facebook&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; pages.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Meyers Fire"></category></entry></feed>