<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Montana Fires - Granite County</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/feeds/granite-county.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/</id><updated>2017-09-02T16:51:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Meyers Fire Closure September 2, 2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5397_39791.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-02T16:51:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-02T16:51:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-02:/montana_fires/5397_39791.html</id><summary type="html">The area closure on the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest around the Meyers Fire has been updated to include area in the Anaconda-Pintler Wilderness. This includes the Continental Divide Trail from Cutaway Pass to Mystic</summary><content type="html">The area closure on the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest around the Meyers Fire has been updated to include area in the Anaconda-Pintler Wilderness. This includes the Continental Divide Trail from Cutaway Pass to Mystic</content><category term="Meyers Fire"></category></entry><entry><title>Sapphire Complex Smoke Report 09.02.2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5364_39741.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-02T11:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-02T11:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-02:/montana_fires/5364_39741.html</id><summary type="html">Sapphire Complex Smoke Report</summary><content type="html">Sapphire Complex Smoke Report</content><category term="Sapphire Complex"></category></entry><entry><title>Sapphire Complex Daily Update 09.02.2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5364_39752.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-02T10:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-02T10:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-02:/montana_fires/5364_39752.html</id><summary type="html">Three fires comprise the Sapphire Complex: Little Hogback, Goat Creek, and Sliderock fires. Mike Almas’ Northern Rockies Type II Incident Management Team (IMT) is managing the incident. The fires are burning in steep, rocky terrain between the Rock Creek and Upper Willow Creek drainages.      Little Hogback Fire: 31,322 acres, 30% contained.      Friday, firefighters (aided by helicopter support) began performing a burnout operation starting on the ridge between Windlass and Sheep Gulch and continuing between Sheep Gulch and Capron Creek. These challenging burnout operations must be performed methodically, but weather has been cooperative and operations have been successful thus far. Such operations may be critical in securing firelines along the fire’s southwest perimeter and protecting structures in that area and will likely continue for one more day. Crews working along the fire’s eastern, western, and southern flanks further improved containment and firelines, mopping up...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sapphire Complex Daily Update 09.02.2017&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Sapphire Complex Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 5 hrs. ago&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- 
cached related article links at 14:31:35
cached id 2db96eb55560499397a27af9e72d3da9
--&gt;
&lt;div id="related_block"&gt;&lt;h4 id="related_head"&gt;Related Information&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul class="related_list"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/photos/MTLNF/2017-07-14-1837-Slide-Rock-Fire/related_files/pict20170802-121630-0.pdf" rel="new"&gt;Sapphire Complex Daily Update 09.02.2017 (pdf 117 kb)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 6pt 0in; tab-stops: center 3.85in;"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p style="margin: 6pt 0in; tab-stops: center 3.85in;"&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;Three fires comprise the Sapphire Complex: Little Hogback, Goat Creek, and Sliderock fires. Mike Almas’ Northern Rockies Type II Incident Management Team (IMT) is managing the incident. The fires are burning in steep, rocky terrain between the Rock Creek and Upper Willow Creek drainages. &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt; tab-stops: center 3.85in;"&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Little Hogback Fire: 31,322 acres, 30% contained.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt; tab-stops: center 3.85in;"&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;Friday, firefighters (aided by helicopter support) began performing a burnout operation starting on the ridge between Windlass and Sheep Gulch and continuing between Sheep Gulch and Capron Creek. These challenging burnout operations must be performed methodically, but weather has been cooperative and operations have been successful thus far. Such operations may be critical in securing firelines along the fire’s southwest perimeter and protecting structures in that area and will likely continue for one more day. Crews working along the fire’s eastern, western, and southern flanks further improved containment and firelines, mopping up hot spots, working inward from the fire perimeter. Structure protection measures (including extensive hoselays) are still in place along Rock Creek Road. Preventing fire growth toward homes and ranches continues to dictate operational priorities, and protection of life is always the primary objective. &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Goat Creek Fire: 8,305 acres, 95% contained.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;Rehabilitation of firelines and fuel break construction is progressing rapidly, and crews continue to mop up hot spots within the fire’s perimeter.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;Sliderock Fire: 901 acres, 95% contained. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;Crews continue to mop up hotspots and patrol the Sliderock Fire, resulting in increased containment.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Resources Threatened:&lt;/b&gt; Private property and structures in the Rock Creek, Upper Willow Creek, and Marshall Creek drainages remain threatened. Other resources threatened include fisheries in Rock Creek, grazing lands along the southern boundary of the Little Hogback Fire, Bonneville Power Administration powerline, and a communication site.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Evacuations:&lt;/b&gt; Three structures in the lower end of Capron Creek, near mile marker 33 on Rock Creek Road remain in Level Red- Evacuation Status. Many homes and communities are still potentially threatened by the fires within the Sapphire Complex, and as a result “Yellow” Pre-evacuation status for those areas also remain in effect. See Inciweb maps and evacuation alerts for details. &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Closures: &lt;/b&gt;The Rock Creek Road from I-90 south to Bitterroot Campground (MP 23.5) is OPEN. Due to fire traffic congestion and fire safety concerns, the Rock Creek Road will continue to be CLOSED from Bitterroot Campground, south to Cornish Gulch (FSR5027), and public traffic is NOT allowed. Upper Willow Creek Road is currently closed to the public. The Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest has reduced closure restrictions in the Black Pine ridge area, but maintains all area closures in the Upper Willow Creek, North Fork Lower Willow Creek, and Harvey Creek areas. The Bureau of Land Management has implemented an area closure in the Upper Willow Creek, Ram Mountain, and nearby areas. The Lolo and Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forests and the Bureau of Land Management have posted closure orders and maps under the &lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/closures/5364/"&gt;&lt;font color="#0000ff" face="Times New Roman"&gt;closures tab&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt; on Inciweb.&lt;u&gt; &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 6pt 0in; tab-stops: center 3.85in;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Weather: &lt;/b&gt; Although winds are predicted to lessen over the fire area today, relative humidities are expected to be very low and temperatures will approach the 90s, which could result in increased fire behavior. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 6pt 0in;"&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Fire Restrictions:&lt;/b&gt; Stage 1 Fire Restrictions are in place on the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest (Forest Service land east of Sandstone Ridge), with the additional modification to prohibit all campfires. Stage 2 Fire Restrictions are in place on BLM, private and state lands in Granite County, and the Lolo National Forest (Forest Service land west of Sandstone Ridge). &lt;b&gt;For information on fire restrictions, please visit &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="https://firerestrictions.us/"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font color="#0000ff"&gt;firerestrictions.us&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 6pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 6pt 0in;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;u&gt; &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Sapphire Complex"></category></entry><entry><title>Meyers Fire Update September 2, 2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5397_39713.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-02T09:46:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-02T09:46:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-02:/montana_fires/5397_39713.html</id><summary type="html">Current Size:  30,486 acresResources Assigned: 322        Extreme fire conditions. No campfires allowed.      Status: The fire is burning in mixed conifer stands, primarily lodgepole pine, Douglas fir, and subalpine fir, with numerous standing dead trees. There are residences still at risk in the Moose Lake, Frog Pond, Springer Memorial Park and Bonanza areas.    Yesterday’s Activities: Fire activity was not as intense as on Thursday, but the periphery did continue to expand in several areas with some short-range spotting, torching and fire runs occurring. The eastern edge of the fire south of Moose Lake advanced beyond the Continental Divide Trail into Deer Lodge County, with some additional spotting ahead of the fire. The Moose Lake and East Fork Bitterroot communities remain in a pre-evacuation warning status. Along the fire’s west edge, ground crews made progress on control lines and burn outs, and continued structure protection measures in the Frog Pond and East Fork...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Meyers Fire Update September 2, 2017&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Meyers Fire Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 5 hrs. ago&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Current Size: &lt;/b&gt; 30,486 acres&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Resources Assigned&lt;/b&gt;: 322 &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p align="center" style="margin: 4pt 0in; text-align: center;"&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;font size="4"&gt;Extreme fire conditions. No campfires allowed.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="4"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Status:&lt;/b&gt; The fire is burning in mixed conifer stands, primarily lodgepole pine, Douglas fir, and subalpine fir, with numerous standing dead trees. There are residences still at risk in the Moose Lake, Frog Pond, Springer Memorial Park and Bonanza areas.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Yesterday’s Activities: &lt;/b&gt;Fire activity was not as intense as on Thursday, but the periphery did continue to expand in several areas with some short-range spotting, torching and fire runs occurring. The eastern edge of the fire south of Moose Lake advanced beyond the Continental Divide Trail into Deer Lodge County, with some additional spotting ahead of the fire. The Moose Lake and East Fork Bitterroot communities remain in a pre-evacuation warning status. Along the fire’s west edge, ground crews made progress on control lines and burn outs, and continued structure protection measures in the Frog Pond and East Fork Bitterroot communities. Hand crews and heavy equipment neared completion of a control line running east from Zeke’s Meadow, which itself was partially burned out today to increase holding capabilities along the north edge.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Current Resources: Three&lt;/b&gt; 20-person crews, &lt;b&gt;twenty&lt;/b&gt; engines, &lt;b&gt;four&lt;/b&gt; pieces of heavy equipment (dozers, masticators), &lt;b&gt;ten &lt;/b&gt;water tenders, and &lt;b&gt;three&lt;/b&gt; helicopters. Total personnel: &lt;b&gt;322&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Today’s Activities:&lt;/b&gt; Fire weather will intensify again today and tomorrow after yesterday’s slight reprieve. Spotting of ¼ to ½ mile may occur. Fire activity will increase, especially along the southwest, south, and southeast edges of the fire. Fire staff will work on building a machine and hand line ahead of the southwest edge of the fire to protect the East Fork Bitterroot structures. Structure protection efforts will continue here, at Frog Pond, Moose Lake, and other isolated buildings. Crews will continue burn out operations to reduce unburned fuels between the fire and the Frog Pond area. Because of the potential for increased fire activity along the east side, the Moose Lake community will be a main focus of attention today.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Evacuations: &lt;/b&gt;The Frog Pond area is under an evacuation order. Moose Lake residents are under an evacuation warning. Additionally, an evacuation warning is in effect on East Fork Rd from FS Rd 5778 to Little East Fork Rd (FS RD 724) on the Bitterroot National Forest.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Restrictions/Closures: &lt;/b&gt;Bitterroot National Forest emergency closure orders are in effect for upper areas of the East Fork Bitterroot River.&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;emergency closure orders are in effect around the fire area.&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;The closure of Forest Roads 893, 8684 and 8685 was rescinded at 6:00AM Friday, September 1, 2017. A temporary flight restriction (TFR) is in effect surrounding the Meyers Fire area. Granite County is under Stage 2 fire restrictions for private lands in the county. Amended Stage 1 fire restrictions have gone into effect today which prohibit &lt;b&gt;ALL&lt;/b&gt; campfires in southwestern Montana, including in fire rings and developed recreation areas. &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;For further information&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;follow the &lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/US-Forest-Service-Beaverhead-Deerlodge-National-Forest-1540138089548920/"&gt;&lt;font color="#0000ff" size="2"&gt;Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest Facebook&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; and &lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/DiscoverBitterrootNF"&gt;&lt;font color="#0000ff" size="2"&gt;Bitterroot National Forest Facebook&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; pages.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Meyers Fire"></category></entry></feed>