<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Montana Fires - Hill County</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/feeds/hill-county.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/</id><updated>2017-09-03T10:36:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Fire Update 9-3-17</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5582_39832.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-03T10:36:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-03T10:36:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-03:/montana_fires/5582_39832.html</id><summary type="html">The East Fork Fire is burning on private lands in Blaine County, Hill County and on the Rocky Boy Reservation, south of Harve, Montana. A small piece of Bureau of Land Management land is also within the fire area. Today, as a cold front moves through the area, a Red Flag Warning is in effect for dry fuels and strong, gusty winds that will begin Sunday morning, and last through Monday evening. A Red Flag Warning notes fire conditions that will likely increase fire activity. This will bring conditions over the fire area that are similar to last week, when the fire quickly grew to over 21,000 acres. The East Fork Fire is currently confined by Sucker Creek to the north, Clear Creek on the east, the West Fork of Clear Creek on the south, and Beaver Creek on the west. The objective for today is to keep the fire within those boundaries in order to protect values at risk such as grazing lands and timber values. It will be a challenge to firefighters today and tomorrow with the Red Flag...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fire Update 9-3-17&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; East Fork Fire Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 24 min. ago&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align="left" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"&gt;Start Date: 8-27-17&lt;br/&gt;Cause: Under Investigation&lt;br/&gt;Size:21,500 acres&lt;br/&gt;Containment: 10%&lt;br/&gt;Helicopters: 3&lt;br/&gt;Engines: 15&lt;br/&gt;Crews: 2&lt;br/&gt;Total Personnel: 170&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align="left" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;The East Fork Fire is burning on private lands in Blaine County, Hill County and on the Rocky Boy Reservation, south of Harve, Montana. A small piece of Bureau of Land Management land is also within the fire area.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align="left" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;Today, as a cold front moves through the area, a Red Flag Warning is in effect for dry fuels and strong, gusty winds that will begin Sunday morning, and last through Monday evening. A Red Flag Warning notes fire conditions that will likely increase fire activity. This will bring conditions over the fire area that are similar to last week, when the fire quickly grew to over 21,000 acres.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align="left" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;The East Fork Fire is currently confined by Sucker Creek to the north, Clear Creek on the east, the West Fork of Clear Creek on the south, and Beaver Creek on the west. The objective for today is to keep the fire within those boundaries in order to protect values at risk such as grazing lands and timber values. It will be a challenge to firefighters today and tomorrow with the Red Flag Warning conditions that will bring gusty winds up to 22 mph this afternoon, and up to 40 mph by early evening. The focus for today is to secure the fire on the east and south sides that still have heat in them.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align="left" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;Great Basin Incident Management Team #2 (Kim Martin, IC) is in place and assumed command of the fire this morning. The team is made up of city, county, state and federal firefighters and managers that bring additional resources to the firefighting effort to assist local firefighters.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align="left" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align="left" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align="left" style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt; text-align: center; line-height: normal;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;p align="left" style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt; text-align: center; line-height: normal;"&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;p align="left" style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt; text-align: center; line-height: normal;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;p align="left" style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt; text-align: center; line-height: normal;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align="center" style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt; text-align: center; line-height: normal;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="East Fork Fire"></category></entry><entry><title>Red Flag Warning in Effect for Dry fuels and Strong Gusty Winds</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5582_39816.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-03T08:44:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-03T08:44:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-03:/montana_fires/5582_39816.html</id><summary type="html">A Red Flag Warning for dry fuels and strong gusty winds is in effect beginning Sunday morning, through Monday Evening. A Red Flag Warning is a condition where fire activity is expected to increase. The fire triangle consist of Fuels, Weather and Terrain - when these parts of the triangle align is a negative a manner, fire activity increases. In this case, the forecasted weather is for strong gusty winds and the fuels in the fire area are extremely dry. Add the rolling and steep terrain that is in the area of the fire, and elements are aligned to promote active fire</summary><content type="html">A Red Flag Warning for dry fuels and strong gusty winds is in effect beginning Sunday morning, through Monday Evening. A Red Flag Warning is a condition where fire activity is expected to increase. The fire triangle consist of Fuels, Weather and Terrain - when these parts of the triangle align is a negative a manner, fire activity increases. In this case, the forecasted weather is for strong gusty winds and the fuels in the fire area are extremely dry. Add the rolling and steep terrain that is in the area of the fire, and elements are aligned to promote active fire</content><category term="East Fork Fire"></category></entry></feed>