<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Montana Fires - Hill County</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/feeds/hill-county.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/</id><updated>2017-09-06T10:27:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Fire Update 9-6-17</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5582_40173.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-06T10:27:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-06T10:27:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-06:/montana_fires/5582_40173.html</id><summary type="html">The Blaine County public meeting will be at the Bear Paw School on Wednesday, September 6, at 4 p.m.  Yesterday: Firefighters were successful in locating and extinguishing hotspots in the Clear Creek and southern Little Box Elder Creek areas. The fire line in these areas are now contained. While firefighters continue to make good progress, heat still remains in the heavy fuels of the Little Box Elder Canyon and the timber stringers along the canyon. Helicopter water drops were used to help extinguish hot spots in areas where heavy fuels are still smoldering. The remaining portions of the fire perimeter are now contained and are being patrolled and improved. Firefighters continued working to insure hotspots in Mooney Coulee have been extinguished. Suppression repair continued along the fire line where containment has been achieved. Night shift patrolled the fire line to insure the fire stayed within containment lines.   Actions Planned: Firefighters will continue working in Little Box...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fire Update 9-6-17&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; East Fork Fire Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 33 min. ago&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p align="center" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="3"&gt;The Blaine County public meeting will be at the Bear Paw School on&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="3"&gt; Wednesday, September 6, at 4 p.m.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="3"&gt;Yesterday&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;: Firefighters were successful in locating and extinguishing hotspots in the Clear Creek and southern Little Box Elder Creek areas. The fire line in these areas are now contained. While firefighters continue to make good progress, heat still remains in the heavy fuels of the Little Box Elder Canyon and the timber stringers along the canyon. Helicopter water drops were used to help extinguish hot spots in areas where heavy fuels are still smoldering. The remaining portions of the fire perimeter are now contained and are being patrolled and improved. Firefighters continued working to insure hotspots in Mooney Coulee have been extinguished. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="3"&gt;Suppression repair continued along the fire line where containment has been achieved. Night shift patrolled the fire line to insure the fire stayed within containment lines. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="3"&gt;Actions Planned:&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="3"&gt;Firefighters will continue working in Little Box Elder Canyon where heavy fuels continue to hold heat.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="3"&gt;Crews are nearing completion of fireline on the fire’s southwestern corner and Miner’s Gulch areas. In Mooney Coulee crews will continue mopping up near structures as needed. The remaining portions of the fire perimeter are contained and will be patrolled and improved. Suppression repair will continue along the fire line where containment has been achieved. Even as fire containment is increasing, smoke may be seen from unburned pockets of fuels burning in the interior of the fire. These unburned pockets are no threat to the fire perimeter.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Closures: &lt;/b&gt;The Hill County Sheriff’s Department has lifted the evacuation order on Sucker Creek Road and Taylor Roads allowing property owners to return to these areas. Sucker Creek Road has been opened to local residents; the public is urged to stay out of the area due to heavy equipment and emergency personnel still working in the area. Highway 234 will remain closed from Taylor Road south. Beaver Creek Park and all side roads within the park remain closed to recreation.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="3"&gt;Background:&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt; The East Fork Fire started on August 27, 2017; the cause is under investigation. It is on private lands in Blaine County, Hill County and on the Rocky Boy Reservation, south of Havre, Montana. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="3"&gt;The state of Montana also has land within the fire area as well as a small piece of Bureau of Land Management land.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="3"&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Weather: &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="3"&gt;Following the predicted trend for the week, today will continue to be dry and warm. Temperatures are expected to be in the low 80s with winds from the ESE at 8 to 12 mph gusting to 15 to 20 mph in the afternoon. Relative humidity is expected to drop to 10% to 15%.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="East Fork Fire"></category></entry><entry><title>Fire Update 9-5-17</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5582_40060.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-05T10:43:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-05T10:43:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-05:/montana_fires/5582_40060.html</id><summary type="html">The Hill County Sheriff’s Department has lifted the evacuation order on Sucker Creek Road and Taylor Road allowing property owners to return to the area. Sucker Creek Road has been opened to local residents; the public is urged to stay out of the area due to heavy equipment and emergency personnel still working in the area. Highway 234 will remain closed from Taylor Road south. Beaver Creek Park and all side roads within the park remain closed to recreation.  A public meeting will be held at the Chippewa Cree Vo-Tech Center on Tuesday, September 5th at 4 p.m.   The Blaine County public meeting will be at the Bear Paw School on  Wednesday, September 6, at 4 p.m.   Yesterday: Firefighters patrolled the northwest and southeast edges of the fire to verify no threats to the line existed and those areas are now contained. Crews located and suppressed smoldering, heavy fuels in the Clear Creek area and continued mop up in Little Box Elder and Mooney Creek around structures. Helicopter...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fire Update 9-5-17&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; East Fork Fire Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 17 min. ago&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="3"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt; text-align: justify;"&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;The Hill County Sheriff’s Department has lifted the evacuation order on Sucker Creek Road and Taylor Road allowing property owners to return to the area. Sucker Creek Road has been opened to local residents; the public is urged to stay out of the area due to heavy equipment and emergency personnel still working in the area. Highway 234 will remain closed from Taylor Road south. Beaver Creek Park and all side roads within the park remain closed to recreation. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p align="center" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt; text-align: center;"&gt; &lt;b&gt;A public meeting will be held at the Chippewa Cree Vo-Tech Center on &lt;br/&gt; Tuesday, September 5th at 4 p.m.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;The Blaine County public meeting will be at the Bear Paw School on &lt;br/&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt; Wednesday, September 6, at 4 &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;p.m.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;Yesterday:&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt; Firefighters patrolled the northwest and southeast edges of the fire to verify no threats to the line existed and those areas are now contained. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;Crews located and suppressed smoldering, heavy fuels in the Clear Creek area and continued mop up in Little Box Elder and Mooney Creek around structures. Helicopter water drops were used to suppress hotspots in Miners Gulch. In areas that are fully contained, suppression repair was started.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;Night shift engines continued to patrol the fire line to insure the lines held. &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;Actions Planned:&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;Today, firefighters will focus efforts on the west side of Little Box Elder Creek, Miner’s Gulch, and Clear Creek areas. The remaining portions of the fire perimeter are contained and will be in patrol status. Even as fire containment is increasing, smoke may be seen from unburned pockets of fuels burning in the interior of the fire. These unburned pockets are no threat to the fire perimeter. Night shift will continue to patrol the fire line to insure no threats exist. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;Suppression repair will continue along the fire line where containment has been achieved. &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;Background:&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt; The East Fork Fire started on August 27, 2017, the cause is under investigation. It is on private lands in Blaine County, Hill County and on the Rocky Boy Reservation, south of Havre, Montana. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;A small piece of Bureau of Land Management land is also within the fire area. &lt;br/&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Weather: &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;Today, winds are expected to be light and out of the ESE at 5 to 10 mph, occasionally gusting to 15 to 20 mph. Relative humidity will drop below 20%. Temperatures will be in the upper 70s to &lt;br/&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt; low 80s. The predicted trend for the week is for warming temperatures and lower humidity.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt; text-align: justify;"&gt; &lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="East Fork Fire"></category></entry><entry><title>Fire Update 9-4-17</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5582_39966.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-04T11:05:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-04T11:05:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-04:/montana_fires/5582_39966.html</id><summary type="html">A public meeting for Hill County has been set for 4 p.m. on  Monday, September 4th at the Havre High School.   Background: The East Fork Fire started on August 27, 2017, the cause is under investigation. It is on private lands in Blaine County, Hill County and on the Rocky Boy Reservation, south of Havre, Montana. A small piece of Bureau of Land Management land is also within the fire area. Volunteer, county, state and federal firefighters from Blaine and Hill Counties did an outstanding job of coming together to conduct an aggressive initial attach on this fire. As firefighting moves into the next phases, many of these firefighters will continue to make significant contributions to the suppression of the fire. Yesterday: Yesterday’s predicted the cold front moved through the area, however winds remained light. Fire behavior was minimal allowing firefighters to identify and extinguish areas of heat. Mop up continued along the fire edge and where secured, the lines were declared...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fire Update 9-4-17&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; East Fork Fire Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 25 min. ago&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p align="left" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="3"&gt;A public meeting for Hill County has been set for 4 p.m. on &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="3"&gt; Monday, September 4&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="2"&gt;th&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="3"&gt; at the Havre High School.&lt;br style="mso-special-character: line-break;"/&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="3"&gt; &lt;br style="mso-special-character: line-break;"/&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="3"&gt;Background:&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt; The East Fork Fire started on August 27, 2017, the cause is under investigation. It is on private lands in Blaine County, Hill County and on the Rocky Boy Reservation, south of Havre, Montana. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="3"&gt;A small piece of Bureau of Land Management land is also within the fire area. Volunteer, county, state and federal firefighters from Blaine and Hill Counties did an outstanding job of coming together to conduct an aggressive initial attach on this fire. As firefighting moves into the next phases, many of these firefighters will continue to make significant contributions to the suppression of the fire.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="3"&gt;Yesterday:&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt; Yesterday’s predicted the cold front moved through the area, however winds remained light. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="3"&gt;Fire behavior was minimal allowing firefighters to identify and extinguish areas of heat. Mop up continued along the fire edge and where secured, the lines were declared contained.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="3"&gt;Actions Planned:&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="3"&gt;Today’s focus remains securing the fire the perimeter, and identifying and extinguishing any areas of heat. Patrol, mop up and suppression rehabilitation will begin along the fire’s perimeter as conditions and staffing allow. In Hill County the fire is roughly bordered by Beaver Creek on the west and Sucker Creek Road on the north. In Blaine County the fire is west of the Clear Creek Road. To the South the fire is roughly bordered by the west of fork of Clear Creek. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Evacuations and Closures: &lt;/b&gt;Beaver Creek Road is open from 5th Avenue through to Taylor Road and to Rocky Boy Agency. Beaver Creek Park is closed to recreation, and the Hill County Sheriff’s Department is asking the public to stay out of the area for firefighter safety- the side roads within the park are still closed to the public. Sucker Creek Road is closed between Beaver Creek and Clear Creek&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Calibri" size="3"&gt;.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="3"&gt;Announcements:&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt; A public meeting for Hill County has been set for 4 p.m. on Monday, September 4&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;th&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="3"&gt; at the Havre High School auditorium. Upcoming public meetings will be announced soon for Blaine County and the Chippewa Cree Tribe; stay tuned for further information.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="3"&gt;The meetings will be facilitated by the Incident Management Team to help the local jurisdiction share information with area residents. Members of the Incident Team will give an update on the current fire situation and expected suppression activities over the next few days. County representatives will be on hand to talk about the fire from their perspective and about plans for the future. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt; line-height: normal;"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="3"&gt;Weather: &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="3"&gt;A Red Flag Warning remains in effect for today. However, winds will be expected to moderate and be out of the north at 10 to 15 mph, occasionally gusting to 20 mph. Temperatures will be in the high 60’s to low 70s.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="East Fork Fire"></category></entry><entry><title>East Fork Fire Closures</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5582_39927.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-03T21:57:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-03T21:57:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-03:/montana_fires/5582_39927.html</id><summary type="html">Beaver Creek Road is open from 5th Avenue through to Taylor Road and to Rocky Boy Agency.   Beaver Creek Park is closed to recreation, and the Hill County Sheriff’s Department is asking the public to stay out of the area for firefighter safety- the side roads within the park are still closed to the public.   Sucker Creek Road is closed between Beaver Creek and Clear</summary><content type="html">Beaver Creek Road is open from 5th Avenue through to Taylor Road and to Rocky Boy Agency.   Beaver Creek Park is closed to recreation, and the Hill County Sheriff’s Department is asking the public to stay out of the area for firefighter safety- the side roads within the park are still closed to the public.   Sucker Creek Road is closed between Beaver Creek and Clear</content><category term="East Fork Fire"></category></entry><entry><title>Public Meetings</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5582_39925.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-03T21:24:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-03T21:24:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-03:/montana_fires/5582_39925.html</id><summary type="html">A public meeting for Hill County has been set for 4p.m. on Monday, September 4th at the Havre High School. Public meetings will be announced soon for Blaine County and the Chipewwa Cree Tribe - stay tuned for that information.These meeting are facilitated by the Incident Management Team to help the local jurisdiction share information with area residents. Members of the Incident Management Team will give an update on the current situation of the fire, and expected suppression activities over the next few days. County representatives will be on hand to talk about the fire from their perspectives and about plans for the</summary><content type="html">A public meeting for Hill County has been set for 4p.m. on Monday, September 4th at the Havre High School. Public meetings will be announced soon for Blaine County and the Chipewwa Cree Tribe - stay tuned for that information.These meeting are facilitated by the Incident Management Team to help the local jurisdiction share information with area residents. Members of the Incident Management Team will give an update on the current situation of the fire, and expected suppression activities over the next few days. County representatives will be on hand to talk about the fire from their perspectives and about plans for the</content><category term="East Fork Fire"></category></entry><entry><title>Fire Update 9-3-17</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5582_39832.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-03T10:36:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-03T10:36:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-03:/montana_fires/5582_39832.html</id><summary type="html">The East Fork Fire is burning on private lands in Blaine County, Hill County and on the Rocky Boy Reservation, south of Harve, Montana. A small piece of Bureau of Land Management land is also within the fire area. Today, as a cold front moves through the area, a Red Flag Warning is in effect for dry fuels and strong, gusty winds that will begin Sunday morning, and last through Monday evening. A Red Flag Warning notes fire conditions that will likely increase fire activity. This will bring conditions over the fire area that are similar to last week, when the fire quickly grew to over 21,000 acres. The East Fork Fire is currently confined by Sucker Creek to the north, Clear Creek on the east, the West Fork of Clear Creek on the south, and Beaver Creek on the west. The objective for today is to keep the fire within those boundaries in order to protect values at risk such as grazing lands and timber values. It will be a challenge to firefighters today and tomorrow with the Red Flag...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fire Update 9-3-17&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; East Fork Fire Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 24 min. ago&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align="left" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"&gt;Start Date: 8-27-17&lt;br/&gt;Cause: Under Investigation&lt;br/&gt;Size:21,500 acres&lt;br/&gt;Containment: 10%&lt;br/&gt;Helicopters: 3&lt;br/&gt;Engines: 15&lt;br/&gt;Crews: 2&lt;br/&gt;Total Personnel: 170&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align="left" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;The East Fork Fire is burning on private lands in Blaine County, Hill County and on the Rocky Boy Reservation, south of Harve, Montana. A small piece of Bureau of Land Management land is also within the fire area.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align="left" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;Today, as a cold front moves through the area, a Red Flag Warning is in effect for dry fuels and strong, gusty winds that will begin Sunday morning, and last through Monday evening. A Red Flag Warning notes fire conditions that will likely increase fire activity. This will bring conditions over the fire area that are similar to last week, when the fire quickly grew to over 21,000 acres.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align="left" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;The East Fork Fire is currently confined by Sucker Creek to the north, Clear Creek on the east, the West Fork of Clear Creek on the south, and Beaver Creek on the west. The objective for today is to keep the fire within those boundaries in order to protect values at risk such as grazing lands and timber values. It will be a challenge to firefighters today and tomorrow with the Red Flag Warning conditions that will bring gusty winds up to 22 mph this afternoon, and up to 40 mph by early evening. The focus for today is to secure the fire on the east and south sides that still have heat in them.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align="left" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;Great Basin Incident Management Team #2 (Kim Martin, IC) is in place and assumed command of the fire this morning. The team is made up of city, county, state and federal firefighters and managers that bring additional resources to the firefighting effort to assist local firefighters.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align="left" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align="left" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align="left" style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt; text-align: center; line-height: normal;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt;&lt;p align="left" style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt; text-align: center; line-height: normal;"&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;p align="left" style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt; text-align: center; line-height: normal;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;p align="left" style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt; text-align: center; line-height: normal;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align="center" style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt; text-align: center; line-height: normal;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="East Fork Fire"></category></entry><entry><title>Red Flag Warning in Effect for Dry fuels and Strong Gusty Winds</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5582_39816.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-03T08:44:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-03T08:44:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-03:/montana_fires/5582_39816.html</id><summary type="html">A Red Flag Warning for dry fuels and strong gusty winds is in effect beginning Sunday morning, through Monday Evening. A Red Flag Warning is a condition where fire activity is expected to increase. The fire triangle consist of Fuels, Weather and Terrain - when these parts of the triangle align is a negative a manner, fire activity increases. In this case, the forecasted weather is for strong gusty winds and the fuels in the fire area are extremely dry. Add the rolling and steep terrain that is in the area of the fire, and elements are aligned to promote active fire</summary><content type="html">A Red Flag Warning for dry fuels and strong gusty winds is in effect beginning Sunday morning, through Monday Evening. A Red Flag Warning is a condition where fire activity is expected to increase. The fire triangle consist of Fuels, Weather and Terrain - when these parts of the triangle align is a negative a manner, fire activity increases. In this case, the forecasted weather is for strong gusty winds and the fuels in the fire area are extremely dry. Add the rolling and steep terrain that is in the area of the fire, and elements are aligned to promote active fire</content><category term="East Fork Fire"></category></entry></feed>