<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Montana Fires - Lake County</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/feeds/lake-county.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/</id><updated>2017-09-03T10:12:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Red Flag Warning In effect Until 9PM Tonight</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5507_39824.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-03T10:12:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-03T10:12:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-03:/montana_fires/5507_39824.html</id><summary type="html">Confederated Salish &amp; Kootenai Division of Fire News Release  For Immediate Release September 3, 2017Red Flag Warning In Effect Until 9PM Tonight POLSON, Mont. – The Red Flag Warning issued by the National Weather Service remains a big concern for firefighters over Labor Day. The public’s continued cooperation with the Stage 2 fire restrictions is a critical step in keeping everyone safe. High temperatures, combined with low relative humidity and wind, will test the work firefighters have recently completed on the Blue Bay Fire and other fires burning on the Flathead Reservation. On the Blue Bay Fire, containment lines have been tested during the past several days of hot, windy conditions. Despite some small spot fires detected in Okie Draw, acreage remains constant at 490 acres with 80% containment. Firefighters continue to work hard extinguishing heat sources on the fire. One firefighter experiencing heat related illness was transported to the hospital Saturday evening. To...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Red Flag Warning In effect Until 9PM Tonight&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Blue Bay Fire Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 18 min. ago&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Confederated Salish &amp;amp; Kootenai Division of Fire News Release &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/b&gt; For Immediate Release September 3, 2017&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Red Flag Warning In Effect Until 9PM Tonight&lt;br/&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;POLSON, Mont. – The Red Flag Warning issued by the National Weather Service remains a big concern for firefighters over Labor Day. The public’s continued cooperation with the Stage 2 fire restrictions is a critical step in keeping everyone safe. High temperatures, combined with low relative humidity and wind, will test the work firefighters have recently completed on the Blue Bay Fire and other fires burning on the Flathead Reservation.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;On the Blue Bay Fire, containment lines have been tested during the past several days of hot, windy conditions. Despite some small spot fires detected in Okie Draw, acreage remains constant at 490 acres with 80% containment. Firefighters continue to work hard extinguishing heat sources on the fire. One firefighter experiencing heat related illness was transported to the hospital Saturday evening. To reduce the risk to firefighters and public, the B-2000 and B-2200 Roads remain closed.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;The Liberty Fire southeast of Arlee, MT is roughly 16,788 acres and is 22% contained. Saturday evening, several wind shifts and strong wind gusts threw multiple spot fires across containment lines near the convergence of the South Fork of the Jocko River and Liberty Creek. 16 firefighters became entrapped by flame, 13 were able to escape to a safety zone while 3 began to deploy fire shelters. Another wind shift provided the 3 with the opportunity to escape to safety. All firefighters are safe, and there were no injuries reported. The South Fork Primitive Area is currently closed, and additional closures are currently in effect; please visit https://inciweb.nwcg.gov for more information.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;The 310-acre Black Fire is 0% contained and fire activity has picked up in recent days due to high temperatures, wind and low relative humidities. It is burning in the Mission Mountains Tribal Wilderness 3 miles north of Black Lake. Firefighters plan to use aircraft today to drop water in an effort to slow the fire’s growth to the north and east. The Confederated Salish &amp;amp; Kootenai Division of Fire is coordinating firefighting efforts with the Montana DNRC – Southwest Land Office and Lolo National Forest. The Division of Fire asks the public to stay out of the North Fork trailhead area (Lost Sheep, Gray Wolf, and Buck Lake) due to the fire danger. Any questions, call the Division of Fire, 406-676-2550.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;The 620-acre Upper Midway Fire near Ravalli is contained, but not yet controlled. Firefighters will continue to extinguish remaining hot spots and monitor the area for flare ups and spot fires.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;Yesterday the 62 acre Cottonwood Fire began on private property in the Camas area. It is contained, however firefighters will continue to monitor it until it is deemed controlled.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Blue Bay Fire"></category></entry><entry><title>Fire Safety Through Labor Day Weekend</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5507_39725.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-02T10:44:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-02T10:44:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-02:/montana_fires/5507_39725.html</id><summary type="html">Confederated Salish &amp; Kootenai Division of Fire News Release For Immediate Release  September 2, 2017Fire Safety Through Labor Day WeekendPOLSON, Mont. – The safety of firefighters and the public remains the number one priority as we enter Labor Day weekend under the most extreme fire conditions of recent years. The public’s continued cooperation with the Stage 2 fire restrictions is a critical step in keeping everyone safe. Weather remains a big concern for firefighters as the Labor Day weekend approaches. High temperatures, combined with low relative humidity and wind, will test the work firefighters have recently completed on the Blue Bay Fire and other fires burning on the Flathead Reservation.At the Blue Bay Fire, containment lines held well during the past several days of hot, windy conditions. Acreage remains at 490 acres and containment is 80 percent. Firefighters are addressing any hot spots they encounter while improving firelines. At this time, no additional community...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fire Safety Through Labor Day Weekend&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Blue Bay Fire Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 4 hrs. ago&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Confederated Salish &amp;amp; Kootenai Division of Fire News Release &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;For Immediate Release&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt; September 2, 2017&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Fire Safety Through Labor Day Weekend&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;POLSON, Mont. – The safety of firefighters and the public remains the number one priority as we enter Labor Day weekend under the most extreme fire conditions of recent years. The public’s continued cooperation with the Stage 2 fire restrictions is a critical step in keeping everyone safe. Weather remains a big concern for firefighters as the Labor Day weekend approaches. High temperatures, combined with low relative humidity and wind, will test the work firefighters have recently completed on the Blue Bay Fire and other fires burning on the Flathead Reservation.&lt;br/&gt;At the Blue Bay Fire, containment lines held well during the past several days of hot, windy conditions. Acreage remains at 490 acres and containment is 80 percent. Firefighters are addressing any hot spots they encounter while improving firelines. At this time, no additional community meetings are planned unless significant fire activity occurs. To reduce the risk to firefighters and public, the B-2000 and B-2200 Roads remain closed.&lt;br/&gt;The Liberty Fire which is southeast of Arlee, is roughly 15,545 acres and is 22% contained. The Liberty Fire will transition from being managed as a single fire by Rohrer’s Great Basin Type 2 Team, to being managed as a branch of the Rice Ridge Fire by Poncin’s Type 1 Team. The branch will be directly supervised by the Confederated Salish &amp;amp; Kootenai Division of Fire. The South Fork Primitive Area is currently closed, and additional closures are currently in effect; please visit https://inciweb.nwcg.gov for more information.&lt;br/&gt;Fire behavior on the 310-acre Black Fire has picked up in recent days due to high temperatures, wind and low relative humidities. This lightning-caused fire is burning in the Mission Mountains Tribal Wilderness 3 miles north of Black Lake. The fire is approximately 5 miles north of the Liberty Fire, and roughly 12 miles west of the Rice Ridge Fire near Seeley Lake. Firefighters plan to use aircraft today to drop water and retardant in an effort to slow the fire’s growth to the north and east. The Confederated Salish &amp;amp; Kootenai Division of Fire is coordinating firefighting efforts with the Montana DNRC – Southwest Land Office and Lolo National Forest.&lt;br/&gt;The 620-acre Upper Midway Fire near Ravalli is 80 percent contained. Firefighters will continue to secure the fire edge, extinguish remaining hot spots and monitor the area for flare ups and spot fires during the day and night shifts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Blue Bay Fire"></category></entry><entry><title>Hot, Dry Conditions to Persist Through Weekend</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5507_39650.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-01T12:52:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-01T12:52:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-01:/montana_fires/5507_39650.html</id><summary type="html">Confederated Salish &amp; Kootenai Division of Fire News Release For Immediate Release September 1, 2017 POLSON, Mont. – Weather remains a big concern for firefighters as the Labor Day weekend approaches. Temperatures 10 to 20 degrees above normal, together with low relative humidity and wind, will test the work firefighters have recently completed on the Blue Bay Fire and other fires burning on the Flathead Reservation.  At the Blue Bay Fire, containment lines held well during the past several days of hot, windy conditions. Acreage remains at 490 acres and containment is 80 percent. Smoldering and creeping continue to be the predominant fire behavior. Firefighters are addressing any hot spots they encounter while improving firelines. At this time, no additional community meetings are planned unless significant fire activity occurs.  Strong winds at the 630-acre Upper Midway Fire near Ravalli pushed flames across containment lines at one location yesterday, but helicopters assisted...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Hot, Dry Conditions to Persist Through Weekend&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Blue Bay Fire Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 1 day ago&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Calibri" size="3"&gt;Confederated Salish &amp;amp; Kootenai Division of Fire News Release&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Calibri" size="3"&gt;For Immediate Release&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Calibri" size="3"&gt;September 1, 2017&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p align="left" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font face="Calibri"&gt;POLSON, Mont. – Weather remains a big concern for firefighters as the Labor Day weekend approaches. Temperatures 10 to 20 degrees above normal, together with low relative humidity and wind, will test the work firefighters have recently completed on the Blue Bay Fire and other fires burning on the Flathead Reservation. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font face="Calibri"&gt;At the &lt;b&gt;Blue Bay Fire&lt;/b&gt;, containment lines held well during the past several days of hot, windy conditions. Acreage remains at 490 acres and containment is 80 percent. Smoldering and creeping continue to be the predominant fire behavior. Firefighters are addressing any hot spots they encounter while improving firelines. At this time, no additional community meetings are planned unless significant fire activity occurs. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Calibri" size="3"&gt;Strong winds at the 630-acre &lt;b&gt;Upper Midway Fire &lt;/b&gt;near Ravalli pushed flames across containment lines at one location yesterday, but helicopters assisted firefighters in responding quickly, limiting the fire’s growth to approximately 26 acres. The fire is burning mostly in grass and is 80 percent contained. Thirty-four firefighters are assigned to the fire.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Calibri" size="3"&gt;Fire behavior on the 230-acre &lt;b&gt;Black Fire &lt;/b&gt;has picked up in recent days due to high temperatures, wind and low relative humidities. The lightning-caused fire, which started on July 15, is burning in the Mission Mountains Tribal Wilderness 3 miles north of Black Lake. Firefighters plan to use aircraft today to drop water and retardant in an effort to slow the fire’s growth to the north and east. No closures are currently in place for the Black Fire. The Confederated Salish &amp;amp; Kootenai Division of Fire is coordinating firefighting efforts with the Montana DNRC – Southwest Land Office and Lolo National Forest.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Calibri" size="3"&gt;The safety of firefighters and the public remains the number one priority as we enter Labor Day weekend under the most extreme fire conditions of recent years. The public’s continued cooperation with the Stage 2 fire restrictions is a critical step in keeping everyone safe. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Calibri" size="3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Evacuation Notices:&lt;/b&gt; None at this time. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt;&lt;font face="Calibri"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Road Closures:&lt;/b&gt; To reduce the risk to firefighters and public, the B-2000 and B-2200 Roads are closed. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p align="center" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Calibri" size="3"&gt;###&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Blue Bay Fire"></category></entry></feed>