<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Montana Fires - Lolo Peak Fire</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/feeds/lolo-peak-fire.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/</id><updated>2017-09-01T10:24:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Update - Lolo Peak September 1, 2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5375_39595.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-01T10:24:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-01T10:24:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-01:/montana_fires/5375_39595.html</id><summary type="html">Lolo Peak Fire UpdateFriday, September 1, 2017; 8:30 AM Northern Rockies Incident Management Team Doug Turman, Incident CommanderFire origin: July 15, 2017, ten miles southwest of Lolo, MT. Fire Information: (406) 272-5433 Hours: 7am – 9pm  Email: LoloPeakFire@gmail.com  Websites: Inciweb: http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5375   Missoula County Sheriff: http://tinyurl.com/ya93jpuf   Ravalli County: http://ravalli.us/557/Fire-Incident-Information  Facebook: Bitterroot National Forest Facebook Page   Lolo National Forest Facebook Page      Weather: Following the thunderstorms a high pressure system is expected to return with persistent hot and dry weather. Temperatures will rise into the 90s at lower elevations and mid-80s on the ridges.    Fire Information Locations: Staffed fire information locations are at Super 1 Foods in Stevensville and Farmers State Bank in Florence. Fire information is also available at the weigh station in Lolo at the corner of Highways 12 and 93.  ...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Update - Lolo Peak September 1, 2017&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Lolo Peak Fire Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 1 day ago&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- 
cached related article links at 14:16:31
cached id 60f33015c19fddfdb156f2f90f83c756
--&gt;
&lt;div id="related_block"&gt;&lt;h4 id="related_head"&gt;Related Information&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul class="related_list"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/photos/MTLNF/2017-07-17-1952-Lolo-Peak-Fire/related_files/pict20170801-190241-0.pdf" rel="new"&gt;Update Sept. 1, 2017 (pdf 236 kb)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="6"&gt;&lt;b style="text-align: center;"&gt;Lolo Peak Fire Update&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Friday, September 1, 2017; 8:30 AM &lt;br/&gt;Northern Rockies Incident Management Team &lt;br/&gt;Doug Turman, Incident Commander&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b style=""&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt;Fire origin&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt;&lt;b style=""&gt;: &lt;/b&gt;July 15, 2017, ten miles southwest of Lolo, MT. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Fire Information&lt;/b&gt;: (406) 272-5433 Hours: 7am – 9pm &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Email: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="mailto:easternmtimt2@gmail.com"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="mailto:LoloPeakFire@gmail.com"&gt;LoloPeakFire@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Websites&lt;/b&gt;: Inciweb: &lt;a href="http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5375"&gt;http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5375&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt; Missoula County Sheriff: &lt;a href="http://tinyurl.com/ya93jpuf"&gt;http://tinyurl.com/ya93jpuf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt; Ravalli County: &lt;a href="http://ravalli.us/557/Fire-Incident-Information"&gt;http://ravalli.us/557/Fire-Incident-Information&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Facebook: &lt;/b&gt;Bitterroot National Forest Facebook Page &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt; Lolo National Forest Facebook Page&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Weather:&lt;/b&gt; Following the thunderstorms a high pressure system is expected to return with persistent hot and dry weather. Temperatures will rise into the 90s at lower elevations and mid-80s on the ridges. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;br/&gt; Fire Information Locations:&lt;/b&gt; Staffed fire information locations are at Super 1 Foods in Stevensville and Farmers State Bank in Florence. Fire information is also available at the weigh station in Lolo at the corner of Highways 12 and 93.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Evacuations and Warnings&lt;/b&gt;: The evacuation warning status was lifted for residents living in certain sections of the highway 12 and 93 corridors. This includes the Highway 12 corridor from mile marker 24 near and including Arena Drive to the Highway 93 junction in Lolo. In the Highway 93 corridor, the evacuation warning was lifted for residents starting at mile marker 79 near and including the Gravel Pit off of Old Highway 93 and the McClain Creek Road north to the Highway 12 junction. The evacuation warning remains in place in the Bear Creek and Elk Creek areas on Highway 12 east of Lolo and in the Highway 93 corridor from McClain Creek Road south to Bass Creek Road. There are no evacuation orders at this time, but this could change based on fire behavior.&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;For current information visit the Missoula County and Ravalli County Sheriffs’ Facebook pages. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;45 mPH speed limit through the fire area - HIGHWAYS ARE OPEN. &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;b&gt;Summary:&lt;/b&gt; Smoke and fire was visible throughout the area due to fire activity in the One Horse Drainage, the upper end of Sweeney Creek, and the northwestern side of the fire as it cleaned out pockets of timber that were previously unburned. Helicopters dropped buckets of water checking the fire on the south slope of the One Horse Creek drainage. Increased afternoon winds pushed the fire slowly uphill. Members of air operations were able to view the entire fire from the air today and two large helicopters worked around changing wind conditions to dump buckets of water and retardant. As the winds died down and humidity increased in the evening, the fire became less active. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt;Due to the favorable weather conditions, firefighters took the opportunity to complete burn operations to connect the already burned blocks that were created as a buffer along the primary control line south from One Horse Creek to Bass Creek. A total of 110 individuals including three 20-member crews, 8 engines, and 2 water tender trucks worked through the night. They used hand torches to ignite the fuels and bring the fire down slowly from the top of the hill. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt;Mop up continues from the northwest side of the fire along Elk Meadows Road. Elsewhere on the fire, firefighters are pulling hose and other equipment for use either in other areas of the fire or neighboring fires. Mop up along the Highway 12 was completed and personnel will continue patrolling the area. Work has begun to repair areas damaged during suppression of the fire along the Highway 12 corridor. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Today&lt;/b&gt;: Fire activity is expected to be less active today in the One Horse drainage where the fire is burning in mixed conifer fuels. The public may see isolated tree torching from deep inside the fire line as wind kicks up flames that continue to consume unburned pockets of fuel. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt;Firefighters will monitor the fire’s movement and continue to prepare for burning operations if needed. Burnout operations allow the fire to progress in a slow, deliberate manner. At that point smoke will be visible in Florence. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Please do not stop along the highways to view fire activity&lt;/b&gt;. It creates a significant traffic hazard, impedes firefighter traffic, impacts the safety of firefighters and citizens, and increases the chances that the fire could escape control lines. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Firewise&lt;/b&gt;: For information on how to improve the chances of your homes and structures surviving a wildfire, visit the Firewise website at &lt;a href="http://www.firewise.org/"&gt;www.Firewise.org&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Evacuation/Closure Information&lt;/b&gt;: Evacuations and road closures are based upon the need to provide for safety of the public and firefighters, current fire behavior, forecasted weather, and planned suppression operations. Fire officials, Missoula and Ravalli County Sheriff’s Offices, and Montana Department of Transportation will evaluate the evacuation and road closures daily. The Incident Commander, Missoula County Rural Fire Chief, Ravalli County Fire Warden, and the Missoula and Ravalli County Sheriffs appreciate your patience and will work hard to get you back into your homes as soon as it is safe to do so. Go to the Sheriffs Offices’ Facebook pages for the most current information. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Drones and TFR: &lt;/b&gt;The Temporary Flight Restriction (TFR) for the Lolo Peak Fire remains in effect. &lt;b&gt;The restriction includes “drones” or unmanned aerial vehicles. If drones are detected, air operations stop&lt;/b&gt;. &lt;b&gt;“&lt;u&gt;If you fly, we can’t!&lt;/u&gt; &lt;/b&gt;If you see a drone in the fire area, including the evacuation areas, report it immediately to 406-272-5433. Please provide your name, phone number, location and time you observed the drone. Your cooperation is needed to insure the safety of our pilots. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Stage II Fire Restrictions&lt;/b&gt; are in effect for Missoula and Ravalli Counties and across the Lolo and Bitterroot National Forests. Additional information can be found on Inciweb. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Closures:&lt;/b&gt; For specific area closure information on the Lolo and Bitterroot National Forests please visit the Inciweb website, the Lolo National Forest website and/or the Bitterroot National Forest website. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Jurisdiction:&lt;/b&gt; The fire is under the jurisdiction of the Lolo and Bitterroot National Forests and the Montana Department of Natural Resources (MTDNRC). It is being managed under unified command consisting of Incident Commander Turman, Missoula Rural Fire Chief Newman and Ravalli County Fire Warden Mohn. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt;Missoula County residents can receive emergency notifications of critical alerts via their choice of text, phone and/or email by signing up at &lt;b&gt;Smart911.com&lt;/b&gt;. Residents in Ravalli County can download the &lt;b&gt;Ravalli County Sheriff’s app&lt;/b&gt; to their mobile devices to receive critical information notifications. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style="margin-right:48.8pt;"&gt; &lt;font size="5"&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;font size="5"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Cooperators:&lt;/b&gt; Stevensville, Ravalli &amp;amp; Missoula County Government; Ravalli and Missoula County Sheriffs' Offices; Missoula Rural Fire; Florence VFD; Florence – Carlton School District; Nez Perce Tribe; Confederated Salish and Kootenai Tribes; MDOT; Carlton and Bass Lake Irrigation; Ravalli and Missoula County DES; Private Landowners. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p align="center" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;font size="5"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Aug 31, 2017: Possible operations tonight in One Horse Creek Drainage</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5375_39583.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-31T22:14:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-08-31T22:14:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-08-31:/montana_fires/5375_39583.html</id><summary type="html">Tonight, due to favorable weather conditions, crews are planning to conduct burn out operations south from One Horse Creek to Bass Creek in order to strengthen the buffer along the primary control line. Three 20 person crews, 8 engines, and 2 water tenders, for a total of over 100 personnel will be working this</summary><content type="html">Tonight, due to favorable weather conditions, crews are planning to conduct burn out operations south from One Horse Creek to Bass Creek in order to strengthen the buffer along the primary control line. Three 20 person crews, 8 engines, and 2 water tenders, for a total of over 100 personnel will be working this</content></entry><entry><title>Update August 31, 2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5375_39512.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-31T12:18:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-08-31T12:18:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-08-31:/montana_fires/5375_39512.html</id><summary type="html">Lolo Peak Fire Update  Thursday, August 31, 2017; 8:30 AM Northern Rockies Incident Management Team  Doug Turman, Incident Commander    Fire origin: July 15, 2017, ten miles southwest of Lolo, MT.    Fire Information: (406) 272-5433 Hours: 7am – 9pm    Email: LoloPeakFire@gmail.com    Websites: Inciweb: http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5375    Missoula County Sheriff: http://tinyurl.com/ya93jpuf    Ravalli County: http://ravalli.us/557/Fire-Incident-Information    Facebook: Bitterroot National Forest Facebook Page    Lolo National Forest Facebook Page         RED FLAG WARNING IN EFFECT THROUGH 9 P.M. THURSDAY         Weather: A mixture of wet and dry thunderstorms are expected with the potential for gusty and erratic winds to 40 mph. Hot and dry weather is predicted to continue with temperatures rising into the 90s at lower elevations and mid-80s on the ridges.      Fire Information Locations: Staffed fire information locations: Super 1 Foods in Stevensville; Farmers State Bank in...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Update August 31, 2017&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Lolo Peak Fire Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 2 days ago&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- 
cached related article links at 14:16:30
cached id 10aed0c1e10053882da518b1f95bc326
--&gt;
&lt;div id="related_block"&gt;&lt;h4 id="related_head"&gt;Related Information&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul class="related_list"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/photos/MTLNF/2017-07-17-1952-Lolo-Peak-Fire/related_files/pict20170731-113217-0.pdf" rel="new"&gt;Update 8-31-17 pdf (pdf 318 kb)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;Lolo Peak Fire Update&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align="left"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;Thursday, August 31, 2017; 8:30 AM&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align="left"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;Northern Rockies Incident Management Team &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align="left"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" size="3"&gt;Doug Turman, Incident Commander&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Fire origin&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;: &lt;/b&gt;July 15, 2017, ten miles southwest of Lolo, MT. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Fire Information&lt;/b&gt;: (406) 272-5433 Hours: 7am – 9pm &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Email: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="mailto:easternmtimt2@gmail.com"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="mailto:LoloPeakFire@gmail.com"&gt;LoloPeakFire@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Websites&lt;/b&gt;: Inciweb: &lt;a href="http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5375"&gt;&lt;font color="#0000ff"&gt;http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5375&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;Missoula County Sheriff: &lt;a href="http://tinyurl.com/ya93jpuf"&gt;&lt;font color="#0000ff"&gt;http://tinyurl.com/ya93jpuf&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ravalli County: &lt;a href="http://ravalli.us/557/Fire-Incident-Information"&gt;&lt;font color="#0000ff"&gt;http://ravalli.us/557/Fire-Incident-Information&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Facebook: &lt;/b&gt;Bitterroot National Forest Facebook Page &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;Lolo National Forest Facebook Page&lt;b&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;u&gt; &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt; &lt;br/&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt; &lt;u&gt; &lt;/u&gt; &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;RED FLAG WARNING IN EFFECT THROUGH 9 P.M. THURSDAY&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Weather:&lt;/b&gt; A mixture of wet and dry thunderstorms are expected with the potential for gusty and erratic winds to 40 mph. Hot and dry weather is predicted to continue with temperatures rising into the 90s at lower elevations and mid-80s on the ridges. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;br/&gt; Fire Information Locations:&lt;/b&gt; Staffed fire information locations: Super 1 Foods in Stevensville; Farmers State Bank in Florence; and the weigh station in Lolo at the corner of Highways 12 and 93. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Evacuations and Warnings&lt;/b&gt;: The evacuation warning status was lifted for residents living in certain sections of the highway 12 and 93 corridors. This includes the Highway 12 corridor from mile marker 24 near and including Arena Drive to the Highway 93 junction in Lolo. In the Highway 93 corridor, the evacuation warning was lifted for residents starting at mile marker 79 near and including the Gravel Pit off of Old Highway 93 and the McClain Creek Road north to the Highway 12 junction. The evacuation warning remains in place in the Bear Creek and Elk Creek areas on Highway 12 east of Lolo and in the Highway 93 corridor from McClain Creek Road south to Bass Creek Road. There are no evacuation orders at this time, but this could change based on fire behavior.&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;For current information visit the Missoula County and Ravalli County Sheriffs’ Facebook pages. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;45 mPH speed limit through the fire area - HIGHWAYS ARE OPEN. &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;b&gt;Summary:&lt;/b&gt; Operations were suspended when afternoon winds picked up as a thunderstorm moved south and east of the fire area. Fire continued to back down through the south-facing slope of One Horse Creek drainage, reaching the valley bottom overnight and moving a quarter ofthe way up the opposite slope. Two large helicopters dumped buckets of water on the fire front in the drainage as it smoldered a mile west of the canyon mouth. The inversion layer kept the fire’s growth up the opposite slope slow as it burns about a mile west of the end of Tie Chute Lane. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;Firefighters started preparing areas for burning operations to connect the already burned blocks created as a buffer along the primary control line south from One Horse Creek to Bass Creek. As the conditions allow, firefighters will conduct these smaller burnout operations in the upcoming days to protect residences in the Highway 93 corridor. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;Mop up continued along the northwest side of the fire along Elk Meadows Road just north of the border as it continues to smolder through some of the unburned pockets of fuel. Elsewhere on the fire, firefighters are pulling hose and other equipment for use either in other areas of the fire or neighboring fires. Mop up along the Highway 12 was completed and will be staffed with personnel patrolling the area. Personnel started repairing areas damaged during suppression of the fire along the Highway 12 corridor. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Today&lt;/b&gt;: A red flag warning continues through 9 p.m. predicting a mixture of wet and dry thunderstorms with strong downburst winds that will be 30-45 mph along the ridges. The next course of action will depend on what thunderstorms bring to the fire. Fire operation will be limited as long as the outflow winds exist and create an unstable working environment. The public may see isolated tree torching from deep inside the fire line as wind kicks up flames that continue to consume unburned pockets of fuel. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;Firefighters will monitor the fire’s movement as it continues to back down into the One Horse Creek drainage and continue to move up the opposite slope. Firefighters have been expecting and preparing for the fire’s movement. If the fire’s pace picks up and moves east, burnout operations may be implemented if needed. Burnout operations allow the fire to progress in a slow, deliberate manner. At that point smoke will be visible in Florence. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Please do not stop along the highways to view fire activity&lt;/b&gt;. It creates a significant traffic hazard, impedes firefighter traffic, impacts the safety of firefighters and citizens, and increases the chances that the fire could escape control lines. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Firewise&lt;/b&gt;: For information on how to improve the chances of your homes and structures surviving a wildfire, visit the Firewise website at &lt;a href="http://www.firewise.org/"&gt;www.Firewise.org&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Evacuation/Closure Information&lt;/b&gt;: Evacuations and road closures are based upon the need to provide for safety of the public and firefighters, current fire behavior, forecasted weather, and planned suppression operations. Fire officials, Missoula and Ravalli County Sheriff’s Offices, and Montana Department of Transportation will evaluate the evacuation and road closures daily. The Incident Commander, Missoula County Rural Fire Chief, Ravalli County Fire Warden, and the Missoula and Ravalli County Sheriffs appreciate your patience and will work hard to get you back into your homes as soon as it is safe to do so. Go to the Sheriffs Offices’ Facebook pages for the most current information. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt; &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Drones and TFR: &lt;/b&gt;The Temporary Flight Restriction (TFR) for the Lolo Peak Fire remains in effect. &lt;b&gt;The restriction includes “drones” or unmanned aerial vehicles. If drones are detected, air operations stop&lt;/b&gt;. &lt;b&gt;“&lt;u&gt;If you fly, we can’t!&lt;/u&gt; &lt;/b&gt;If you see a drone in the fire area, including the evacuation areas, report it immediately to 406-272-5433. Please provide your name, phone number, location and time you observed the drone. Your cooperation is needed to insure the safety of our pilots. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Stage II Fire Restrictions&lt;/b&gt; are in effect for Missoula and Ravalli Counties and across the Lolo and Bitterroot National Forests. Additional information can be found on Inciweb. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Closures:&lt;/b&gt; For specific area closure information on the Lolo and Bitterroot National Forests please visit the Inciweb website, the Lolo National Forest website and/or the Bitterroot National Forest website. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Jurisdiction:&lt;/b&gt; The fire is under the jurisdiction of the Lolo and Bitterroot National Forests and the Montana Department of Natural Resources (MTDNRC). It is being managed under unified command consisting of Incident Commander &lt;font size="3"&gt;Turman&lt;/font&gt;, Missoula Rural Fire Chief Newman and Ravalli County Fire Warden Mohn. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;Missoula County residents can receive emergency notifications of critical alerts via their choice of text, phone and/or email by signing up at &lt;b&gt;Smart911.com&lt;/b&gt;. Residents in Ravalli County can download the &lt;b&gt;Ravalli County Sheriff’s app&lt;/b&gt; to their mobile devices to receive critical information notifications. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Cooperators:&lt;/b&gt; Stevensville, Ravalli &amp;amp; Missoula County Government; Ravalli and Missoula County Sheriffs' Offices; Missoula Rural Fire; Florence VFD; Florence – Carlton School District; Nez Perce Tribe; Confederated Salish and Kootenai Tribes; MDOT; Carlton and Bass Lake Irrigation; Ravalli and Missoula County DES; Private Landowners. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content></entry></feed>