<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Montana Fires - Meyers Fire</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/feeds/meyers-fire.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/</id><updated>2017-09-02T09:46:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Meyers Fire Update September 2, 2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5397_39713.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-02T09:46:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-02T09:46:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-02:/montana_fires/5397_39713.html</id><summary type="html">Current Size:  30,486 acresResources Assigned: 322        Extreme fire conditions. No campfires allowed.      Status: The fire is burning in mixed conifer stands, primarily lodgepole pine, Douglas fir, and subalpine fir, with numerous standing dead trees. There are residences still at risk in the Moose Lake, Frog Pond, Springer Memorial Park and Bonanza areas.    Yesterday’s Activities: Fire activity was not as intense as on Thursday, but the periphery did continue to expand in several areas with some short-range spotting, torching and fire runs occurring. The eastern edge of the fire south of Moose Lake advanced beyond the Continental Divide Trail into Deer Lodge County, with some additional spotting ahead of the fire. The Moose Lake and East Fork Bitterroot communities remain in a pre-evacuation warning status. Along the fire’s west edge, ground crews made progress on control lines and burn outs, and continued structure protection measures in the Frog Pond and East Fork...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Meyers Fire Update September 2, 2017&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Meyers Fire Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 5 hrs. ago&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Current Size: &lt;/b&gt; 30,486 acres&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Resources Assigned&lt;/b&gt;: 322 &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p align="center" style="margin: 4pt 0in; text-align: center;"&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;font size="4"&gt;Extreme fire conditions. No campfires allowed.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="4"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Status:&lt;/b&gt; The fire is burning in mixed conifer stands, primarily lodgepole pine, Douglas fir, and subalpine fir, with numerous standing dead trees. There are residences still at risk in the Moose Lake, Frog Pond, Springer Memorial Park and Bonanza areas.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Yesterday’s Activities: &lt;/b&gt;Fire activity was not as intense as on Thursday, but the periphery did continue to expand in several areas with some short-range spotting, torching and fire runs occurring. The eastern edge of the fire south of Moose Lake advanced beyond the Continental Divide Trail into Deer Lodge County, with some additional spotting ahead of the fire. The Moose Lake and East Fork Bitterroot communities remain in a pre-evacuation warning status. Along the fire’s west edge, ground crews made progress on control lines and burn outs, and continued structure protection measures in the Frog Pond and East Fork Bitterroot communities. Hand crews and heavy equipment neared completion of a control line running east from Zeke’s Meadow, which itself was partially burned out today to increase holding capabilities along the north edge.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Current Resources: Three&lt;/b&gt; 20-person crews, &lt;b&gt;twenty&lt;/b&gt; engines, &lt;b&gt;four&lt;/b&gt; pieces of heavy equipment (dozers, masticators), &lt;b&gt;ten &lt;/b&gt;water tenders, and &lt;b&gt;three&lt;/b&gt; helicopters. Total personnel: &lt;b&gt;322&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Today’s Activities:&lt;/b&gt; Fire weather will intensify again today and tomorrow after yesterday’s slight reprieve. Spotting of ¼ to ½ mile may occur. Fire activity will increase, especially along the southwest, south, and southeast edges of the fire. Fire staff will work on building a machine and hand line ahead of the southwest edge of the fire to protect the East Fork Bitterroot structures. Structure protection efforts will continue here, at Frog Pond, Moose Lake, and other isolated buildings. Crews will continue burn out operations to reduce unburned fuels between the fire and the Frog Pond area. Because of the potential for increased fire activity along the east side, the Moose Lake community will be a main focus of attention today.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Evacuations: &lt;/b&gt;The Frog Pond area is under an evacuation order. Moose Lake residents are under an evacuation warning. Additionally, an evacuation warning is in effect on East Fork Rd from FS Rd 5778 to Little East Fork Rd (FS RD 724) on the Bitterroot National Forest.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Restrictions/Closures: &lt;/b&gt;Bitterroot National Forest emergency closure orders are in effect for upper areas of the East Fork Bitterroot River.&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;emergency closure orders are in effect around the fire area.&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;The closure of Forest Roads 893, 8684 and 8685 was rescinded at 6:00AM Friday, September 1, 2017. A temporary flight restriction (TFR) is in effect surrounding the Meyers Fire area. Granite County is under Stage 2 fire restrictions for private lands in the county. Amended Stage 1 fire restrictions have gone into effect today which prohibit &lt;b&gt;ALL&lt;/b&gt; campfires in southwestern Montana, including in fire rings and developed recreation areas. &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;For further information&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;follow the &lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/US-Forest-Service-Beaverhead-Deerlodge-National-Forest-1540138089548920/"&gt;&lt;font color="#0000ff" size="2"&gt;Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest Facebook&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; and &lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/DiscoverBitterrootNF"&gt;&lt;font color="#0000ff" size="2"&gt;Bitterroot National Forest Facebook&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; pages.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content></entry></feed>