<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Montana Fires - Meyers Fire</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/feeds/meyers-fire.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/</id><updated>2017-09-01T10:08:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Meyers Fire Update for September 1, 2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5397_39600.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-01T10:08:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-01T10:08:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-01:/montana_fires/5397_39600.html</id><summary type="html">There is a public meeting tonight at 6:00PM at the Sula Community Clubhouse in Sula.Current Size:  28,914 acres  Resources Assigned: 292      Status: The fire is burning in mixed conifer stands, primarily lodgepole pine, with many standing dead trees. There are residences at risk in the vicinity of the fire in the areas of Moose Lake, Frog Pond, Springer Memorial Park and Bonanza.     Yesterday’s Activities: Significant fire activity occurred yesterday as a result of dry, hot conditions and tinder-dry fuels responding to gusty, erratic winds. The eastern edge of the fire south of Moose Lake extended well beyond the primary containment line. The slop over caused a temporary closure of the Moose Lake Rd while officials re-assessed the threat to the Moose Lake community which remains, for the moment, in a pre-evacuation warning status. Slower rates of fire towards the Springer Memorial and Bonanza areas has allowed firefighters to identify and implement structure protection...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Meyers Fire Update for September 1, 2017&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Meyers Fire Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 1 day ago&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;There is a public meeting tonight at 6:00PM at the Sula Community Clubhouse in Sula.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Current Size: &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;28,914 acres &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;b&gt;Resources Assigned&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;: 292 &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Status:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;The fire is burning in mixed conifer stands, primarily lodgepole pine, with many standing dead trees. There are residences at risk in the vicinity of the fire in the areas of Moose Lake, Frog Pond, Springer Memorial Park and Bonanza.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Yesterday’s Activities: &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Significant fire activity occurred yesterday as a result of dry, hot conditions and tinder-dry fuels responding to gusty, erratic winds. The eastern edge of the fire south of Moose Lake extended well beyond the primary containment line. The slop over caused a temporary closure of the Moose Lake Rd while officials re-assessed the threat to the Moose Lake community which remains, for the moment, in a pre-evacuation warning status. Slower rates of fire towards the Springer Memorial and Bonanza areas has allowed firefighters to identify and implement structure protection measures. Firefighters continued to provide aggressive structure protection around Frog Pond residences where fire is backing towards the cabins. On the north end, as crews and heavy equipment extended control line toward Zeke’s Meadow, fire moved toward the northeastern containment lines. The east-west contingency lines from MT Hwy 1 to the Moose Lake Rd were completed.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Current Resources: &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;One &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;type-1 20-person crew, &lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;one&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; type-2 20-person crew, &lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;fourteen&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; engines, &lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;four&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; pieces of heavy equipment (dozers, masticators, skidgines), &lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;ten &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;water tenders, and &lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;two&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; helicopters.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Total personnel:&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;b&gt;292&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Today’s Activities:&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; As the red flag conditions of the past two days subside, firefighting efforts will address the outcome of yesterday’s fire growth. More work will be done to regain containment east of the burned over containment lines south of Moose Lake. With uncontrolled fire returning to this side of the incident, increased suppression activity can be expected and public preparedness is encouraged. On the west flank, as structure protection measures for Frog Pond and Springer Memorial are implemented, a decrease of predominant west/ northwest winds provides more favorable conditions for containment efforts. The completion of the east-west contingency lines south of Georgetown Lake enables the resources from those areas to shift and assist with line construction east of Moose Lake Rd and in the Springer Memorial area.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Evacuations: &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;The Frog Pond area is under an evacuation order. Moose Lake residents are under an evacuation warning. Additionally, an evacuation warning is in effect on East Fork Rd from FS Rd 5778 to Little East Fork Rd (FS RD 724) on the Bitterroot National Forest.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Restrictions/Closures: &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Bitterroot National Forest emergency closure orders are in effect for upper areas of the East Fork Bitterroot River.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;emergency closure orders are in effect around the fire area.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;The closure of Forest Roads 893, 8684 and 8685 was rescinded at 6:00AM Friday, September 1, 2017. A temporary flight restriction (TFR) is in effect surrounding the Meyers Fire area. Granite County is under Stage 2 fire restrictions for private lands in the county. Amended Stage 1 fire restrictions are going into effect Saturday which prohibit &lt;/font&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;ALL&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; campfires in southwestern Montana, including in fire rings and developed recreation areas. &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;For further information&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt;,&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; follow the &lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/US-Forest-Service-Beaverhead-Deerlodge-National-Forest-1540138089548920/"&gt;&lt;font color="#0000ff" size="2"&gt;Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest Facebook&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; and &lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/DiscoverBitterrootNF"&gt;&lt;font color="#0000ff" size="2"&gt;Bitterroot National Forest Facebook&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font size="2"&gt; pages.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Meyers Fire Community Meetings</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5397_39530.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-31T12:45:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-08-31T12:45:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-08-31:/montana_fires/5397_39530.html</id><summary type="html">The Northern Rockies Type 2 Incident Management Team is hosting a public meeting on the Meyers Fire. A meeting will be held on Friday, September 1 at 6:00 pm at the Sula Community Club House on East Fork Road in Sula for the Meyers Fire.</summary><content type="html">The Northern Rockies Type 2 Incident Management Team is hosting a public meeting on the Meyers Fire. A meeting will be held on Friday, September 1 at 6:00 pm at the Sula Community Club House on East Fork Road in Sula for the Meyers Fire.</content></entry></feed>