<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Montana Fires - Rice Ridge Fire</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/feeds/rice-ridge-fire.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/</id><updated>2017-09-01T10:21:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Air Quality Report for 9-1-2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5414_39602.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-01T10:21:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-01T10:21:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-01:/montana_fires/5414_39602.html</id><summary type="html">Smoke: The hot, stagnant conditions from the last few days will give way to critical fire weather today for dry thunderstorms with gusty outflow winds. This will be followed by a dry cold front that should pass through the area beginning this evening bringing increased westerly winds. Active fire behavior, with the potential for rapid growth is possible. Yesterday, Rice Ridge and Liberty added 1,560 acres and 529 acres respectively.   Fire: As the stable conditions break down there should be a slight clearing of smoke later today and into the evening, however this will be slow to materialize and variable in terms of the locations due to the erratic nature of the winds associated the dry thunderstorms. As the cold front moves through this evening and tomorrow, accumulated smoke should start to clear but this could be followed by new smoke. Seeley Lake will remain Hazardous and the rest of the sites will remain in the Unhealthy to USG range.   Other: Critical fire weather will continue...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Air Quality Report for 9-1-2017&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Rice Ridge Fire Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 1 day ago&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- 
cached related article links at 14:16:33
cached id 698a9532e165d1e6c2e027077c0a66f9
--&gt;
&lt;div id="related_block"&gt;&lt;h4 id="related_head"&gt;Related Information&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul class="related_list"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/photos/MTLNF/2017-07-24-2216-Rice-Ridge-Fire/related_files/pict20170801-150528-0.pdf" rel="new"&gt;Air Quality Report for 9-1-2017 (pdf 163 kb)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 4.8pt 17.4pt 0pt 5.1pt; line-height: 118%;"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Smoke: &lt;/b&gt;The hot, stagnant conditions from the last few days will give way to critical fire weather today for dry thunderstorms with gusty outflow winds. This will be followed by a dry cold front that should pass through the area beginning this evening bringing increased westerly winds. Active fire behavior, with the potential for rapid growth is possible. Yesterday, Rice Ridge and Liberty added 1,560 acres and 529 acres respectively.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0.6pt 0in 0pt;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 7.65pt 0pt 5.1pt; line-height: 118%;"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Fire: &lt;/b&gt;As the stable conditions break down there should be a slight clearing of smoke later today and into the evening, however this will be slow to materialize and variable in terms of the locations due to the erratic nature of the winds associated the dry thunderstorms. As the cold front moves through this evening and tomorrow, accumulated smoke should start to clear but this could be followed by new smoke. Seeley Lake will remain Hazardous and the rest of the sites will remain in the Unhealthy to USG range.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0.6pt 0in 0pt;"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 10.7pt 0pt 5.1pt; line-height: 116%;"&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"&gt;Other: &lt;/b&gt;Critical fire weather will continue Thursday with sustained dry gusty winds. For additional information please refer to Missoula City-County Health Department in the "links" below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Rice Ridge Fire Update 9-1-2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5414_39601.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-01T10:13:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-01T10:13:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-01:/montana_fires/5414_39601.html</id><summary type="html">A community meeting will be held tonight, September 1, at 6:00 p.m. at the Ovando Elementary School. This event will not be live streamed. Location: Approximately1.4 miles northeast of Seeley Lake Montana Cause: Lightning caused on July 24, 2017 Fire Size and Containment: 37,032 acres and 18% contained Total Personnel: 729 Yesterday: Crews held fire growth at critical locations across the perimeter despite yesterday’s red flag warning. On the west flank of the fire, ground and aerial resources limited spread in the Murphy Creek and Sawyer Creek drainages where the fire spotted frequently during afternoon winds. Windy conditions and active fire behavior once again forced crews to disengage from the fire during the afternoon. New line construction began between Findell and Sawyer Creek in an attempt to limit fire growth to the north and west. In the Morrell Creek area, growth to the south was limited by new fire line and direct engagement of spot fires. Active fire behavior was...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Rice Ridge Fire Update 9-1-2017&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Rice Ridge Fire Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 1 day ago&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- 
cached related article links at 14:16:33
cached id 60add36c49f3e0f138630b6a77b94830
--&gt;
&lt;div id="related_block"&gt;&lt;h4 id="related_head"&gt;Related Information&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul class="related_list"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/photos/MTLNF/2017-07-24-2216-Rice-Ridge-Fire/related_files/pict20170801-150404-0.pdf" rel="new"&gt;Rice Ridge Fire Update 9-1-2017 (pdf 55 kb)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font size="4"&gt;A&lt;/font&gt; &lt;font size="4"&gt;community meeting will be held tonight, September 1, at 6:00 p.m. at the Ovando Elementary School. This event will not be live streamed. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Location:&lt;/b&gt; Approximately1.4 miles northeast of Seeley Lake Montana&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt; Cause: &lt;/b&gt;Lightning caused on July 24, 2017 &lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Fire Size and Containment:&lt;/b&gt; 37,032 acres and 18% contained &lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Total Personnel:&lt;/b&gt; 729 &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Yesterday:&lt;/b&gt; Crews held fire growth at critical locations across the perimeter despite yesterday’s red flag warning. On the west flank of the fire, ground and aerial resources limited spread in the Murphy Creek and Sawyer Creek drainages where the fire spotted frequently during afternoon winds. Windy conditions and active fire behavior once again forced crews to disengage from the fire during the afternoon. New line construction began between Findell and Sawyer Creek in an attempt to limit fire growth to the north and west. In the Morrell Creek area, growth to the south was limited by new fire line and direct engagement of spot fires. Active fire behavior was observed in the Morrell Mountain area as the fire continued to remove fuel and back down towards the Cottonwood Lakes Road. Backing fire activity was also seen to the east of Cottonwood Lakes as the fire moved south towards the Cottonwood Lakes Road. Crews and aircraft were able to hold the fire to the north of the road with the help of previous fuel treatments and support from heavy helicopters. Significant spotting was observed in the Cottonwood Lakes area, but firefighters assisted by heavy helicopters successfully held fire growth to the north of the Cottonwood Lakes Road. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Planned Actions:&lt;/b&gt; Fire managers will reassess fire line locations after yesterday’s growth along the north end of the fire perimeter while attempting to tie into the 2015 Morrell Complex Fire burn scar. On the west flank of the fire crews will continue to construct and extend direct fire line in an effort to increase containment. Current containment lines will be patrolled throughout the day. In the Morrell Creek drainage, crews will continue to engage spot fires and may use strategic burning operations to enhance fire line if conditions allow. Personnel will continue to hold fire to the north near Morrell Mountain. A newly acquired hotshot crew may be burning in the Morrell Mountain area to eliminate fuel between indirect lines and the fire front. Engines, crews, and aircraft will be working along the Cottonwood Lakes Road near Cottonwood Lakes to address spot fires and hold the fire to the north of the road. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Evacuations&lt;/b&gt;: The Missoula County Sheriff has issued multiple evacuation ORDERS and WARNINGS. The current map and description is posted on &lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/article/5414/39277/"&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;Inciweb&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;. A shelter site is located at the UCC Church, 405 University Avenue, Missoula MT. Anyone seeking shelter may call the Red Cross of Montana at 1-800-272-6668. Residents of the area should sign up for Smart911 at &lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.smart911.com/"&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;https://www.smart911.com/&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt; to ensure they receive messages about potential evacuations. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Closures:&lt;/b&gt; New closures are in effect for the Horseshoe Hills area, the Blackfoot-Clearwater Wildlife Management Area, and surrounding Montana DNRC and BLM lands. An existing closure order in effect for the areas surrounding the Rice Ridge Fire is posted on &lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5414/"&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;Inciweb&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;. Big Larch Campground, Big Larch boat launch, Seeley Lake Campground boat launch, Canoe Trail and Seeley Lake waters are closed due to aerial operations related to Rice Ridge Fire suppression efforts. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Air Quality:&lt;/b&gt; For current air quality information please visit &lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/news/5414/"&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;Inciweb&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Weather:&lt;/b&gt; Today will be mostly clear with valley smoke in the morning. Temperatures could reach the low 80’s on ridge tops and the mid 80’s in valley bottoms. Minimum humidity levels are expected between 17% and 22%. Winds will be out of the West/Southwest and shifting to the West/Northwest at 8 mph with potential gusts in the afternoon up to 18 mph. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Important:&lt;/b&gt; Drones are prohibited in the fire vicinity &amp;amp;have; the potential to shut down all air operations. A Temporary Flight Restriction (TFR) remains in place. (&lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="http://tfr.faa.gov/save_pages/detail_7_9440.html"&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;http://tfr.faa.gov/save_pages/detail_7_9440.html&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;)&lt;/font&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; Cooperators: Seeley Lake FD, Missoula County Sherriff, Missoula County OEM, Montana DNRC, Montana Fish and Wildlife and Parks, Montana DOT, American Red Cross, Montana Highway Patrol. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; ###&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content></entry></feed>