<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Montana Fires - Sanders County</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/feeds/sanders-county.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/</id><updated>2017-09-12T15:14:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Voluntary Evacuations and Road Closures will be Lifted this Evening</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5600_40848.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-12T15:14:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-12T15:14:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-12:/montana_fires/5600_40848.html</id><summary type="html">Voluntary evacuations occurring near the 20MP on the Thompson River Road, and road closures at MP17 and MP27 on the County road and the ACM Road will be lifted at 1900</summary><content type="html">Voluntary evacuations occurring near the 20MP on the Thompson River Road, and road closures at MP17 and MP27 on the County road and the ACM Road will be lifted at 1900</content><category term="McCully Fire"></category></entry><entry><title>Pre-evacuation notices remain in effect</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5600_40489.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-09T10:35:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-09T10:35:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-09:/montana_fires/5600_40489.html</id><summary type="html">Pre-evacuation notices remain in effect for residences in the Chippy Creek, Semen Creek, and Fishtrap</summary><content type="html">Pre-evacuation notices remain in effect for residences in the Chippy Creek, Semen Creek, and Fishtrap</content><category term="McCully Fire"></category></entry><entry><title>Weyerhaeuser Annouces Closure of Lands</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5600_40418.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-08T15:26:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-08T15:26:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-08:/montana_fires/5600_40418.html</id><summary type="html">Weyerhaeuser announced that all of its lands in Flathead, Lake, Lincoln, Missoula, Sanders, and Ravalli counties in western Montana are now closed to public access due to the extreme forest fire danger. This closure will remain in effect until further</summary><content type="html">Weyerhaeuser announced that all of its lands in Flathead, Lake, Lincoln, Missoula, Sanders, and Ravalli counties in western Montana are now closed to public access due to the extreme forest fire danger. This closure will remain in effect until further</content><category term="McCully Fire"></category></entry><entry><title>Closures in Place on Thompson River and ACM Roads</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5600_40417.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-08T15:13:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-08T15:13:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-08:/montana_fires/5600_40417.html</id><summary type="html">Localized road closures are in place on the Thompson River Road and ACM Road (mile markers 17 - 23).Weyerhaeuser announced that all of its lands in Flathead, Lake, Lincoln, Missoula, Sanders, and Ravalli counties in western Montana are closed to public access due to the extreme forest fire danger. This closure will remain in effect until further</summary><content type="html">Localized road closures are in place on the Thompson River Road and ACM Road (mile markers 17 - 23).Weyerhaeuser announced that all of its lands in Flathead, Lake, Lincoln, Missoula, Sanders, and Ravalli counties in western Montana are closed to public access due to the extreme forest fire danger. This closure will remain in effect until further</content><category term="McCully Fire"></category></entry><entry><title>Plains Public Meeting, Saturday, Sept 9th</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5558_40348.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-08T09:46:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-08T09:46:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-08:/montana_fires/5558_40348.html</id><summary type="html">The Western Montana Incident Management Team will be hosting a public meeting in Thompson Falls to discuss the Highway 200 Complex Fires. Presentations will include an update and planned actions from operations, a discussion about evacuations from the Sheriff, updates from the Forest Service, and a closing message from the Incident Commander. Following the presentations, we will have a question and answer session and fire management personnel will stick around after the meeting for one-on-one discussions as</summary><content type="html">The Western Montana Incident Management Team will be hosting a public meeting in Thompson Falls to discuss the Highway 200 Complex Fires. Presentations will include an update and planned actions from operations, a discussion about evacuations from the Sheriff, updates from the Forest Service, and a closing message from the Incident Commander. Following the presentations, we will have a question and answer session and fire management personnel will stick around after the meeting for one-on-one discussions as</content><category term="Sheep Gap"></category></entry><entry><title>Evacuation Notice and Public Meeting Notice</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5558_39779.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-02T14:34:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-02T14:34:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-02:/montana_fires/5558_39779.html</id><summary type="html">Evacuation Notice: The Fire Management Team, in conjunction with the Sanders County Sheriff’s office, has decided to implement evacuation procedures on the Sheep Gap fire. The evacuation will cover all private residences from the corner of the road on the River Road West in Section 11, T20N, R27W west to the end of River Road West. The evacuation plan was activated at noon and residents are asked to be clear of the area by 6 p.m. this evening. Public Meeting: A public meeting on the Sheep Gap, Deep Creek and other fires under Kootenai National Forest and DNRC jurisdiction, which will be managed by the incoming Fire Management Team, will be held at the Plains High School gymnasium in Plains at 1 p.m. Sunday, Sept. 3.</summary><content type="html">Evacuation Notice: The Fire Management Team, in conjunction with the Sanders County Sheriff’s office, has decided to implement evacuation procedures on the Sheep Gap fire. The evacuation will cover all private residences from the corner of the road on the River Road West in Section 11, T20N, R27W west to the end of River Road West. The evacuation plan was activated at noon and residents are asked to be clear of the area by 6 p.m. this evening. Public Meeting: A public meeting on the Sheep Gap, Deep Creek and other fires under Kootenai National Forest and DNRC jurisdiction, which will be managed by the incoming Fire Management Team, will be held at the Plains High School gymnasium in Plains at 1 p.m. Sunday, Sept. 3.</content><category term="Sheep Gap"></category></entry><entry><title>Highway 200 Complex will contain Sheep Gap and Deep Creek</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5558_39770.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-02T12:57:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-02T12:57:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-02:/montana_fires/5558_39770.html</id><summary type="html">Today, Sept 2nd at 8:00 pm, Sheep Gap and Deep Creek will be managed by the Northern Rockies Western Montana Type 2 Incident Management Team under Incident Commander Connel. Sheep Gap and Deep Creek Fires as well as four fires on the Kootenai National Forest will be managed by this team. Updates, Closures and Maps for both Sheep Gap and Deep Creek Fires will be found on this page today.</summary><content type="html">Today, Sept 2nd at 8:00 pm, Sheep Gap and Deep Creek will be managed by the Northern Rockies Western Montana Type 2 Incident Management Team under Incident Commander Connel. Sheep Gap and Deep Creek Fires as well as four fires on the Kootenai National Forest will be managed by this team. Updates, Closures and Maps for both Sheep Gap and Deep Creek Fires will be found on this page today.</content><category term="Sheep Gap"></category></entry><entry><title>9-2-2017 Sheep Gap &amp; Deep Creek Fires Update</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5558_39767.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-02T12:50:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-02T12:50:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-02:/montana_fires/5558_39767.html</id><summary type="html">Sheep Creek and Deep Creek Fires UpdateSeptember 2, 2017, 7 A.M. Phone: 406-826-4345 or 406-529-5475 Inciweb: https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5558/ Contact: John Hamilton  What: Sheep Gap and Deep Creek Fires Update Location: Fire is approximately 9 miles west of Plains, Plains-Thompson Falls Ranger District (T 20 North R 27 W Section 7), Deep Creek Fire is approximately 12 miles northwest of Thompson Falls, (T 23 North R 30 W Section 14) Size: Sheep Gap 2,242 acres, Deep Creek 533 acres Containment: 0 Cause: Started by lightning Aug. 29 (Sheep Gap), Aug. 30 (Deep Creek)  The Sheep Gap and Deep Creeks Fires: The Sheep Gap and Deep Creek fires were started by lightning earlier this week and are currently being managed jointly under a local incident management team. Pre-evacuation notices have been issued to residents near both fires, for the River Road West and West Fork Swamp areas on the Sheep Gap fire, and for the Blue Slide road area for the Deep Creek fire. The primary...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;9-2-2017 Sheep Gap &amp;amp; Deep Creek Fires Update&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Sheep Gap Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 1:45 hrs. ago&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sheep Creek and Deep Creek Fires Update&lt;font face="Verdana"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face="Verdana"&gt;September 2, 2017, 7 A.M.&lt;/font&gt; Phone: 406-826-4345 or 406-529-5475 Inciweb: https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5558/&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Contact: John Hamilton &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What: Sheep Gap and Deep Creek Fires Update&lt;br/&gt; Location: Fire is approximately 9 miles west of Plains, Plains-Thompson Falls Ranger District (T 20 North R 27 W Section 7), Deep Creek Fire is approximately 12 miles northwest of Thompson Falls, (T 23 North R 30 W Section 14)&lt;br/&gt; Size: Sheep Gap 2,242 acres, Deep Creek 533 acres&lt;br/&gt; Containment: 0&lt;br/&gt; Cause: Started by lightning Aug. 29 (Sheep Gap), Aug. 30 (Deep Creek) &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Sheep Gap and Deep Creeks Fires: The Sheep Gap and Deep Creek fires were started by lightning earlier this week and are currently being managed jointly under a local incident management team. Pre-evacuation notices have been issued to residents near both fires, for the River Road West and West Fork Swamp areas on the Sheep Gap fire, and for the Blue Slide road area for the Deep Creek fire. The primary objectives for both fires is to first secure identified resources of value and structures in the vicinity of each incident while attempting to contain both. Contingency lines are being constructed on the Sheep Gap fire in case the fire moves towards the east or north where structures are located. Helicopters with buckets, heavy air tanker retardant and single engine air tanker retardant planes continue to be utilized to help contain fire spread. Continuing hot and dry weather, with temperatures forecast to be well into the 90s for the next several days, are another factor affecting fire behavior on all fires burning in the area. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Resources: Resources assigned to the incidents include 51 personnel, several engines and a structure assessment group on the Sheep Gap fire, and two 20-person crews on the Deep Creek fire. Structure assessment and pre-evacuation planning is also ongoing on the Deep Creek fire.&lt;br/&gt; Both fires will continue to utilize helicopters with buckets and retardant planes as available and needed. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Structures: Both fires have structures and dwellings below the incidents along roads, and pre- evacuation warnings have been issued to those residents determined to be possibly affected. Homeowners have been advised to keep informed on current fire conditions and to be prepared as possible in the event that evacuations are implemented by the Sanders County Sheriff’s office. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Hazards: Steep, rocky terrain on both fires and access to both is problematic. Very dry forest fuels and continuing hot and dry weather are complicating factors. The hunting season for upland game birds and archery starts today in Montana, meaning more people will be out and the risk of new fire starts will increase. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you fly, we can’t! The use of unmanned aircraft (drones) is illegal near forest fires and can force the grounding of firefighting aircraft, jeopardize firefighter and pilot safety and impede successful suppression. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Closures: Roads and trails in both fire areas have been closed. Please see those area closure orders for more information on specific roads and trails. Please access Inciweb at https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/closures/5558/ for all roads and trails affected. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Sheep Gap"></category></entry><entry><title>2017-9-2 Deep Creek Closure Order #77</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5558_39765.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-02T12:29:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-02T12:29:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-02:/montana_fires/5558_39765.html</id><summary type="html">F17-077-LOLO-D5LOLO NATIONAL FOREST 24 Fort Missoula Road Missoula, Montana 59804-7297 FOREST SUPERVISOR’S ORDER   Pursuant to Title 36 Code of Federal Regulations 261.50 (a &amp; b), the following acts are prohibited as described below within the Plains/Thompson Falls Ranger District of the Lolo National Forest. These restrictions are in addition to those enumerated in Subpart A, Part 261, Title 36, Code of Federal Regulations, and become effective upon signing and will remain in effect until rescinded.  36 CFR – Special Closures   It is prohibited to go into or be upon the area (36 CFR 261.53(e)).   The closure cited in this order is to protect the public from potential harm from wildfires and firefighting operations associated with the Deep Creek Fire.    Description of Closed Areas:   This area closure closes the area as described below and shown on the ATTACHED MAP.   All of sections 3 – 8, and parts of sections 1, 2, 9 – 11, &amp; 16 – 19, T. 22 N., R. 29 W. Part of section 1,...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2017-9-2 Deep Creek Closure Order #77&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Sheep Gap Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 2 hrs. ago&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- 
cached related article links at 14:34:51
cached id 627bf911735481011c43f4319e03e5ab
--&gt;
&lt;div id="related_block"&gt;&lt;h4 id="related_head"&gt;Related Information&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul class="related_list"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/photos/MTLNF/2017-08-30-1109-Sheep-Gap/related_files/pict20170802-124903-0.pdf" rel="new"&gt;9-1-17 Deep Creek Closure Order #077 (pdf 64 kb)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/photos/MTLNF/2017-08-30-1109-Sheep-Gap/related_files/pict20170802-124953-0.pdf" rel="new"&gt;8-31-2017 Deep Creek Fire Closure Map #077 (pdf 4,914 kb)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p align="center" style="text-align: left;"&gt;F17-077-LOLO-D5&lt;b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align="center" style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;b&gt;LOLO NATIONAL FOREST&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="center" style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;b&gt;24 Fort Missoula Road&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="center" style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Missoula, Montana 59804-7297&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="center" style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;b&gt;FOREST SUPERVISOR’S ORDER&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="center" style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Pursuant to Title 36 Code of Federal Regulations 261.50 (a &amp;amp; b), the following acts are prohibited as described below within the Plains/Thompson Falls Ranger District of the Lolo National Forest. These restrictions are in addition to those enumerated in Subpart A, Part 261, Title 36, Code of Federal Regulations, and become effective upon signing and will remain in effect until rescinded. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt;36 CFR – Special Closures&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;It is prohibited to go into or be upon the area (36 CFR 261.53(e)).&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;The closure cited in this order is to protect the public from potential harm from wildfires and firefighting operations associated with the Deep Creek Fire. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Description of Closed Areas:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt;This area closure closes the area as described below and shown on the ATTACHED MAP.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;All of sections 3 – 8, and parts of sections 1, 2, 9 – 11, &amp;amp; 16 – 19, T. 22 N., R. 29 W.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;Part of section 1, T. 22 N., R. 30 W.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;All of sections and Protracted Blocks PB37, PB38, 8, 16, 17, PB39, PB40, 20 – 23, 27 – 29, PB41, PB42, PB43, PB44, &amp;amp; PB45, and parts of sections and Protracted Blocks 5, 9, 10, 14, 15, 24, 25, 26, PB46, PB47, T. 23 N., R. 29 W.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;All of sections 1, 11 – 15, &amp;amp; 23 – 25, and parts of sections 2, 9, 10, 22, 26, 36, T. 23 N., R. 30 W.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;Parts of sections and Protracted Blocks 30, PB45, &amp;amp; 32, T. 24 N., R. 29 W.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;All of Protracted Block PB52 and part of section 25 and part of Protracted Block PB51, T. 24 N., R. 30 W&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt;36 CFR – National Forest System Roads&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Being on the road. 36 CFR 261.54(e). It is prohibited to be on the road. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;The closure cited in this order is to protect the public from potential harm from wildfires and firefighting operations associated with the Deep Creek Fire. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Description of Closed Road:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Including all road encompassed by the area closure.&lt;/b&gt; See description of area closure above. &lt;b&gt;See attached map.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt;36 CFR – National Forest System Trails&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Being on the trail. 36 CFR 261.55(a). It is prohibited to be on the trail. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;The closure cited in this order is to protect the public from potential harm from wildfires and firefighting operations associated with the Deep Creek Fire. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Description of Trails:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Including all trails encompassed by the area closure.&lt;/b&gt; See description of area closure above. &lt;b&gt;See attached map.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left;tab-stops:1.75in"&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Exemptions:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Pursuant to 36 CFR 261.50(e), the following persons are exempt from this order:&lt;/p&gt; 1. Persons with a permit issued by a forest officer specifically authorizing the otherwise prohibited act or omission. 2. Any Federal, State, or local officer, or member of an organized rescue or firefighting force in the performance of an official duty. &lt;p&gt;Signed in Missoula, Montana, this &lt;u&gt;1st&lt;/u&gt; day of September, 2017.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;u&gt;/s/ Timothy Garcia&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Timothy Garcia&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Forest Supervisor&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Lolo National Forest&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Penalty: &lt;/b&gt;Violation of these prohibitions is punishable by a fine of not more than $5000 for and individual or $10,000 for an organization, or imprisonment for not more than 6 months, or both (16 USC 551 and 18 USC 3559 and 3571).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Notification: &lt;/b&gt;A copy of this order shall be posted as prescribed in 36 CFR 261.51.&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Sheep Gap"></category></entry><entry><title>09-01-2017_Sheep Gap Fire Area, Rd, Tr Closure #075</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5558_39671.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-01T14:44:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-01T14:44:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-01:/montana_fires/5558_39671.html</id><summary type="html">F17-075-LOLO-D5LOLO NATIONAL FOREST 24 Fort Missoula Road Missoula, Montana 59804-7297 FOREST SUPERVISOR’S ORDER   Pursuant to Title 36 Code of Federal Regulations 261.50 (a &amp; b), the following acts are prohibited as described below within the Plains/Thompson Falls Ranger District of the Lolo National Forest. These restrictions are in addition to those enumerated in Subpart A, Part 261, Title 36, Code of Federal Regulations, and become effective upon signing and will remain in effect until rescinded.  36 CFR – Special Closures   It is prohibited to go into or be upon the area (36 CFR 261.53(e)).   The closure cited in this order is to protect the public from potential harm from wildfires and firefighting operations associated with the Sheep Gap Fire.    Description of Closed Areas:   This area closure closes the area as described below and shown on the ATTACHED MAP.   All of sections and Protracted Blocks 2, PB37, PB38, PB39, PB40 &amp; 11, and parts of sections and Protracted Blocks...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;09-01-2017_Sheep Gap Fire Area, Rd, Tr Closure #075&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Sheep Gap Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 24 hrs. ago&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- 
cached related article links at 14:31:41
cached id 5cc5e1d33363138f9ddf21bd783f6ef5
--&gt;
&lt;div id="related_block"&gt;&lt;h4 id="related_head"&gt;Related Information&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul class="related_list"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/photos/MTLNF/2017-08-30-1109-Sheep-Gap/related_files/pict20170802-122804-0.pdf" rel="new"&gt;9-1-2017 Sheep Gap Closure Order #075 (pdf 62 kb)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/photos/MTLNF/2017-08-30-1109-Sheep-Gap/related_files/pict20170802-122907-0.pdf" rel="new"&gt;9-1-2017 Sheep Gap Closure Map #075 (pdf 4,675 kb)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align="center" style="text-align:center"&gt;F17-075-LOLO-D5&lt;b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align="center" style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;b&gt;LOLO NATIONAL FOREST&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="center" style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;b&gt;24 Fort Missoula Road&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="center" style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Missoula, Montana 59804-7297&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="center" style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;b&gt;FOREST SUPERVISOR’S ORDER&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="center" style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Pursuant to Title 36 Code of Federal Regulations 261.50 (a &amp;amp; b), the following acts are prohibited as described below within the Plains/Thompson Falls Ranger District of the Lolo National Forest. These restrictions are in addition to those enumerated in Subpart A, Part 261, Title 36, Code of Federal Regulations, and become effective upon signing and will remain in effect until rescinded. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt;36 CFR – Special Closures&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;It is prohibited to go into or be upon the area (36 CFR 261.53(e)).&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;The closure cited in this order is to protect the public from potential harm from wildfires and firefighting operations associated with the Sheep Gap Fire. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Description of Closed Areas:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt;This area closure closes the area as described below and shown on the ATTACHED MAP.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;All of sections and Protracted Blocks 2, PB37, PB38, PB39, PB40 &amp;amp; 11, and parts of sections and Protracted Blocks 1, 7, 8, 9, PB41, 12, 13, PB42, PB43, &amp;amp; 16, T. 19 N., R. 27 W.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;All of Protracted Block PB37 and parts of sections 2, 3, 11, &amp;amp; 12, T. 19 N., R. 28 W.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;All of sections 7 – 9, 15 – 20, 23, 30, 31, &amp;amp; 32, and parts of sections 3 – 6, 10, 14, 33, &amp;amp; 34, T. 20 N., R. 27 W.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;All of sections and Protracted Blocks PB37, PB38, PB39, 11, PB43, PB44, PB45, 15, PB46, PB48, PB49, 26, 35, PB51, and parts of sections and Protracted Blocks PB40, 9, 10, 16, 21, 22, 27, &amp;amp; 34, T. 20 N., R. 28 W.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;Part of sections 31 &amp;amp; 32, T. 21 N., R. 27 W.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;All of sections 35 &amp;amp; 36, and parts of 22, 26, 27, 28, 33, &amp;amp; 34, T. 21 N., R. 28 W.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt;36 CFR – National Forest System Roads&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Being on the road. 36 CFR 261.54(e). It is prohibited to be on the road. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;The closure cited in this order is to protect the public from potential harm from wildfires and firefighting operations associated with the Sheep Gap Fire. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Description of Closed Road:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Including all road encompassed by the area closure.&lt;/b&gt; See description of area closure above. &lt;b&gt;See attached map.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt;36 CFR – National Forest System Trails&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Being on the trail. 36 CFR 261.55(a). It is prohibited to be on the trail. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;The closure cited in this order is to protect the public from potential harm from wildfires and firefighting operations associated with the Sheep Gap Fire. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Description of Trails:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Including all trails encompassed by the area closure.&lt;/b&gt; See description of area closure above. &lt;b&gt;See attached map.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left;tab-stops:1.75in"&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p align="left" style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Exemptions:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Pursuant to 36 CFR 261.50(e), the following persons are exempt from this order:&lt;/p&gt; 1. Persons with a permit issued by a forest officer specifically authorizing the otherwise prohibited act or omission. 2. Any Federal, State, or local officer, or member of an organized rescue or firefighting force in the performance of an official duty. &lt;p&gt;Signed in Missoula, Montana, this &lt;u&gt;1st&lt;/u&gt; day of September, 2017.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;u&gt;/s/ Timothy Garcia&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Timothy Garcia&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Forest Supervisor&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Lolo National Forest&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Penalty: &lt;/b&gt;Violation of these prohibitions is punishable by a fine of not more than $5000 for and individual or $10,000 for an organization, or imprisonment for not more than 6 months, or both (16 USC 551 and 18 USC 3559 and 3571).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Notification: &lt;/b&gt;A copy of this order shall be posted as prescribed in 36 CFR 261.51.&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Sheep Gap"></category></entry><entry><title>Plains-Thompson Falls Community Meeting_Fire Situation_9-1-2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5558_39669.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-01T14:20:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-01T14:20:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-01:/montana_fires/5558_39669.html</id><summary type="html">Community Meeting To discuss the current fire situation in the area of Thompson Falls and Plains 6 PM Friday, September 1, 2017 Thompson Falls Community Center 410 Golf Street, Thompson Falls  Representatives from the Lolo and Kootenai National Forests, Sanders County Sheriff’s Department, Montana Disaster and Emergency Services, Sanders County Emergency Management, and the Department of Natural Resources and Conservation will be present to discuss the suppression effort, area and road closures, evacuation warnings and contingency</summary><content type="html">Community Meeting To discuss the current fire situation in the area of Thompson Falls and Plains 6 PM Friday, September 1, 2017 Thompson Falls Community Center 410 Golf Street, Thompson Falls  Representatives from the Lolo and Kootenai National Forests, Sanders County Sheriff’s Department, Montana Disaster and Emergency Services, Sanders County Emergency Management, and the Department of Natural Resources and Conservation will be present to discuss the suppression effort, area and road closures, evacuation warnings and contingency</content><category term="Sheep Gap"></category></entry><entry><title>09-01-2017_Sheep Gap Fire Update</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5558_39667.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-01T14:11:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-01T14:11:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-01:/montana_fires/5558_39667.html</id><summary type="html">September 1, 2017, 7 A.M.Contact: John HamiltonPhone: 406-826-4345 or 406-529-5475 Inciweb: https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5558/  What: Sheep Gap and Deep Creek Fire Update Location: Sheep Gap fire is approximately 9 miles west of Plains, Plains-Thompson Falls Ranger District (T 20 North R 27 W Section 7); Deep Creek fire is approximately 12 miles northwest of Thompson Falls (T 23 North R 30 W Section 14) Size: Approximately 1,637 acres Containment: 0 Cause: Started by lightning August 29  The Sheep Gap and Deep Creek fires: Both fires were started by lightning earlier this week. A Type 3 organization was assigned management of the Deep Creek fire as well as the Sheep Gap fire as of this morning, September 1. The primary initial attack priorities on both fast-growing incidents is to first secure identified high-value resources while attempting to control these fires. Helicopters with buckets, heavy air tankers and single engine air tankers were utilized when available throughout...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;09-01-2017_Sheep Gap Fire Update&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Sheep Gap Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 24 hrs. ago&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;September 1, 2017, 7 A.M.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Contact:&lt;/b&gt; John Hamilton&lt;b&gt;Phone: &lt;/b&gt;406-826-4345 or 406-529-5475&lt;b&gt; Inciweb: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5558/"&gt;https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5558/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;b&gt;What:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight:normal"&gt;Sheep Gap and Deep Creek Fire Update&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;Location:&lt;/b&gt; Sheep Gap fire is approximately 9 miles west of Plains, Plains-Thompson Falls Ranger District (T 20 North R 27 W Section 7); Deep Creek fire is approximately 12 miles northwest of Thompson Falls (T 23 North R 30 W Section 14) &lt;b&gt;Size:&lt;/b&gt; Approximately 1,637 acres &lt;b&gt;Containment:&lt;/b&gt; 0 &lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal"&gt;Cause&lt;/b&gt;: Started by lightning August 29 &lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal"&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal"&gt;The Sheep Gap and Deep Creek fires: &lt;/b&gt;Both&lt;b style="mso-bidi-font-weight:normal"&gt; &lt;/b&gt;fires were started by lightning earlier this week. A Type 3 organization was assigned management of the Deep Creek fire as well as the Sheep Gap fire as of this morning, September 1. The primary initial attack priorities on both fast-growing incidents is to first secure identified high-value resources while attempting to control these fires. Helicopters with buckets, heavy air tankers and single engine air tankers were utilized when available throughout the work cycle. High winds associated with forecast red flag weather warnings curtailed these activities in the afternoon. Contingency lines were being constructed at strategic locations ahead of the Sheep Gap fire. Resources: Heavy air tankers and helicopters were also instrumental in moderating spread on the Deep Creek fire, which has no road access. Three engines were being utilized on the Sheep Gap fire. A 20-person crew is on the Deep Creek fire and approximately 50 personnel are assigned to the Sheep Gap fire. Structures: Both fires have structures and dwellings well below the incidents along roads, and pre-evacuation warnings have been issued to those residents. Homeowners that have been contacted have a clearly identifiable purple ribbon attached to those residences to aid in the rapid identification should evacuation procedures be implemented. A structure assessment specialist is presently going door-to-door through the area to ensure that people are aware of the situation. Hazards: Steep, rocky terrain and access to both fires is problematic. Very dry forest fuels and continuing hot and dry weather are complicating factors. The rugged terrain is very challenging for on-the-ground forces. If you fly, we can’t! The use of unmanned aircraft (drones) is illegal near forest fires and can force the grounding of firefighting aircraft, jeopardize firefighter and pilot safety and impede successful suppression. Please, don’t be the person that helps this fire escape.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;Closures: Road Nos. 7583 and 7589, and Road No. 217 after the junction with 7589 are closed. Trails 385 (Sacajawea Peak), 398 (Dee Creek) and 1400 (West Fork of Swamp Creek) are also closed. See Inciweb for additional area closure information: &lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/closures/5558/"&gt;https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/closures/5558/&lt;/a&gt;. Area closures for public and firefighter safety will be established today around both of these fires.
		&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Sheep Gap"></category></entry><entry><title>08-31-2017_Sheep Gap Fire Update</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5558_39664.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-01T13:50:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-01T13:50:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-01:/montana_fires/5558_39664.html</id><summary type="html">August 31, 2017, 7 P.M. Contact: John Hamilton Phone: 406-826-4345 or 406-529-5475 Inciweb: https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5558/   What: Sheep Gap Fire Update Location: Fire is approximately 9 miles west of Plains, Plains-Thompson Falls Ranger District (T 20 North R 27 W Section 7) Size: Approximately 1000 acres Containment: 0 Cause: Started by lightning at approximately 5 p.m., Aug. 29    The Sheep Gap Fire: Fire was started by lightning on the evening of Aug. 29 and quickly grew to over 200 acres that night. By evening Aug 30, the fire has grown to an estimated 1000 acres. The Forest Service will conduct an infrared detection flight overnight to determine the new size and perimeter of the fire. Today firefighters reinforced fire line on the northern edge to prevent movement toward structures and other resources of value. Air tankers laid down a line of fire retardant along the south edge of Road 7581 to increase the road’s effectiveness as a fireline. Firefighters using...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;08-31-2017_Sheep Gap Fire Update&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Sheep Gap Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 1 day ago&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;August 31, 2017, 7 P.M.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;b&gt;Contact:&lt;/b&gt; John Hamilton &lt;b&gt;Phone: &lt;/b&gt;406-826-4345 or 406-529-5475&lt;b&gt; Inciweb: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5558/"&gt;https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5558/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;b&gt;What:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;Sheep Gap Fire Update&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;Location:&lt;/b&gt; Fire is approximately 9 miles west of Plains, Plains-Thompson Falls Ranger District (T 20 North R 27 W Section 7) &lt;b&gt;Size:&lt;/b&gt; Approximately 1000 acres &lt;b&gt;Containment:&lt;/b&gt; 0 &lt;b&gt;Cause&lt;/b&gt;: Started by lightning at approximately 5 p.m., Aug. 29 &lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;The Sheep Gap Fire: &lt;/b&gt;Fire was started by lightning on the evening of Aug. 29 and quickly grew to over 200 acres that night. By evening Aug 30, the fire has grown to an estimated 1000 acres. The Forest Service will conduct an infrared detection flight overnight to determine the new size and perimeter of the fire. Today firefighters reinforced fire line on the northern edge to prevent movement toward structures and other resources of value. Air tankers laid down a line of fire retardant along the south edge of Road 7581 to increase the road’s effectiveness as a fireline. Firefighters using helicopter bucket drops successfully knocked down a spot fire that had become established north of the road. &lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;Resources: &lt;/b&gt;Heavy air tankers and helicopters were instrumental in moderating spread of the fire to allow work on contingency lines between the fire and homes to the north. Excavators worked to clear roads for use as firelines. More personnel will be assigned to the fire as they are released from other fires in the area. Firefighting resources, both equipment and people, are being moved among separate fires to protect the highest values at risk. &lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;Structures: &lt;/b&gt;This fire does not directly threaten structures currently, but pre-evacuation notices have been issued to residents along River Road West. Residents in areas under warning notice should be prepared to evacuate with very little additional notice.&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;Hazards: &lt;/b&gt;Steep, rocky terrain. Access to much of the fire area is difficult. The forest fuels feeding the fire are at near-record dryness, and low humidity and wind have made all Montana fires extremely dangerous and rapidly moving. &lt;b&gt;If you fly, we can’t! &lt;/b&gt;The use of unmanned aircraft (drones) is illegal near forest fires and can force the grounding of firefighting aircraft, jeopardize firefighter and pilot safety and impede successful suppression. Please, don’t be the person that helps this fire escape. &lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;Closures: &lt;/b&gt;Road Nos. 7583 and 7589, and Road No. 217 after the junction with 7589 are closed. Trails 385 (Sacajawea Peak), 398 (Dee Creek) and 1400 (West Fork of Swamp Creek) are also closed. See Inciweb for additional area closure information: &lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/closures/5558/"&gt;https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/closures/5558/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Sheep Gap"></category></entry></feed>