<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Montana Fires - Sapphire Complex</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/feeds/sapphire-complex.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/</id><updated>2017-09-01T10:00:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Sapphire Complex Daily Update 09.01.2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5364_39617.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-01T10:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-01T10:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-01:/montana_fires/5364_39617.html</id><summary type="html">Three fires comprise the Sapphire Complex: Little Hogback, Goat Creek, and Sliderock fires. Mike Almas’ Northern Rockies Type II Incident Management Team (IMT) is managing the incident. The fires are burning in steep, rocky terrain between the Rock Creek and Upper Willow Creek drainages.      Little Hogback Fire: 30,929 acres, 30% contained.      Thursday, the fire continued to back downhill along the southwestern flank between upper Sheep Gulch and Capron Creek, and helicopters helped moderate fire behavior with water drops. Thunderstorms and associated wind moved much of the smoke out of the area, which could result in more active fire behavior. At this point, fire managers believe burnout operations in Capron Creek may be the only way to secure firelines in that area, but gusty winds prevented those plans for a second day in a row. Crews continued to further secure firelines elsewhere around the fire, resulting in increased containment. Mop up of hot spots and patrolling for...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sapphire Complex Daily Update 09.01.2017&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Sapphire Complex Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 1 day ago&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- 
cached related article links at 14:16:29
cached id ecdfea90a5071dea2240bab261f5db61
--&gt;
&lt;div id="related_block"&gt;&lt;h4 id="related_head"&gt;Related Information&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul class="related_list"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/photos/MTLNF/2017-07-14-1837-Slide-Rock-Fire/related_files/pict20170801-184055-0.pdf" rel="new"&gt;Sapphire Complex Daily Update 09.01.2017 (pdf 135 kb)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p style="margin: 6pt 0in; tab-stops: center 3.85in;"&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;Three fires comprise the Sapphire Complex: Little Hogback, Goat Creek, and Sliderock fires. Mike Almas’ Northern Rockies Type II Incident Management Team (IMT) is managing the incident. The fires are burning in steep, rocky terrain between the Rock Creek and Upper Willow Creek drainages. &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt; tab-stops: center 3.85in;"&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Little Hogback Fire: 30,929 acres, 30% contained.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt; tab-stops: center 3.85in;"&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;Thursday, the fire continued to back downhill along the southwestern flank between upper Sheep Gulch and Capron Creek, and helicopters helped moderate fire behavior with water drops. Thunderstorms and associated wind moved much of the smoke out of the area, which could result in more active fire behavior. At this point, fire managers believe burnout operations in Capron Creek may be the only way to secure firelines in that area, but gusty winds prevented those plans for a second day in a row. Crews continued to further secure firelines elsewhere around the fire, resulting in increased containment. Mop up of hot spots and patrolling for spot fires is ongoing, and structure protection measures are still in place along Rock Creek Road. Preventing fire growth toward homes and ranches continues to dictate operational priorities, and protection of life is always the primary objective. &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Goat Creek Fire: 8,305 acres, 95% contained.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;Rehabilitation of firelines and fuel break construction is progressing rapidly, and crews continue to mop up hot spots within the fire’s perimeter.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;Sliderock Fire: 901 acres, 90% contained. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;Crews continue to mop up hotspots and patrol the Sliderock Fire.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Resources Threatened:&lt;/b&gt; Private property and structures in the Rock Creek, Upper Willow Creek, and Marshall Creek drainages remain threatened. Other resources threatened include fisheries in Rock Creek, grazing lands along the southern boundary of the Little Hogback Fire, Bonneville Power Administration powerline, and a communication site.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Evacuations:&lt;/b&gt; Three structures in the lower end of Capron Creek, near mile marker 33 on Rock Creek Road remain in Level Red- Evacuation Status. Many homes and communities are still potentially threatened by the fires within the Sapphire Complex, and as a result “Yellow” Pre-evacuation status for those areas also remain in effect. See Inciweb maps and evacuation alerts for details. &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Closures: &lt;/b&gt;The Rock Creek Road from I-90 south to Bitterroot Campground (MP 23.5) is OPEN. Due to fire traffic congestion and fire safety concerns, the Rock Creek Road will continue to be CLOSED from Bitterroot Campground, south to Cornish Gulch (FSR5027), and public traffic is NOT allowed. Upper Willow Creek Road is currently closed to the public. The Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest has reduced closure restrictions in the Black Pine ridge area, but maintains all area closures in the Upper Willow Creek, North Fork Lower Willow Creek, and Harvey Creek areas. The Bureau of Land Management has implemented an area closure in the Upper Willow Creek, Ram Mountain, and nearby areas. The Lolo and Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forests and the Bureau of Land Management have posted closure orders and maps under the &lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/closures/5364/"&gt;&lt;font color="#0000ff" face="Times New Roman"&gt;closures tab&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt; on Inciweb&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;Weather: &lt;/b&gt; Although winds are predicted to lessen over the fire area today, relative humidities are expected to be very low and temperatures will approach the 90s, which could result in increased fire behavior. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Fire Restrictions:&lt;/b&gt; Stage 1 Fire Restrictions are in place on the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest (Forest Service land east of Sandstone Ridge), with the additional modification to prohibit all campfires. Stage 2 Fire Restrictions are in place on BLM, private and state lands in Granite County, and the Lolo National Forest (Forest Service land west of Sandstone Ridge). &lt;b&gt;For information on fire restrictions, please visit &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://firerestrictions.us/"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font color="#0000ff" face="Times New Roman"&gt;firerestrictions.us&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;u&gt; &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;u&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Lolo National Forest - Revised Area Closure</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5364_39686.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-31T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-08-31T19:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-08-31:/montana_fires/5364_39686.html</id><summary type="html">Effective August 31st, the Lolo National Forest has modified the area closure related to the Sapphire Complex of fires. Please see the attached area closure order and map for full</summary><content type="html">Effective August 31st, the Lolo National Forest has modified the area closure related to the Sapphire Complex of fires. Please see the attached area closure order and map for full</content></entry><entry><title>Livestream of today's public meeting</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5364_39561.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-31T16:03:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-08-31T16:03:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-08-31:/montana_fires/5364_39561.html</id><summary type="html">The Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest will Facebook Live stream tonight's community meeting for the Sapphire Complex and the Meyers Fire. The meeting is at Granite County High School, Philipsburg, at 5:30 p.m. See their feed at</summary><content type="html">The Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest will Facebook Live stream tonight's community meeting for the Sapphire Complex and the Meyers Fire. The meeting is at Granite County High School, Philipsburg, at 5:30 p.m. See their feed at</content></entry><entry><title>Sapphire Complex Smoke Report 08.31.2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5364_39527.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-31T12:42:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-08-31T12:42:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-08-31:/montana_fires/5364_39527.html</id><summary type="html">Sapphire Complex Smoke Report</summary><content type="html">Sapphire Complex Smoke Report</content></entry><entry><title>Sapphire Complex Daily Update 08.31.2017</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5364_39524.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-31T12:23:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-08-31T12:23:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-08-31:/montana_fires/5364_39524.html</id><summary type="html">Three fires comprise the Sapphire Complex: Little Hogback, Goat Creek, and Sliderock fires. Mike Almas’ Northern Rockies Type II Incident Management Team (IMT) is managing the incident. The fires are burning in steep, rocky terrain between the Rock Creek and Upper Willow Creek drainages. Fire managers will hold a public meeting jointly for both the Sapphire Complex and the Meyers Fire TONIGHT at 5:30 p.m. at the Granite County High School library.     Little Hogback Fire: 30,929 acres, 30% contained.      Wednesday, the fire continued to back downhill along the southwestern flank between upper Sheep Gulch and Capron Creek, resulting in the evacuation of three structures in Capron Creek drainage, along Rock Creek Road. Fire managers continue to seek opportunities to complete indirect line and secure firelines along the southwest corner where fire intensity and treacherous terrain continue to hamper containment efforts. Firefighters may need to perform a small burnout operation in...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sapphire Complex Daily Update 08.31.2017&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Sapphire Complex Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 2 days ago&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- 
cached related article links at 14:16:29
cached id 608c7736569a5aca41a7aab47f8bb029
--&gt;
&lt;div id="related_block"&gt;&lt;h4 id="related_head"&gt;Related Information&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul class="related_list"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/photos/MTLNF/2017-07-14-1837-Slide-Rock-Fire/related_files/pict20170731-123734-0.pdf" rel="new"&gt;Sapphire Complex Daily Update 08.31.2017 (pdf 137 kb)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font color="#000000" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0.3pt;"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;font color="#000000"&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;Three fires comprise the Sapphire Complex: Little Hogback, Goat Creek, and Sliderock fires. Mike Almas’ Northern Rockies Type II Incident Management Team (IMT) is managing the incident. The fires are burning in steep, rocky terrain between the Rock Creek and Upper Willow Creek drainages. Fire managers will hold a public meeting jointly for both the Sapphire Complex and the Meyers Fire &lt;b&gt;TONIGHT at 5:30 p.m. at the Granite County High School library.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt; tab-stops: center 3.85in;"&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Little Hogback Fire: 30,929 acres, 30% contained.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt; tab-stops: center 3.85in;"&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;Wednesday, the fire continued to back downhill along the southwestern flank between upper Sheep Gulch and Capron Creek, resulting in the evacuation of three structures in Capron Creek drainage, along Rock Creek Road. Fire managers continue to seek opportunities to complete indirect line and secure firelines along the southwest corner where fire intensity and treacherous terrain continue to hamper containment efforts. Firefighters may need to perform a small burnout operation in that area in order to protect structures. Elsewhere around the fire, previously unburned fuels within the fire’s interior continued to burn and torch. Crews made significant headway holding and further securing existing firelines, mopping up hot spots that started smoldering and smoking with the increased winds, while remaining vigilant in case spot fires were to occur. Structure protection measures are still in place along Rock Creek Road. Preventing fire growth toward homes and ranches continues to dictate operational priorities, and protection of life is always the primary objective. &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Goat Creek Fire: 8,305 acres, 95% contained.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;Limited suppression repair has begun, where practical, while crews continue to mop-up and patrol some portions of the fire.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;Sliderock Fire: 901 acres, 90% contained. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;Crews continue to mop up on hotspots around the Sliderock Fire perimeter and will continue to patrol the area.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Resources Threatened:&lt;/b&gt; Private property and structures in the Rock Creek, Upper Willow Creek, and Marshall Creek drainages remain threatened. Other resources threatened include fisheries in Rock Creek, grazing lands along the southern boundary of the Little Hogback Fire, Bonneville Power Administration powerline, and a communication site.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Evacuations:&lt;/b&gt; Late Wednesday, the Granite County Sheriff issued an evacuation order for three structures in the lower end of Capron Creek, near mile marker 33 on Rock Creek Road. Many homes and communities are still potentially threatened by the fires within the Sapphire Complex, and as a result “Yellow” Pre-evacuation status for those areas remain in effect. See Inciweb maps and evacuation alerts for details. &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Closures: &lt;/b&gt;The Lolo National Forest instituted a new area closure, effective Thursday, August 31, which allows public access to the Bitterroot Campground. The Rock Creek Road from I-90 south to Bitterroot Campground (MP 23.5) is OPEN. Due to fire traffic congestion and fire safety concerns, the Rock Creek Road will continue to be CLOSED from Bitterroot Campground, south to Cornish Gulch, and public traffic is NOT allowed. Upper Willow Creek Road is currently closed to the public. The Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest has reduced closure restrictions in the Black Pine ridge area, but maintains all area closures in the Upper Willow Creek, North Fork Lower Willow Creek, and Harvey Creek areas. The Bureau of Land Management has implemented an area closure in the Upper Willow Creek, Ram Mountain, and nearby areas. The Lolo and Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forests and the Bureau of Land Management have posted closure orders and maps under the &lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/closures/5364/"&gt;&lt;font color="#0000ff" face="Times New Roman"&gt;closures tab&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt; on Inciweb. &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Weather: &lt;/b&gt;Sapphire Complex meteorologists issued a Red Flag Warning again today! Wednesday’s thunderstorms resulted in gusty winds over portions of the fire area; however, measurable precipitation only fell on Goat Creek Fire.&lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Fire Restrictions:&lt;/b&gt; Stage 1 Fire Restrictions are in place on the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest (Forest Service land east of Sandstone Ridge), with the additional modification to prohibit all campfires. Stage 2 Fire Restrictions are in place on BLM, private and state lands in Granite County, and the Lolo National Forest (Forest Service land west of Sandstone Ridge).&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;b&gt;For information on fire restrictions, please visit &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://firerestrictions.us/"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font color="#0000ff" face="Times New Roman"&gt;firerestrictions.us&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman"&gt;.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content></entry></feed>