<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Montana Fires - Sprague Fire</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/feeds/sprague-fire.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/</id><updated>2017-09-02T12:28:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Evacuation Warning for Sprague Fire Area</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5510_39764.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-02T12:28:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-02T12:28:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-02:/montana_fires/5510_39764.html</id><summary type="html">Today, Glacier National Park Rangers are issuing an Evacuation Warning for the south end of Lake McDonald north to Logan Pass. This warning includes North McDonald Road. This warning DOES NOT include the Apgar area. The Going-to-the-Sun Road will remain OPEN. Trails and campgrounds in the area will be closed on Sunday. See 9/2/17 Update for specific</summary><content type="html">Today, Glacier National Park Rangers are issuing an Evacuation Warning for the south end of Lake McDonald north to Logan Pass. This warning includes North McDonald Road. This warning DOES NOT include the Apgar area. The Going-to-the-Sun Road will remain OPEN. Trails and campgrounds in the area will be closed on Sunday. See 9/2/17 Update for specific</content></entry><entry><title>PREPARATIONS ARE BEING MADE FOR WIND SWITCH</title><link href="https://rjames86.github.io/montana_fires/5510_39734.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-02T10:50:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-02T10:50:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Ryan M</name></author><id>tag:rjames86.github.io,2017-09-02:/montana_fires/5510_39734.html</id><summary type="html">Preparations are being made for the east winds forecast for Sunday night. Glacier National Park will be issuing an Evacuation Warning on Saturday, September 2, 2017, from the south end of Lake McDonald north to Logan Pass. This will include the North McDonald Road. This will not include the Apgar area at this time. An Evacuation Warning is triggered when current or projected threats from hazards associated with the Sprague Fire are severe enough to indicate a good probability of the need to evacuate.   The Going-to-the-Sun Road will remain open. The Sprague Creek and Avalanche Campgrounds will be open on Saturday night but will close by noon on Sunday. Glacier Park Boat Co. will remain open at Lake McDonald Lodge. Swan Mountain Outfitters at Lake McDonald will be open on Saturday and closed on Sunday. Effective Sunday morning, all trails accessed from the Going-to-the-Sun Road from the south end of Lake McDonald to Avalanche, including Trail of the Cedars, will be closed.   ...</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="content"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;PREPARATIONS ARE BEING MADE FOR WIND SWITCH &lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident:&lt;/strong&gt; Sprague Fire Wildfire&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Released:&lt;/strong&gt; 4 hrs. ago&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- 
cached related article links at 14:31:31
cached id 58de8faa92b60d8036959d4b1684435a
--&gt;
&lt;div id="related_block"&gt;&lt;h4 id="related_head"&gt;Related Information&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul class="related_list"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/photos/MTGNP/2017-08-15-1634-Sprague-Fire/related_files/pict20170802-105513-0.pdf" rel="new"&gt;Sept. 2nd Update (pdf 145 kb)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt; line-height: normal;"&gt; &lt;font face=""&gt;&lt;font size="4"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Preparations are being made for the east winds forecast for Sunday night.&lt;/b&gt; Glacier National Park will be issuing an Evacuation &lt;i&gt;Warning&lt;/i&gt; on Saturday, September 2, 2017, from the south end of Lake McDonald north to Logan Pass. This will include the North McDonald Road. This will &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;not &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;include the Apgar area at this time. An Evacuation &lt;i&gt;Warning&lt;/i&gt; is triggered when current or projected threats from hazards associated with the Sprague Fire are severe enough to indicate a good probability of the need to evacuate. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="" size="4"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face=""&gt;&lt;font size="4"&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Going-to-the-Sun Road will remain open. &lt;/b&gt;The Sprague Creek and Avalanche Campgrounds will be open on Saturday night but will close by noon on Sunday. Glacier Park Boat Co. will remain open at Lake McDonald Lodge. Swan Mountain Outfitters at Lake McDonald will be open on Saturday and closed on Sunday. Effective Sunday morning, all trails accessed from the Going-to-the-Sun Road from the south end of Lake McDonald to Avalanche, including Trail of the Cedars, will be closed. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="" size="4"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt; line-height: normal;"&gt;&lt;font face="" size="4"&gt; &lt;b&gt;Structure protection work resuming in Lake McDonald area&lt;/b&gt;. The Fort Apache Hotshots will be working in the Lake McDonald area installing hose lays, sprinklers, and pumps as contingency measures given the predicted east winds. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt; line-height: normal;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="" size="4"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face=""&gt;&lt;font size="4"&gt;&lt;b&gt;The following trails are currently closed due to fire activity&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;The Avalanche Lake Trail including the Avalanche Lake area, Sprague, Snyder, and Lincoln Creek drainages and associated trails, from Lake McDonald Trailhead on the west and &lt;i&gt;Gunsight Lake&lt;/i&gt; on the east, are also closed to all use. Visit &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="http://go.nps.gov/glacconditions"&gt;&lt;font color="#0563c1" face="" size="4"&gt;http://go.nps.gov/glacconditions&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font face="" size="4"&gt; for trail, road, and campground information. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="" size="4"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt; line-height: normal; tab-stops: 134.85pt;"&gt;&lt;font face="" size="4"&gt; &lt;b&gt;The Sprague Fire perimeter is now estimated at 5,116 acres.&lt;/b&gt; An infrared flight on Friday night reported a growth of 470 acres. Hot, dry weather dominates the forecast. The fire is burning actively in high elevation areas that normally would not carry fire. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="" size="4"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face=""&gt;&lt;font size="4"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Lake McDonald Lodge is closed for the season. Other concessions operations adjusted their services in the Lake McDonald Lodge area. &lt;/b&gt;The Swan Mountain Outfitters will continue to guide horseback rides out of their Lake McDonald corral on Saturday, and Glacier Park Boat Company will continue to offer boat tours on Lake McDonald, with some schedule changes to accommodate concerns about localized poor air quality during mornings and evenings. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="" size="4"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt; line-height: normal;"&gt;&lt;font face="" size="4"&gt; &lt;b&gt;Fire managers are working to protect values at risk and evaluating structure protection needs. &lt;/b&gt;The fire is now very close to the Mt. Brown Lookout which is a priority value at risk and is wrapped with protective material. Other threatened values include backcountry cabins and campgrounds, structures in the Lake McDonald area, and trail infrastructure such as footbridges. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="" size="4"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt; line-height: normal;"&gt;&lt;font face="" size="4"&gt; &lt;b&gt;Smoke will continue to settle into low-lying areas when air temperatures cool at night and in the early morning hours.&lt;/b&gt; If you encounter smoke while driving, slow down, turn on your headlights, and watch out for people and wildlife. Montana Wildfire Smoke Updates are available on &lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="http://svc.mt.gov/deq/todaysair/"&gt;&lt;font color="#0563c1" face="" size="4"&gt;http://svc.mt.gov/deq/todaysair/&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font face="" size="4"&gt;. If it’s smoky in one area of the park, there are often other areas of the park with better visibility. Smoke conditions vary in intensity, location and duration with fire activity.&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;You can monitor current conditions on the Park’s webcams at &lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="http://go.nps.gov/glacwebcams"&gt;&lt;font color="#0563c1" face="" size="4"&gt;http://go.nps.gov/glacwebcams&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font face="" size="4"&gt;. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br/&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="" size="4"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt; line-height: normal;"&gt;&lt;font face=""&gt;&lt;font size="4"&gt; &lt;b&gt;Fire Information Line:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font face=""&gt;&lt;font size="4"&gt; 406-888-7077 &lt;br/&gt; &lt;b&gt;Inciweb: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5510/"&gt;&lt;font color="#0563c1" face="" size="4"&gt;https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5510/&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font face="" size="4"&gt; (fire updates, maps and photos, air quality info, and park webcams) &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="" size="4"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt; line-height: normal;"&gt;&lt;font face=""&gt;&lt;font size="4"&gt; &lt;b&gt;Facebook: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://facebook.com/GlacierNPS"&gt;&lt;font color="#0563c1" face="" size="4"&gt;https://facebook.com/GlacierNPS&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font face="" size="4"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="" size="4"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt; line-height: normal;"&gt;&lt;font face=""&gt;&lt;font size="4"&gt; &lt;b&gt;Twitter: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/GlacierNPS"&gt;&lt;font color="#0563c1" face="" size="4"&gt;https://twitter.com/GlacierNPS&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font face="" size="4"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content></entry></feed>